<reference anchor="I-D.day-impp-basis">
  <front>
    <title>Proposed Design Decisions for IMPP</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-day-impp-basis-00"/>
    <author fullname="Mark Day" initials="M." surname="Day">
      <organization>Lotus</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Gordon Mohr" initials="G." surname="Mohr"/>
    <author fullname="Sonu Aggarwal" initials="S." surname="Aggarwal">
      <organization>Microsoft</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Greg Hudson" initials="G." surname="Hudson">
      <organization>MIT</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="1999" month="October" day="4"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>As of this writing, the IMPP working group has largely reachedconsensus on the requirements for IMPP [Reqts]. In addition, Hudson[Issues] has catalogued a set of design issues discussed on themailing list.This document proposes a starting point for further discussions aboutthe design of the Instant Messaging and Presence Protocol (IMPP). Itis not a fully-specified protocol, but a summary of design decisionson which the authors were able to reach agreement during two full daysof discussion. Our discussions drew on knowledge of operational andarchitectural aspects of Activerse Ding!, Lotus Sametime, MicrosoftExchange instant messaging, MSN Messenger, and Zephyr, among otherdiverse, widely-deployed systems supporting presence and/or instantmessaging. We believe that the issues on which we reached agreementare issues on which the working group as a whole should be able toquickly reach rough consensus. We hope that the working group will beable to adopt these decisions as the basis for further work ondesigning IMPP; of course, we recognize the possibility that strongtechnical arguments not hitherto considered may cause the group toarrive at different decisions in some instances.We also identified some areas, primarily related to security, in whichwe were lacking enough information or experience to make a solidrecommendation. We draw the working group's attention to these issuesin the hope that others can contribute. Although we have treated presence and instant messaging in the samedocument, we believe that these design decisions allow implementors tooffer either service independently of the other.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>