<reference anchor="I-D.many-ip-optical-framework" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-many-ip-optical-framework-03">
  <front>
    <title>IP over Optical Networks - A Framework</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-many-ip-optical-framework-03"/>
    <author initials="B." surname="Rajagopalan" fullname="Dr. Bala Rajagopalan"/>
    <author initials="J. V." surname="Luciani" fullname="Dr. James V. Luciani"/>
    <author initials="D. O." surname="Awduche" fullname="Daniel O. Awduche"/>
    <author initials="B." surname="Cain" fullname="Bradley Cain"/>
    <author initials="B." surname="Jamoussi" fullname="Bilel Jamoussi"/>
    <author initials="D." surname="Saha" fullname="Dr. Debanjan Saha"/>
    <date day="05" month="March" year="2001"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>The Internet transport infrastructure is moving towards a model of 
high-speed routers interconnected by optical core networks. A 
consensus is emerging in the industry on utilizing IP-centric 
protocols for the optical control plane [9, 10], as well as for 
dynamic bandwidth provisioning for IP services. Also, there has 
recently been significant activity in defining models for IP 
transport over optical networks, specifically, the routing and 
signaling aspects [2,6,7]. This draft attempts to define a framework 
for IP over Optical networks, considering both the IP control plane 
for optical networks as well as IP transport over optical networks 
(together referred to as 'IP over optical networks'). Within this 
framework, we develop a common set of terms and concepts which allows 
to discuss these IP over optical technologies in a consistent fashion.  
Additionally, this draft surveys some architectural frameworks that 
might be useful and appropriate for the deployment of IP over hybrid 
optical networks that contain IP routers, WDM multiplexers, and 
optical cross-connects (OXCs). This document is complementary to the 
framework of Multiprotocol Lambda Switching proposed in [2].
	 </t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>