<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-pwe3-mpls-transport" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-ietf-pwe3-mpls-transport-04">
  <front>
    <title>Application of Ethernet Pseudowires to MPLS Transport Networks</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-pwe3-mpls-transport-04"/>
    <author initials="R." surname="Cherukuri" fullname="Rao Cherukuri">
      <organization>Juniper Networks</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="M." surname="Morrow" fullname="Monique Morrow">
      <organization>Cisco Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="T." surname="Nadeau" fullname="Thomas Nadeau">
      <organization>Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="G." surname="Swallow" fullname="George Swallow">
      <organization>Cisco Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="N." surname="Harrison" fullname="Neil Harrison">
      <organization>BT</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="B." surname="Niven-Jenkins" fullname="Ben Niven-Jenkins">
      <organization>Velocix</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="S." surname="Bryant" fullname="Stewart Bryant">
      <organization>Cisco Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="29" month="June" year="2009"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Ethernet pseudowires are widely deployed to support packet transport of Ethernet services. These services in-turn provide transport for a variety of client networks, e.g., IP and MPLS. This document uses procedures defined in the existing IETF specifications of Ethernet pseudowires carried over MPLS networks.

 Many of the requirements for the services provided by the mechanisms explained in this document are also recognized by the MPLS transport profile (MPLS-TP) design effort formed jointly by the IETF and ITU-T. The solution described here does not address all of the MPLS-TP requirements, but it provides a viable form of packet transport service using tools that are already available.

 This document also serves as an indication that existing MPLS techniques form an appropriate basis for the design of a fully- featured packet transport solution addressing all of the requirements of MPLS-TP. This document is not an Internet Standards Track specification; it is published for informational purposes.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>