<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-teas-enhanced-vpn" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-ietf-teas-enhanced-vpn-04">
  <front>
    <title>A Framework for Enhanced Virtual Private Networks (VPN+) Services</title>
    <author fullname="Jie Dong" initials="J." surname="Dong">
      <organization>Huawei</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Stewart Bryant" initials="S." surname="Bryant">
      <organization>Futurewei</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Zhenqiang Li" initials="Z." surname="Li">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Takuya Miyasaka" initials="T." surname="Miyasaka">
      <organization>KDDI Corporation</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Young Lee" initials="Y." surname="Lee">
      <organization>Sung Kyun Kwan University</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2020" month="January" day="23"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document describes the framework for Enhanced Virtual Private Network (VPN+) service. The purpose is to support the needs of new applications, particularly applications that are associated with 5G services, by utilizing an approach that is based on existing VPN and TE technologies and adds features that specific services require over and above traditional VPNs. Typically, VPN+ will be used to form the underpinning of network slicing, but could also be of use in its own right providing enhanced connectivity services between customer sites. It is envisaged that enhanced VPNs will be delivered using a combination of existing, modified, and new networking technologies. This document provides an overview of relevant technologies and identifies some areas for potential new work. It is not envisaged that large numbers of VPN+ instances will be deployed in a network and, in particular, it is not intended that all VPNs supported by a network will use VPN+ related techniques.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-teas-enhanced-vpn-04"/>
</reference>