<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-idr-bgp-flowspec-oid">
  <front>
    <title>Revised Validation Procedure for BGP Flow Specifications</title>
    <author>
      <organization abbrev="IETF">Internet Engineering Task Force</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jim Uttaro" initials="J." surname="Uttaro">
      <organization>AT&amp;T</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Juan Alcaide" initials="J." surname="Alcaide">
      <organization>Cisco</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Clarence Filsfils" initials="C." surname="Filsfils">
      <organization>Cisco</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="David Smith" initials="D." surname="Smith">
      <organization>Cisco</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Prodosh Mohapatra" initials="P." surname="Mohapatra">
      <organization>Sproute Networks</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2021" month="April" day="12"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document describes a modification to the validation procedure defined for the dissemination of BGP Flow Specifications. The dissemination of BGP Flow Specifications requires that the originator of the Flow Specification matches the originator of the best-match unicast route for the destination prefix embedded in the Flow Specification. For an iBGP received route, the originator is typically a border router within the same autonomous system. The objective is to allow only BGP speakers within the data forwarding path to originate BGP Flow Specifications. Sometimes it is desirable to originate the BGP Flow Specification any place within the autonomous system itself, for example, from a centralized BGP route controller. However, the validation procedure will fail in this scenario. The modification proposed herein relaxes the validation rule to enable Flow Specifications to be originated within the same autonomous system as the BGP speaker performing the validation. Additionally, this document revises AS_PATH validation rules so Flow Specifications received from an eBGP peer can be validated when such peer is a BGP route server. This document updates the validation procedure in RFC8955.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-idr-bgp-flowspec-oid-13"/>
</reference>