<reference anchor="I-D.eman-green-rfc6988bis" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-eman-green-rfc6988bis-01">
  <front>
    <title>Requirements for Energy Efficiency Management, 11 years after the EMAN RFC6988</title>
    <author fullname="Benoît Claise" initials="B." surname="Claise">
      <organization>Huawei</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Qin Wu" initials="Q." surname="Wu">
      <organization>Huawei</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Marisol Palmero" initials="M." surname="Palmero">
      <organization>Cisco Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Emile Stephan" initials="E." surname="Stephan">
      <organization>Orange</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2024" month="July" day="21"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document defines requirements for standards specifications for Energy Management, taking RFC6988 as a starting point. Eleven years after the RFC 6988 publication, this document re-evaluates the requirements. The requirements defined in this document are concerned with discovery f unctions, monitoring functions as well as control functions. Discovery functions include identifying energy- managed network, devices and their components, discovery of inventory of power components capabilities, optimization control capabilities, nominal condition use. Monitoring functions include monitoring their Power States, Power Attributes, energy consumption, network performance, energy efficiency metrics. Control functions include such functions as controlling energy saving and optimization functions and Power State of energy-managed devices and their components. This document does not specify the features that must be implemented by compliant implementations but rather lists features that must be supported by standards for Energy efficiency Management. Discussion Venues Source of this draft and an issue tracker can be found at https://github.com/bclaise/green-ietf</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-eman-green-rfc6988bis-01"/>
</reference>