<reference anchor="I-D.song-opsawg-ifit-framework">
  <front>
    <title>In-situ Flow Information Telemetry</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-song-opsawg-ifit-framework-12"/>
    <author>
      <organization abbrev="IETF">Internet Engineering Task Force</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Haoyu Song" initials="H." surname="Song">
      <organization>Futurewei</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Fengwei Qin" initials="F." surname="Qin">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Huanan Chen" initials="H." surname="Chen">
      <organization>China Telecom</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jaewhan Jin" initials="J." surname="Jin">
      <organization>LG U+</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jongyoon Shin" initials="J." surname="Shin">
      <organization>SK Telecom</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2020" month="April" day="14"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>As networks increase in scale and network operations become more sophisticated, traditional Operation, Administration and Maintenance (OAM) methods, which include proactive and reactive techniques, running in active and passive modes, are no longer sufficient to meet the monitoring and measurement requirements. Emerging on-path telemetry techniques which provide high-precision flow insight and real-time issue notification are required to ensure suitable quality of experience for users and applications, and identify faults or network deficiencies before they become critical. This document outlines a high-level framework to provide an operational environment that utilizes existing and emerging on-path telemetry techniques to enable the collection and correlation of performance information from the network. The framework identifies the components that are needed to coordinate the existing protocol tools and telemetry mechanisms, and addresses key deployment challenges for flow-oriented on-path telemetry techniques, especially in carrier networks. The framework is informational and intended to guide system designers attempting to use the referenced techniques as well as to motivate further work to enhance the ecosystem .</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>