<reference anchor="I-D.song-tsvwg-camp" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-song-tsvwg-camp-00">
  <front>
    <title>Consistency-Aware Multipath Transport (CAMP) toward Interactive Multimodal LLM-Based Systems</title>
    <author fullname="Yuhong Song" initials="Y." surname="Song">
      <organization>Pengcheng Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Changlong Li" initials="C." surname="Li">
      <organization>East China Normal University</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Qing Li" initials="Q." surname="Li">
      <organization>Pengcheng Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2026" month="March" day="2"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>With the prosperity of generative large language models (LLMs), interactive LLM-based services, such as digital humans, have imposed new stringent requirements on low latency and high multimodal consistency. Traditional interactive LLM-based systems typically transmit multimodal content over a single network path, thereby failing to exploit the advantages offered by multipath networks. Even when multipath transport mechanisms are adopted, single-stream encapsulation does not enable differentiated management of heterogeneous modalities. However, naively separating modalities into multiple streams further introduces inter-modal arrival inconsistency. To address these challenges, this document specifies CAMP, a consistency-aware multipath transport design over the Multipath QUIC (MPQUIC) protocol. First, CAMP defines a three-stream separation encapsulation format to support modality-differentiated transmission. Second, it incorporates a transport-layer consistency- aware multipath scheduler to reduce inter-modal arrival time deviation across network paths. Third, it specifies a client-side application-layer alignment mechanism that operates in coordination with the transport scheduler. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first specification to address multipath-enabled multimodal consistency guarantees for interactive LLM-based systems.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-song-tsvwg-camp-00"/>
</reference>