<reference anchor="I-D.quilbeuf-opsawg-configuration-tracing" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-quilbeuf-opsawg-configuration-tracing-00">
  <front>
    <title>External Transaction ID for Configuration Tracing</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-quilbeuf-opsawg-configuration-tracing-00"/>
    <author initials="J." surname="Quilbeuf" fullname="Jean Quilbeuf">
      <organization>Huawei</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="B." surname="Claise" fullname="Beno&#xEE;t Claise">
      <organization>Huawei</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="T." surname="Graf" fullname="Thomas Graf">
      <organization>Swisscom</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="D." surname="Lopez" fullname="Diego Lopez">
      <organization>Telefonica I+D</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="S." surname="Qiong" fullname="Sun Qiong">
      <organization>China Telecom</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="20" month="October" year="2022"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>   Network equipments are often configured by a variety of network
   management systems (NMS), protocols, and people.  If a network issue
   arises because of a wrong configuration modification, it's important
   to quickly identify the specific service request and obtain the
   reason for pushing that modification.  Another potential network
   issue can stem from concurrent NMS's with overlapping intent, each
   having their own tasks to perform: in such a case, it's important to
   map the respective modifications to its originating NMS.  This
   document specifies a mechanism to automatically map the configuration
   modifications to their source, up to a specific NMS service request,
   in the context of NETCONF.  Such a mechanism is required for
   autonomous networks, to trace the reason of a particular
   configuration change that lead to an anomaly detection or a broken
   SLA.  This mechanism facilitates the troubleshooting, the post mortem
   analysis, and in the end the closed loop automation required for
   self-healing networks.  The specifications contain a new YANG module
   mapping a local configuration change to the corresponding northbound
   transaction, up to the controller or even the orchestrator.

	 </t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>