<reference anchor="I-D.liu-ippm-active-loss-considerations" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-liu-ippm-active-loss-considerations-00">
  <front>
    <title>Considerations for Interpreting Packet Loss Observed by Active Performance Measurements</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-liu-ippm-active-loss-considerations-00"/>
    <author initials="L." surname="Liu" fullname="Libin Liu">
      <organization>Zhongguancun Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="01" month="July" year="2026"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Active performance measurement protocols and metrics are commonly
   used to measure packet loss, delay, delay variation, reachability,
   and path behavior.  When an active measurement packet is not
   received, a response is missing, or a measurement exchange times out,
   the measurement result identifies the observable outcome but often
   does not identify the underlying cause.

   Loss observed by active performance measurements can be associated
   with congestion, queue discard, link or forwarding failures, routing
   changes, endpoint or reflector behavior, administrative filtering,
   policing, multipath effects, or validation-related packet discard
   such as Source Address Validation (SAV).  Different operational
   conditions can produce similar measurement observations, but they may
   have different meanings and require different troubleshooting
   actions.

   This document discusses considerations for interpreting packet loss
   observed by active performance measurements.  It provides a common
   set of considerations for separating measured outcomes from inferred
   causes, describes operational conditions that can lead to observed
   loss, discusses implications for one-way and two-way measurements,
   delay and delay variation interpretation, OWAMP, TWAMP, STAMP, and
   measurements over ECMP and link aggregation.  It also discusses how
   some considerations may apply to hybrid and passive performance
   measurements and identifies sources of operational context that can
   help operators and measurement systems reason about possible
   explanations.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>