<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-lamps-csr-attestation" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-ietf-lamps-csr-attestation-12">
  <front>
    <title>Use of Remote Attestation with Certification Signing Requests</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-lamps-csr-attestation-12"/>
    <author initials="M." surname="Ounsworth" fullname="Mike Ounsworth">
      <organization>Entrust Limited</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="H." surname="Tschofenig" fullname="Hannes Tschofenig">
      <organization>Siemens</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="H." surname="Birkholz" fullname="Henk Birkholz">
      <organization>Fraunhofer SIT</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="M." surname="Wiseman" fullname="Monty Wiseman">
      <organization>Beyond Identity</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="N." surname="Smith" fullname="Ned Smith">
      <organization>Intel Corporation</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="12" month="October" year="2024"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>A PKI end entity requesting a certificate from a Certification
   Authority (CA) may wish to offer trustworthy claims about the
   platform generating the certification request and the environment
   associated with the corresponding private key, such as whether the
   private key resides on a hardware security module.

   This specification defines an attribute and an extension that allow
   for conveyance of Evidence in Certificate Signing Requests (CSRs)
   such as PKCS#10 or Certificate Request Message Format (CRMF) payloads
   which provides an elegant and automatable mechanism for transporting
   Evidence to a Certification Authority.

   Including Evidence along with a CSR can help to improve the
   assessment of the security posture for the private key, and can help
   the Certification Authority to assess whether it satisfies the
   requested certificate profile.  These Evidence Claims can include
   information about the hardware component's manufacturer, the version
   of installed or running firmware, the version of software installed
   or running in layers above the firmware, or the presence of hardware
   components providing specific protection capabilities or shielded
   locations (e.g., to protect keys).</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>