<reference anchor="I-D.lucente-grow-bmp-offline" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-lucente-grow-bmp-offline-01">
  <front>
    <title>BMP State Summaries</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-lucente-grow-bmp-offline-01"/>
    <author initials="P." surname="Lucente" fullname="Paolo Lucente">
      <organization>NTT</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="C." surname="Cardona" fullname="Camilo Cardona">
      <organization>NTT</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="C." surname="Petrie" fullname="Colin Petrie">
      <organization>NTT</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="L." surname="Hendriks" fullname="Luuk Hendriks">
      <organization>NLnet Labs</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="01" month="March" year="2025"></date>
    <abstract>
      <t>   BMP (BGP Monitoring Protocol) is perfectly suited for real-time
   consumption but less ideal in stream processing and off-wire
   historical scenarios.  The main issue is that the ability to
   correctly parse BGP Update PDUs, carried in BMP Route Monitoring
   messages, depends on the BGP Capabilities exchanged during the
   establishment of the BGP session between the peers via BGP Open PDUs.
   The BGP Open PDUs, carried in BMP Peer Up Notification messages, are
   exported at the establishment of the BMP session.  Similar to BGP,
   BMP sessions are typically long-lived, so the crucial information to
   correctly parse subsequent messages of such sessions was possibly
   sent a relatively long time ago (days, weeks, months).

   This document introduces the concept of Summaries.  It defines a new
   optional BMP message type, called State Summary, and a new TLV,
   called Summary Id.  A Summary is similar to the initial
   synchronisation performed upon establishment of the BMP session: all
   BGP session information is exported in Peer Up Notification messages,
   and all RIB contents are exported in Route Monitoring messages.  All
   the messages carry the new Summary Id TLV, containing an ID uniquely
   identifying the summary these messages belong to.  The messages are
   preceded by a State Summary message carrying the same Summary Id TLV,
   as well as meta-data describing the Summary.

	 </t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>