<reference anchor="I-D.irtf-nmrg-green-ps" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-irtf-nmrg-green-ps-03">
  <front>
    <title>Challenges and Opportunities in Management for Green Networking</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-irtf-nmrg-green-ps-03"/>
    <author initials="A." surname="Clemm" fullname="Alexander Clemm">
      <organization>Sympotech</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="C." surname="Westphal" fullname="Cedric Westphal"/>
    <author initials="J." surname="Tantsura" fullname="Jeff Tantsura">
      <organization>Nvidia</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="L." surname="Ciavaglia" fullname="Laurent Ciavaglia">
      <organization>Nokia</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="C." surname="Pignataro" fullname="Carlos Pignataro">
      <organization>North Carolina State University</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="M." surname="Odini" fullname="Marie-Paule Odini"/>
    <date day="28" month="June" year="2024"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>   Reducing humankind's environmental footprint and making technology
   more environmentally sustainable are among the biggest challenges of
   our age.  Networks play an important part in this challenge.  On one
   hand, they enable applications that help to reduce this footprint.
   On the other hand, they contribute to this footprint themselves in no
   insignificant way.  Therefore, methods to make networking technology
   itself "greener" and to manage and operate networks in ways that
   reduce their environmental footprint without impacting their utility
   need to be explored.  This document outlines a corresponding set of
   opportunities, along with associated research challenges, for
   networking technology in general and management technology in
   particular to become "greener", i.e., more sustainable, with reduced
   greenhouse gas emissions and less negative impact on the environment.

   This document is a product of the Network Management Research Group
   (NMRG) of the Internet Research Task Force (IRTF).  This document
   reflects the consensus of the research group.  It is not a candidate
   for any level of Internet Standard and is published for informational
   purposes.

	 </t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>