<reference anchor="I-D.an-nmrg-i2icf-cits" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-an-nmrg-i2icf-cits-02">
  <front>
    <title>Agentic Interface to In-Network Computing Functions for Software-Defined Vehicles in Cooperative Intelligent Transportation Systems</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-an-nmrg-i2icf-cits-02"/>
    <author initials="B." surname="An" fullname="Byoungman An">
      <organization>Intelligent Information R and D Division Mobility Platform Research Center</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="J. P." surname="Jeong" fullname="Jaehoon Paul Jeong">
      <organization>Department of Computer Science &amp; Engineering</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="P." surname="Park" fullname="Pusik Park">
      <organization>Intelligent Information R and D Division Mobility Platform Research Center</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="S." surname="Jang" fullname="Soohyun Jang">
      <organization>Intelligent Information R and D Division Mobility Platform Research Center</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="10" month="June" year="2026"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document specifies a structured framework for orchestrating,
   managing, and monitoring In-Network Computing Functions (ICFs) for
   Software-Defined Vehicles (SDVs) in Cooperative Intelligent
   Transportation Systems (C-ITS), with a first-class role given to the
   Agent-to-Agent (A2A) communication paradigm.  SDVs decouple vehicular
   functions from underlying hardware and expose them as software-
   driven, continuously updatable services; this architectural shift
   makes them natural participants in an agentic control plane that
   spans vehicles, roadside infrastructure, and mobile networks.  AI
   agents are co-located with each functional entity of the C-ITS
   architecture (e.g., C-ITS Center, Government Public Center, C-ITS
   Infra, Mobile Network Operator (MNO), Roadside Unit (RSU), SDV, and
   Vulnerable Road User (VRU)) and interact over an A2A protocol overlay
   to advertise capabilities, discover peers, negotiate resources, and
   coordinate the placement and execution of ICFs across multi-domain
   networks.  In the context of Vehicle-to-Everything (V2X)
   communications, this agentic overlay enables efficient management of
   Vehicle-to-Vehicle (V2V) and Vehicle-to-Infrastructure (V2I)
   communications and their integration with C-ITS by leveraging in-
   network computing to optimize real-time communication, streamline
   traffic management, and enhance data processing and security services
   at the network edge.  The framework aligns with ongoing IRTF NMRG
   work on agentic AI and A2A applicability to network management, and
   adapts these concepts to the specific operational and safety
   requirements of SDV-centric C-ITS deployments.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>