<reference anchor="I-D.mackie-sfc-using-virtual-networking" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-mackie-sfc-using-virtual-networking-01">
  <front>
    <title>Service Function Chains Using Virtual Networking</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-mackie-sfc-using-virtual-networking-01"/>
    <author initials="S." surname="Mackie" fullname="Stuart Mackie"/>
    <author initials="M." surname="Napierala" fullname="Maria Napierala"/>
    <author initials="D." surname="Daino" fullname="Diego Daino"/>
    <author initials="D. R." surname="Lopez" fullname="Diego R. Lopez"/>
    <author initials="D." surname="Bernier" fullname="Daniel Bernier"/>
    <author initials="W." surname="Haeffner" fullname="Walter Haeffner"/>
    <date day="17" month="October" year="2014"></date>
    <abstract>
      <t>   This document describes how service function chains (SFC) can be
   applied to traffic flows using routing in a virtual (overlay)
   network to steer traffic between service nodes. Chains can include
   services running in routers, on physical appliances or in virtual
   machines. Service chains have applicability at the subscriber edge,
   business edge and in multi-tenant datacenters. The routing function
   into SFCs and between service functions within an SFC can be
   performed by physical devices (routers), be virtualized inside
   hypervisors, or run as part of a host OS.

   The architecture uses a controller to calculate and install routes
   to implement an SFC, based on a topological model of the chain and
   knowledge of the network addresses that should pass through the
   chain. An advantage of the approach is that SFCs can be implemented
   without alteration to today's BGP standard, and without change to
   the current operation of routers.

   Service chains need to support load balancing between network
   functions, and symmetric forward and reverse paths are required when
   stateful services are involved. This document shows how these
   requirements can be met by using VRFs at the ingress and egress of
   each service instance and by performing load balancing after the
   egress of each service as part of the routing function.

	 </t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>