<reference anchor="I-D.hongcs-t2trg-ras">
  <front>
    <title>Resource Allocation Strategy for Latency Sensitive IoT Traffic</title>
    <author fullname="Choong Seon Hong" surname="Choong Seon Hong">
      <organization>Kyung Hee University</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Shashi Raj Pandey" surname="Shashi Raj Pandey">
      <organization>Kyung Hee University</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Yan Kyaw Tun" surname="Yan Kyaw Tun">
      <organization>Kyung Hee University</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Sabah Suhail" surname="Sabah Suhail">
      <organization>Kyung Hee University</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Kitae Kim" surname="Kitae Kim">
      <organization>Kyung Hee University</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2020" month="October" day="13"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>An efficient resource allocation scheme directly affects the overall system's network utilization, and notably, the wireless resource such as bandwidth is itself an expensive commodity. In this regards, to address the requirement of massively increased IoT traffic at the edge, as a solution approach, a number of small cell base stations (SBSs) have been deployed with certain computational capabilities. However, it is still limited, and any inappropriate resource allocation scheme for the associated nodes with traffic characterized by ultra-reliability and low-latency (URLLC) requirements can impact the system's resource utilization and performance. Considering a reserve resource for such kind of traffic, the resource allocation problem in each time slot behaves as a node selection problem with contention amongst active nodes for the resource. In this paper, we have formulated this as an index problem, and with simulation results have shown that the cumulative reward in terms of network utility is maximized following this approach.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-hongcs-t2trg-ras-00"/>
  <format type="TXT" target="https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-hongcs-t2trg-ras-00.txt"/>
</reference>