<reference anchor="I-D.schmidt-avt-rfc3016bis">
  <front>
    <title>RTP Payload Format for MPEG-4 Audio/Visual Streams</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-schmidt-avt-rfc3016bis-03"/>
    <author fullname="Malte Schmidt"/>
    <author fullname="Frans Bont"/>
    <author fullname="Stefan Doehla"/>
    <author fullname="Jaehwan Kim"/>
    <date year="2009" month="December" day="23"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document describes Real-Time Transport Protocol (RTP) payloadformats for carrying each of MPEG-4 Audio and MPEG-4 Visualbitstreams without using MPEG-4 Systems. For the purpose of directlymapping MPEG-4 Audio/Visual bitstreams onto RTP packets, it providesspecifications for the use of RTP header fields and also specifiesfragmentation rules. It also provides specifications for Media Typeregistration and the use of Session Description Protocol (SDP).Comments are solicited and should be addressed to the working group'smailing list at avt@ietf.org and/or the author(s).Status of this MemoThis Internet-Draft is submitted to IETF in full conformance with theprovisions of BCP 78 and BCP 79.Internet-Drafts are working documents of the Internet EngineeringTask Force (IETF), its areas, and its working groups. Note thatother groups may also distribute working documents as Internet-Drafts.Internet-Drafts are draft documents valid for a maximum of six monthsand may be updated, replaced, or obsoleted by other documents at anytime. It is inappropriate to use Internet-Drafts as referencematerial or to cite them other than as "work in progress."The list of current Internet-Drafts can be accessed athttp://www.ietf.org/ietf/1id-abstracts.txt.The list of Internet-Draft Shadow Directories can be accessed athttp://www.ietf.org/shadow.html.This Internet-Draft will expire on June 24, 2010.Copyright NoticeCopyright (c) 2009 IETF Trust and the persons identified as thedocument authors. All rights reserved.This document is subject to BCP 78 and the IETF Trust's LegalProvisions Relating to IETF Documents(http://trustee.ietf.org/license-info) in effect on the date ofpublication of this document. Please review these documentscarefully, as they describe your rights and restrictions with respectto this document. Code Components extracted from this document mustinclude Simplified BSD License text as described in Section 4.e ofthe Trust Legal Provisions and are provided without warranty asdescribed in the BSD License.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>