<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-ldapext-ldap-c-api" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-ietf-ldapext-ldap-c-api-05">
  <front>
    <title>The C LDAP Application Program Interface</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-ldapext-ldap-c-api-05"/>
    <author initials="M. C." surname="Smith" fullname="Mark C. Smith">
      <organization>Netscape Communications Corp.</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="T." surname="Howes" fullname="Tim Howes">
      <organization>Loudcloud, Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="A." surname="Herron" fullname="Andrew Herron">
      <organization>Microsoft Corp.</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="M." surname="Wahl" fullname="Mark Wahl">
      <organization>Sun Microsystems</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="A." surname="Anantha" fullname="Anoop Anantha">
      <organization>Microsoft Corp.</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="22" month="November" year="2000"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document defines a C language application program interface (API)
to the Lightweight Directory Access Protocol (LDAP). This document
replaces the previous definition of this API, defined in RFC 1823,
updating it to include support for features found in version 3 of the
LDAP protocol.  New extended operation functions were added to support
LDAPv3 features such as controls.  In addition, other LDAP API changes
were made to support information hiding and thread safety.
 
The C LDAP API is designed to be powerful, yet simple to use. It defines
compatible synchronous and asynchronous interfaces to LDAP to suit a
wide variety of applications. This document gives a brief overview of
the LDAP model, then an overview of how the API is used by an applica-
tion program to obtain LDAP information.  The API calls are described in
detail, followed by appendices that provide example code demonstrating
use of the API, the namespace consumed by the API, a summary of require-
ments for API extensions, known incompatibilities with RFC 1823, and a
list of changes made since the last revision of this document.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>