<reference anchor="I-D.jiang-intent-security" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-jiang-intent-security-03">
  <front>
    <title>Security Considerations and Requirements for Intent-Based Requests in Agentic Systems</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-jiang-intent-security-03"/>
    <author initials="Y." surname="Jiang" fullname="Yuning Jiang">
      <organization>Huawei</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="L." surname="Lun" fullname="LUN LI">
      <organization>Huawei</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="Y." surname="Song" fullname="Yurong Song">
      <organization>Huawei</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="F." surname="Liu" fullname="Faye Liu">
      <organization>Huawei</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="22" month="June" year="2026"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Intent-based requests enable users, applications, and agents to
   express goals and constraints without specifying step-by-step
   procedures.  Such intents are commonly translated into executable
   directives and propagated across multiple entities (clients, agents,
   authorization components, orchestration functions, and execution
   endpoints).  This multi-hop processing expands the attack surface for
   tampering, privilege escalation, constraint bypass, and intent drift.
   In addition, at the point where an intent enters the system, a forged
   or unauthorized origin may cause actions to be taken without valid
   consent.

   This document provides a solution-agnostic security analysis for
   intent-based requests across agentic systems.  It presents attack
   scenarios, a threat model, security requirements, and per-scenario
   mitigation considerations, supported by a reference model.  The
   document is Informational: it does not define a protocol, message
   format, or registry, and concrete mechanisms are left to companion
   specifications.  It emphasizes origin authentication and admission
   control, constraint validation, invocation validation, multi-hop
   chain-of-custody, enforcement placement across hops, and policy-
   driven responses to drift, while remaining independent of any
   specific deployment domain.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>