<reference anchor="I-D.song-fann-framework" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-song-fann-framework-01">
  <front>
    <title>A Framework for Fast Network Notifications</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-song-fann-framework-01"/>
    <author initials="H." surname="Song" fullname="Haoyu Song">
      <organization>Futurewei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="J." surname="Dong" fullname="Jie Dong">
      <organization>Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="W." surname="Cheng" fullname="Weiqiang Cheng">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="Y." surname="Zhu" fullname="Yongqing Zhu">
      <organization>China Telecom</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="R." surname="Pang" fullname="Ran Pang">
      <organization>China Unicom</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="L. M." surname="Contreras" fullname="Luis M. Contreras">
      <organization>Telefonica</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="L." surname="Guo" fullname="Lei Guo">
      <organization>COSCO Shipping Technology Co., Ltd.</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="06" month="July" year="2026"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Many network applications, ranging from Artificial Intelligence (AI)
   / Machine Learning (ML) training and inference to large-scale cloud
   services, require networks with various combinations of high
   bandwidth, low delay, low jitter, and minimal packet loss.  Meeting
   these requirements depends on the network's ability to adapt rapidly
   to faults, signal degradation, and congestion.  The companion problem
   statement describes why existing mechanisms are too slow, too coarse,
   or too resource-intensive to react within the timescales at which
   modern forwarding hardware can detect and disseminate intended
   conditions.

   This document defines a framework for Fast Network Notifications
   (FANN).  It describes a reference architecture, the functional roles
   involved in generating and consuming notifications, an information
   model, delivery and scoping models, procedures for discovery,
   registration, and subscription, and the integration of fast network
   notifications with existing Layer 2 to 4 mechanisms.  This framework
   is intended to guide the development of one or more fast network
   notification protocol specifications.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>