<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-roll-rpl" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-ietf-roll-rpl-19">
  <front>
    <title>RPL: IPv6 Routing Protocol for Low-Power and Lossy Networks</title>
    <author fullname="Roger Alexander" initials="R." surname="Alexander">
      <organization>Cooper Power Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Anders Brandt" initials="A." surname="Brandt">
      <organization>Sigma Designs</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="JP Vasseur" initials="V." surname="Jp">
      <organization>Cisco Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jonathan Hui" initials="J." surname="Hui">
      <organization>Arch Rock Corporation</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Kris Pister" initials="K." surname="Pister">
      <organization>Dust Networks</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Pascal Thubert" initials="P." surname="Thubert">
      <organization>Cisco Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="P Levis" initials="P." surname="Levis">
      <organization>Stanford University</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Rene Struik" initials="R." surname="Struik">
      <organization>Struik Security Consultancy</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Richard Kelsey" initials="R." surname="Kelsey">
      <organization>Ember Corporation</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Tim Winter" initials="T." surname="Winter">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <date year="2011" month="March" day="14"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Low-Power and Lossy Networks (LLNs) are a class of network in which both the routers and their interconnect are constrained. LLN routers typically operate with constraints on processing power, memory, and energy (battery power). Their interconnects are characterized by high loss rates, low data rates, and instability. LLNs are comprised of anything from a few dozen to thousands of routers. Supported traffic flows include point-to-point (between devices inside the LLN), point-to-multipoint (from a central control point to a subset of devices inside the LLN), and multipoint-to-point (from devices inside the LLN towards a central control point). This document specifies the IPv6 Routing Protocol for Low-Power and Lossy Networks (RPL), which provides a mechanism whereby multipoint-to-point traffic from devices inside the LLN towards a central control point as well as point-to-multipoint traffic from the central control point to the devices inside the LLN are supported. Support for point-to-point traffic is also available. [STANDARDS-TRACK]</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-roll-rpl-19"/>
</reference>