<reference anchor="I-D.zhangb-cats-service-metrics-op" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-zhangb-cats-service-metrics-op-02">
  <front>
    <title>Computing Service Metric Definitions and Operation under CATS</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-zhangb-cats-service-metrics-op-02"/>
    <author initials="B." surname="Zhang" fullname="Bin Zhang">
      <organization>Pengcheng Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="Y." surname="Dai" fullname="Yina Dai">
      <organization>Sun Yat-sen University</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="Z." surname="Du" fullname="Zongpeng Du">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="C." surname="Miao" fullname="Chuanyang Miao">
      <organization>ZTE Corporation</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="29" month="June" year="2026"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Computing-Aware Traffic Steering (CATS) optimizes traffic forwarding
   by considering both computing and networking metrics.  While the
   existing framework and metric drafts provide theoretical models
   (e.g., L1/L2 normalized metrics), they face significant challenges to
   achieve direct operational execution in real-world deployments.
   Normalization methods vary across providers, and aggregated unitless
   scores often lose critical operational information, making it
   difficult for routers to make precise decisions.

   This document is proposed to fill this gap by providing an executable
   approach.  It defines a set of Computing Service Metrics and their
   operations under the CATS framework.  Instead of transmitting low-
   level raw hardware metrics, service sites dynamically evaluate and
   report service-oriented metrics (e.g., Global Available Slots) to the
   control plane.  The document also clarifies how such service-oriented
   metrics can be derived from basic resource information, service
   reference information, and local policy, and how updates can be
   controlled in large-scale deployments.  This enables efficient and
   precise traffic-steering policies without negating the value of
   existing normalized metrics.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>