<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-policy-framework-pfdl">
  <front>
    <title>Policy Framework Definition Language</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-policy-framework-pfdl-00"/>
    <author fullname="John Strassner" initials="J." surname="Strassner">
      <organization>Cisco Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Stephen Schleimer" initials="S." surname="Schleimer">
      <organization>Cisco Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="1998" month="November" day="23"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Recently, the IETF has developed protocols that classify packets inorder to treat certain classes or flows of packets in a particularway compared to other classes or flows of packets. The successfulwide-scale deployment of these protocols depends on the ability toadminister and distribute consistent policy information to differenttypes of network devices as well as hosts and servers that participatein policy decision making, administration, distribution and control.There is a clear need to develop a scalable framework for policyadministration and distribution that will enable interoperabilityamong multiple devices and device types that must work together toachieve a consistent implementation of policy.This document defines a language, called the Policy FrameworkDefinition Language (PFDL), that maps requirements for services to beprovided by the network as defined in a business specification (e.g.,an SLA) to a common vendor- and device-independent intermediate form.This enables policy information and specifications to be shared amongthe heterogeneous components that comprise the policy framework, andallows multiple vendors to use multiple devices to implement thatframework. The PFDL is the common 'currency' that is exchanged betweenthese heterogeneous components to enable them all to perform theirfunction in providing, securing, distributing, and administeringpolicy. The PFDL becomes the way to ensure that multiple vendorsinterpret the policy the same way while enabling vendors to providevalue-added services.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>