<reference anchor="I-D.various-snmpv2-adminv2-syn">
  <front>
    <title>Administrative Model for Version 2 of the Simple Network Management Protocol (SNMPv2)</title>
    <author fullname="Dr. Jeff D. Case" initials="J. D." surname="Case">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="James R. Davin" initials="J. R." surname="Davin">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Dr. Marshall T. Rose" initials="M. T." surname="Rose">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Steven Waldbusser" initials="S." surname="Waldbusser">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Keith McCloghrie" initials="K." surname="McCloghrie">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="James Galvin" initials="J." surname="Galvin">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <date year="1995" month="December" day="22"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document is a submission to the SNMPv2 Working Group of the IETF. Computer security systems can be usually be understood as being composed of two or more logically distinct components. There is often a privacy service that protects data from disclosure, an authentication service that validates the identity of the entity requesting service, and an access control service which, given an authorized entity, restricts the data and operations to which that entity has access. The SNMPv2 Administrative Model makes these distinctions. It specifies the data and protocols that a compliant SNMPv2 entity must implement in order to provide an access control service. However, it does not say anything about how authentication, privacy, timeliness, and the like ought to be implemented. Rather, it leaves the hooks in place for these services to be implemented in a variety of ways. Henceforth, this collection of unspecified services will be collectively referred to as 'the authentication and privacy services'. Consequently, the SNMPv2 Administrative Model provides an architecture that realizes an access control service, and provides the means for integrating authentication</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-various-snmpv2-adminv2-syn-01"/>
  <format type="TXT" target="https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-various-snmpv2-adminv2-syn-01.txt"/>
</reference>