<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-pim-v2-sm">
  <front>
    <title>Protocol Independent Multicast-Sparse Mode (PIM-SM): Protocol Specification</title>
    <author>
      <organization abbrev="IETF">Internet Engineering Task Force</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Dr. Deborah Estrin" initials="D." surname="Estrin">
      <organization>USC</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Van Jacobson" initials="V." surname="Jacobson">
      <organization>Cisco</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Dino Farinacci" initials="D." surname="Farinacci">
      <organization>Procket</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Liming Wei" initials="L." surname="Wei">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Dr. Steve E. Deering" initials="S. E." surname="Deering">
      <organization>Cisco</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Mark J. Handley" initials="M. J." surname="Handley">
      <organization>ACIRI</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Dave Thaler" initials="D." surname="Thaler">
      <organization>Microsoft</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Ching-Gung Liu" initials="C." surname="Liu">
      <organization>Fujitsu</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Puneet Sharma" initials="P." surname="Sharma">
      <organization>HPL</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Ahmed Helmy" initials="A." surname="Helmy">
      <organization>USC</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="1999" month="December"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document describes a protocol for efficiently routing to multicast groups that may span wide-area (and inter-domain) internets. We refer to the approach as Protocol Independent Multicast--Sparse Mode (PIM-SM) because it is not dependent on any particular unicast routing protocol, and because it is designed to support sparse groups as defined in [1][2]. This document describes the protocol details. For the motivation behind the design and a description of the architecture, see [1][2]. Section 2 summarizes PIM-SM operation. It describes the protocol from a network perspective, in particular, how the participating routers interact to create and maintain the multicast distribution tree. Section 3 describes PIM-SM operations from the perspective of a single router implementing the protocol; this section constitutes the main body of the protocol specification. It is organized according to PIM-SM message type; for each message type we describe its contents, its generation, and its processing.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-pim-v2-sm-01"/>
</reference>