<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-idr-route-leak-detection-mitigation">
  <front>
    <title>Methods for Detection and Mitigation of BGP Route Leaks</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-idr-route-leak-detection-mitigation-07"/>
    <author>
      <organization abbrev="IETF">Internet Engineering Task Force</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Kotikalapudi Sriram" initials="K." surname="Sriram">
      <organization>US NIST</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Doug Montgomery" initials="D." surname="Montgomery">
      <organization>US NIST</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Brian Dickson" initials="B." surname="Dickson"/>
    <author fullname="Keyur Patel" initials="K." surname="Patel">
      <organization>Arrcus</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Andrei Robachevsky" initials="A." surname="Robachevsky">
      <organization>Internet Society</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2017" month="September"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>RFC 7908 provides a definition of the route leak problem, and also enumerates several types of route leaks. This document first examines which of those route-leak types are detected and mitigated by the existing origin validation (OV) [RFC 6811]. It is recognized that OV offers a limited detection and mitigation capability against route leaks. This document specifies enhancements that significantly extend the route-leak prevention, detection, and mitigation capabilities of BGP. One solution component involves intra-AS messaging from ingress router to egress router using a BGP Community or Attribute. This intra-AS messaging prevents the AS from causing route leaks. Another solution component involves carrying a per-hop route-leak protection (RLP) field in BGP updates. The RLP fields are proposed to be carried in a new optional transitive attribute, called BGP RLP attribute. The RLP attribute helps with detection and mitigation of route leaks at ASes downstream from the leaking AS.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>