<reference anchor="I-D.yan-dmm-man" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-yan-dmm-man-11">
  <front>
    <title>Mobility Capability Negotiation</title>
    <author fullname="Zhiwei Yan" initials="Z." surname="Yan">
      <organization>CNNIC</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Tianji Jiang" initials="T." surname="Jiang">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jianfeng Guan" initials="J." surname="Guan">
      <organization>BUPT</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Tao Huang" initials="T." surname="Huang">
      <organization>BUPT</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jong-Hyouk Lee" initials="J." surname="Lee">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <date year="2023" month="July" day="3"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Mobile peers exchange signals with networks, for both IP and wireless domains, to negotiate capabilities for mobile registration, connection management, session establishment, service provisioning, etc. Generally, mobility capabilities include the supported and provisioned resources along with associated protocols for certain mobility management scenarios. While devices in the mobile IP domain would mostly focus on the IP-related negotiation, devices in the wireless domain, e.g., the 5G system (5GS), embrace both mobile IP- related resources as well as wireless-specific capabilities. Regarding both the mobile-IP and wireless domains, we have generalized two protocol categories for mobility capability negotiation &amp; management, i.e., the host-initiated category that involves the direct &amp; active engagement of mobile end devices vs. the network-based category over which mobile endpoints play almost no role in the process. The classification and then the application of the two categories help us analyze the mobility capability negotiation for both the mobile IPv6 and the 3GPP 5G system. The comparison of the capability negotiation under both the Home-Routed (HR) and the Local BreakOut (LBO) roaming cases in 5GS further reflects the feasibility of the protocol dichotomy.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-yan-dmm-man-11"/>
</reference>