<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-lisp-nexagon" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-ietf-lisp-nexagon-49">
  <front>
    <title>Network-Hexagons:Geolocation Mobility Network Based On H3 and LISP</title>
    <author fullname="Sharon Barkai" initials="S." surname="Barkai">
      <organization>Nexar Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Bruno Fernandez-Ruiz" initials="B." surname="Fernandez-Ruiz">
      <organization>Nexar Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Rotem Tamir" initials="R." surname="Tamir">
      <organization>Nexar Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Alberto Rodriguez-Natal" initials="A." surname="Rodriguez-Natal">
      <organization>Cisco Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Fabio Maino" initials="F." surname="Maino">
      <organization>Cisco Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Albert Cabellos-Aparicio" initials="A." surname="Cabellos-Aparicio">
      <organization>Universitat Politecnica de Catalunya</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jordi Paillisse" initials="J." surname="Paillisse">
      <organization>Universitat Politecnica de Catalunya</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Dino Farinacci" initials="D." surname="Farinacci">
      <organization>lispers.net</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2023" month="March" day="27"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This specification describes the use of Locator/ID SeparationProtocol (LISP) for network virtualization overlays (NVO) and network function distribution (NFD) to enable a mobility network overlay with distributed geolocation functions. The distributed geolocation functions are anchored by logically addressed geolocation agents. Geolocation agents endpoint identifiers (EID) are determined according to the H3 hierarchical hexagonal grid area they cover. Geolocation agents consolidate, delegate, federate, and propagate information and logic to and from in-vehicle agents. In-vehicle agents EIDs are ephemeral to protect the geo-privacy of the vehicle owner while interacting with distributed geolocation functions. In-vehicle EIDs are obtained and renewed through authorization, authentication, and accounting procedure(AAA). The primary function supported by this specification is dynamic mapping of road conditions and navigation using in-vehicle agents equipped with perception AI. Secondary distributed AI compute functions can use the same network.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-lisp-nexagon-49"/>
</reference>