<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-cats-usecases-requirements" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-ietf-cats-usecases-requirements-03">
  <front>
    <title>Computing-Aware Traffic Steering (CATS) Problem Statement, Use Cases, and Requirements</title>
    <author fullname="Kehan Yao" initials="K." surname="Yao">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Dirk Trossen" initials="D." surname="Trossen">
      <organization>Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Luis M. Contreras" initials="L. M." surname="Contreras">
      <organization>Telefonica</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Hang Shi" initials="H." surname="Shi">
      <organization>Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Yizhou Li" initials="Y." surname="Li">
      <organization>Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Shuai Zhang" initials="S." surname="Zhang">
      <organization>China Unicom</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Qing An" initials="Q." surname="An">
      <organization>Alibaba Group</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2024" month="July" day="3"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Distributed computing is a tool that service providers can use to achieve better service response time and optimized energy consumption. In such a distributed computing environment, providing services by utilizing computing resources hosted in various computing facilities aids support of services such as computationally intensive and delay sensitive services. Ideally, compute services are balanced across servers and network resources to enable higher throughput and lower response times. To achieve this, the choice of server and network resources should consider metrics that are oriented towards compute capabilities and resources instead of simply dispatching the service requests in a static way or optimizing solely on connectivity metrics. The process of selecting servers or service instance locations, and of directing traffic to them on chosen network resources is called "Computing-Aware Traffic Steering" (CATS). This document provides the problem statement and the typical scenarios for CATS, which shows the necessity of considering more factors when steering traffic to the appropriate computing resource to best meet the customer's expectations and deliver the requested service.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-cats-usecases-requirements-03"/>
</reference>