<reference anchor="I-D.li-spring-sr-sfc-control-plane-framework" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-li-spring-sr-sfc-control-plane-framework-11">
  <front>
    <title>A Framework for Constructing Service Function Chaining Systems Based on Segment Routing</title>
    <author fullname="Yuanyang Yin" initials="Y." surname="Yin">
      <organization>China Telecom</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Cheng Li" initials="C." surname="Li">
      <organization>Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Ahmed El Sawaf" initials="A." surname="El Sawaf">
      <organization>Saudi Telecom Company</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Hongyi Huang" initials="H." surname="Huang">
      <organization>Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Zhenbin Li" initials="Z." surname="Li">
      <organization>Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2024" month="September" day="10"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Segment Routing (SR) introduces a versatile methodology for defining end-to-end network paths by encoding sequences of topological sub- paths, known as "segments". This architecture can be deployed over both MPLS and IPv6 data planes, offering a flexible routing solution. Service Function Chaining (SFC) supports the establishment of composite services through an ordered sequence of Service Functions (SFs) that are applied to packets or frames based on initial classification. SFC's implementation can utilize various underlying technologies, including the Network Service Header (NSH) and SR, to facilitate the creation and management of service chains. This document presents a comprehensive control framework for developing SFC architectures using Segment Routing. It explores control plane solutions for the distribution of service function instance routes and service function paths, as well as techniques for directing packets into specific service function chains. The discussion encompasses both theoretical foundations and practical considerations for integrating SR into SFC deployments.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-li-spring-sr-sfc-control-plane-framework-11"/>
</reference>