<reference anchor="I-D.xu-intarea-challenge-icmpv4" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-xu-intarea-challenge-icmpv4-00">
  <front>
    <title>Enhancing ICMP Error Message Authentication Using Challenge-Confirm Mechanism</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-xu-intarea-challenge-icmpv4-00"/>
    <author initials="K." surname="Xu" fullname="Ke Xu">
      <organization>Tsinghua University &amp; Zhongguancun Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="X." surname="Feng" fullname="Xuewei Feng">
      <organization>Tsinghua University</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="Y." surname="Yang" fullname="Yuxiang Yang">
      <organization>Tsinghua University</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="L." surname="Qi" fullname="Li Qi">
      <organization>Tsinghua University &amp; Zhongguancun Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="26" month="February" year="2025"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>   The Internet Control Message Protocol (ICMP) plays a crucial role in
   network diagnostics and error reporting.  However, it is a challenge
   to verify the legitimacy of a received ICMP error message,
   particularly when the ICMP error message is embedded with stateless
   protocol data.  As a result, adversaries can forge ICMP error
   messages, leading to potential exploitation and off-path attacks.
   This document proposes a novel method to enhance ICMP authentication
   by introducing a challenge-confirm mechanism.  This mechanism embeds
   random numbers in the IP options field to strengthen the
   authentication of ICMP error messages.  By doing so, it mitigates the
   risks associated with forged messages, improves the overall
   robustness of the protocol, and enhances network security.  The
   proposed solution includes details on the challenge-confirm
   mechanism, random number generation and management, and integration
   with IP options.  Additionally, it discusses security and deployment
   considerations to ensure its practical implementation.

	 </t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>