<reference anchor="I-D.song-opsawg-ifit-framework">
  <front>
    <title>In-situ Flow Information Telemetry</title>
    <author fullname="Haoyu Song" initials="H." surname="Song">
      <organization>Futurewei</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Fengwei Qin" initials="F." surname="Qin">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Huanan Chen" initials="H." surname="Chen">
      <organization>China Telecom</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jaewhan Jin" initials="J." surname="Jin">
      <organization>LG U+</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jongyoon Shin" initials="J." surname="Shin">
      <organization>SK Telecom</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2019" month="December" day="31"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>As networks increase in scale and network operations become more sophisticated, traditional Operation, Administration and Maintenance (OAM) methods, which include proactive and reactive techniques, running in active and passive modes, become more susceptible to measurement accuracy and misconfiguration errors. With the advent of programmable data-plane, emerging on-path telemetry techniques provide unprecedented flow insight and realtime notification of network issues. This document enumerates the key deployment challenges for flow- oriented on-path telemetry techniques, especially in carrier operator networks. To address these issues, a high-level framework, In-situ Flow Information Telemetry (iFIT), is outlined. iFIT includes several essential functional components that can be materialized and assembled to implement a complete solution for on-path telemetry. This informational document aims to clarify the problem domain, and summarize the best practices and sensible system design considerations. The iFIT framework helps to guide the analysis on the current standard status and gaps, and motivate new works to complete the ecosystem. It also helps to inspire innovative network telemetry applications supporting advanced network operations. As a reference and open framework, iFIT does not specify the implementation of the components and the interfaces between the components. The compliance with iFIT framework is not mandatory for telemetry applications either.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-song-opsawg-ifit-framework-10"/>
</reference>