<reference anchor="I-D.sambo-opsawg-ccamp-supa-ext-yang-fsm">
  <front>
    <title>Extending YANG for events, actions, and finite state machine</title>
    <author>
      <organization abbrev="IETF">Internet Engineering Task Force</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Nicola Sambo">
      <organization>Scuola Superiore Sant'Anna</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Matteo Dallaglio">
      <organization>Scuola Superiore Sant'Anna</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Piero Castoldi">
      <organization>Scuola Superiore Sant'Anna</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Giuseppe Fioccola">
      <organization>Telecom Italia</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Andrea Di Giglio">
      <organization>Telecom Italia</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Filippo Cugini">
      <organization>CNIT</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Giacomo Bernini">
      <organization>Nextworks</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Pietro G. Giardina">
      <organization>Nextworks</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2017" month="June" day="28"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Network operators and service providers are facing the challenge of deployment of systems from different vendors while looking for a trade-off among transmission performance, network device reuse, and capital expenditure without the need of being tied to single vendor equipment. The deployment and operation of more dynamic and programmable transport optical network infrastructures can be driven by adopting model-driven and software-defined control and management paradigms. In this context, YANG enables to compile a set of consistent vendor-neutral data models for optical networks and components based on actual operational needs emerging from heterogeneous use cases. This document extends YANG from data to functional modeling in order to describe events, operations, and finite state machine of YANG-defined network elements. The proposed models can be applied in the context of optical networks to pre- instruct data plane devices (e.g., an optical transponder) on the actions to be performed (e.g., code adaptation) in case some events, such as physical layer degradations, occur.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-sambo-opsawg-ccamp-supa-ext-yang-fsm-00"/>
</reference>