<reference anchor="I-D.eckert-ietf-and-energy-overview" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-eckert-ietf-and-energy-overview-09">
  <front>
    <title>An Overview of Energy-related Effort within the IETF, IRTF, and IAB</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-eckert-ietf-and-energy-overview-09"/>
    <author initials="T. T." surname="Eckert" fullname="Toerless Eckert">
      <organization>Futurewei Technologies USA</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="M." surname="Boucadair" fullname="Mohamed Boucadair">
      <organization>Orange</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="P." surname="Thubert" fullname="Pascal Thubert">
      <organization>Cisco Systems, Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="J." surname="Tantsura" fullname="Jeff Tantsura">
      <organization>NVIDIA</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="C." surname="Pignataro" fullname="Carlos Pignataro">
      <organization>NC State University</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="06" month="September" year="2025"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>   This memo provides a compilation of existing work performed by or
   proposed within the IETF, the IRTF, and the IAB that relates to
   energy and sustainability: awareness, management, control, or
   reduction of energy consumption.

   The principal goal is to help IETF, IRTF, and IAB participants,
   especially newcomers and future contributors, become familiar with
   the body of work already published.  This document serves as the
   first catalog of such efforts, providing a consolidated internal
   reference.

   An additional goal is to raise awareness and interest in energy-
   related activities within the IETF, IRTF, and IAB, to continue
   identifying gaps and investigating solutions as appropriate.

   The scope of this document includes selected work from the IETF,
   IRTF, and IAB where relevant.  This document is descriptive in nature
   and does not propose new work items.

   This document captures work until 12/2022, when the "IAB workshop on
   Environmental Impact of Internet Applications and Systems"
   contextualized renewed community interest and discussion of the
   topic.  This memo itself does not recommend or direct future work.

	 </t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>