<reference anchor="I-D.whh-pce-capability-advertize" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-whh-pce-capability-advertize-00">
  <front>
    <title>PCEP Extension for INTERACTING-CAPBILITY</title>
    <author fullname="Minxue Wang" initials="M." surname="Wang">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Liuyan Han" initials="L." surname="Han">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Mianzhang Huang" initials="M." surname="Huang">
      <organization>CICT</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Zhen Han" initials="Z." surname="Han">
      <organization>CICT</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jinyou Dai" initials="J." surname="Dai">
      <organization>CICT</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2022" month="March" day="25"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>The PCE communication Protocol (PCEP) is used to convey path computation requests and responses both between Path Computation Clients (PCCs), Path Computation Elements (PCEs) and cooperating PCEs, support of traffic engineering in Multiprotocol Label Switching (MPLS), Generalized MPLS (GMPLS) and Segment Routing (SR) networks. In PCEP, due to the different implementing of PCC tunnel capability, especially bidirectional SR tunnels, the PCE can only provides path computation functions between the PCCs which adopt identical mechanisms. With the introduction and evolvement of 5G and other network scenarios, the scale of bearing and transport network has developed to a high level. On the other hand, with the improvement of network slicing ability, network equipments can provide network slicing service, such as enhanced VPNs (VPN+). Transport network employing time slot isolation technology, such as FlexE,MTN,can provide advanced timeslot slicing for the high quality customer services. The high quality customer services, for example industry production service, demand for superior SLA and end-to-end timeslot service slicing, regardless of whether it is across of different network equipment providers or across of different regions. Therefore, there is an urgent need of a method to support PCE to provide end-to-end path computation and establishment of SR tunnels regardless of PCC enables different protocol selections. This document specifies the extensions to PCE communication Protocol (PCEP) to carry bidirectional SR tunnel capability advertisement information in PCEP message to enhance PCE ability to perceive the protocol mechanism supported by PCC.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-whh-pce-capability-advertize-00"/>
</reference>