<reference anchor="I-D.cpaasch-ippm-responsiveness">
  <front>
    <title>Responsiveness under Working Conditions</title>
    <author fullname="Christoph Paasch" initials="C." surname="Paasch">
      <organization>Apple Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Randall Meyer" initials="R." surname="Meyer">
      <organization>Apple Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Stuart Cheshire" initials="S." surname="Cheshire">
      <organization>Apple Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Omer Shapira" initials="O." surname="Shapira">
      <organization>Apple Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2021" month="August" day="13"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Bufferbloat has been a long-standing problem on the Internet with more than a decade of work on standardizing technical solutions, implementations and testing. However, to this date, bufferbloat is still a very common problem for the end-users. Everyone "knows" that it is "normal" for a video conference to have problems when somebody else on the same home-network is watching a 4K movie. The reason for this problem is not the lack of technical solutions, but rather a lack of awareness of the problem-space, and a lack of tooling to accurately measure the problem. We believe that exposing the problem of bufferbloat to the end-user by measuring the end- users' experience at a high level will help to create the necessary awareness. This document is a first attempt at specifying a measurement methodology to evaluate bufferbloat the way common users are experiencing it today, using today's most frequently used protocols and mechanisms to accurately measure the user-experience. We also provide a way to express the bufferbloat as a measure of "Round-trips per minute" (RPM) to have a more intuitive way for the users to understand the notion of bufferbloat.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-cpaasch-ippm-responsiveness-00"/>
  <format type="TXT" target="https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-cpaasch-ippm-responsiveness-00.txt"/>
</reference>