<reference anchor="I-D.irtf-gaia-alternative-network-deployments">
  <front>
    <title>Alternative Network Deployments: Taxonomy, Characterization, Technologies, and Architectures</title>
    <author fullname="Jose Saldana" surname="Jose Saldana">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Andres Arcia-Moret" surname="Andres Arcia-Moret">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Bart Braem" surname="Bart Braem">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Ermanno Pietrosemoli" surname="Ermanno Pietrosemoli">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Arjuna Sathiaseelan" surname="Arjuna Sathiaseelan">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Marco Zennaro" surname="Marco Zennaro">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <date year="2016" month="July" day="18"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document presents a taxonomy of a set of "Alternative Network Deployments" that emerged in the last decade with the aim of bringing Internet connectivity to people or providing a local communication infrastructure to serve various complementary needs and objectives. They employ architectures and topologies different from those of mainstream networks and rely on alternative governance and business models. The document also surveys the technologies deployed in these networks, and their differing architectural characteristics, including a set of definitions and shared properties. The classification considers models such as Community Networks, Wireless Internet Service Providers (WISPs), networks owned by individuals but leased out to network operators who use them as a low-cost medium to reach the underserved population, networks that provide connectivity by sharing wireless resources of the users, and rural utility cooperatives.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-irtf-gaia-alternative-network-deployments-08"/>
  <format type="TXT" target="https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-irtf-gaia-alternative-network-deployments-08.txt"/>
</reference>