<reference anchor="I-D.yan-iba-routing-security-requirements" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-yan-iba-routing-security-requirements-00">
  <front>
    <title>Security Requirements for Intent-based Agent Routing</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-yan-iba-routing-security-requirements-00"/>
    <author initials="Y." surname="&#x4E25;&#x8C6B;" fullname="&#x4E25;&#x8C6B;">
      <organization>Institute of Computing Technology, Chinese Academy of Sciences</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="" surname="ShengSun" fullname="ShengSun">
      <organization>Institute of Computing Technology, Chinese Academy of Sciences</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="Q." surname="Gao" fullname="Qiangzhou Gao">
      <organization>Huawei</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="L." surname="Min" fullname="Liu Min">
      <organization>Institute of Computing Technology, Chinese Academy of Sciences</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="X." surname="Zhang" fullname="Xinyi Zhang">
      <organization>Computer Network Information Center, Chinese Academy of Sciences</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="08" month="April" year="2026"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>   This document specifies security requirements for intent-based agent
   routing.  It defines a security architecture, phase-specific attack
   surface analysis, and normative protections for the Registration,
   Resolution, and Dispatch phases of routing.  It also describes a
   secure operational process and an annotated interaction flow for
   protecting routing decisions, intent privacy, and capability
   integrity.

   Intent-based routing enables autonomous agents to collaborate based
   on semantic intent rather than static addresses, but this model
   introduces new security risks beyond those addressed by traditional
   channel protection and endpoint authentication.  Existing mechanisms
   such as Transport Layer Security (TLS) and Public Key Infrastructure
   (PKI) verify identity and protect transport, but do not constrain
   what an agent claims to be capable of, nor do they protect the
   semantic content of intent queries during routing.  This document
   establishes requirements to mitigate these risks and provides a
   comprehensive security framework for intent-based agent networks.

	 </t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>