<reference anchor="I-D.finzi-priority-switching-scheduler" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-finzi-priority-switching-scheduler-04">
  <front>
    <title>Priority Switching Scheduler</title>
    <author fullname="Fred Baker" initials="F." surname="Baker">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Anaïs Finzi" initials="A." surname="Finzi">
      <organization>TTTech Computertechnik AG</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Fabrice Frances" initials="F." surname="Frances">
      <organization>ISAE-SUPAERO</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Nicolas Kuhn" initials="N." surname="Kuhn">
      <organization>CNES</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Emmanuel Lochin" initials="E." surname="Lochin">
      <organization>ISAE-SUPAERO</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Ahlem Mifdaoui" initials="A." surname="Mifdaoui">
      <organization>ISAE-SUPAERO</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2018" month="October" day="22"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>We detail the implementation of a network rate scheduler based on both a packet-based implementation of the generalized processor sharing (GPS) and a strict priority policies. This credit based scheduler called Priority Switching Scheduler (PSS), inherits from the standard Strict Priority Scheduler (SP) but dynamically changes the priority of one or several queues. Usual scheduling architectures often combine rate schedulers with SP to implement DiffServ service classes. Furthermore, usual implementations of rate scheduler schemes (such as WRR, DRR,...) do not allow to efficiently guarantee the capacity dedicated to both AF and DF DiffServ classes as they mostly provide soft bounds. This means excessive margin is used to ensure the capacity requested and this impacts the number of additional users that could be accepted in the network. PSS allows a more predictable output rate per traffic class and is a one fit all scheme allowing to enable both SP and rate scheduling policies within a single algorithm.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-finzi-priority-switching-scheduler-04"/>
</reference>