<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-lisp-nexagon">
  <front>
    <title>Network-Hexagons:Geolocation Mobility Edge Network Based On H3 and LISP</title>
    <author fullname="Sharon Barkai" initials="S." surname="Barkai">
      <organization>Nexar Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Bruno Fernandez-Ruiz" initials="B." surname="Fernandez-Ruiz">
      <organization>Nexar Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Rotem Tamir" initials="R." surname="Tamir">
      <organization>Nexar Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Alberto Rodriguez-Natal" initials="A." surname="Rodriguez-Natal">
      <organization>Cisco Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Fabio Maino" initials="F." surname="Maino">
      <organization>Cisco Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Albert Cabellos-Aparicio" initials="A." surname="Cabellos-Aparicio">
      <organization>Universitat Politecnica de Catalunya</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jordi Paillisse" initials="J." surname="Paillisse">
      <organization>Universitat Politecnica de Catalunya</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Dino Farinacci" initials="D." surname="Farinacci">
      <organization>lispers.net</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2023" month="January" day="14"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This specification describes a mobility network that generates a dynamic map of road-routes and their current conditions. The map is generated by a network of vehicles equipped with vision AI and geolocation agents that apply consolidation AI functions. The map is generated using the Locator/IDSeparation Protocol (LISP) and a common data-model, H3 hierarchical hexagonal grid. Each geolocation agent is responsible for generating the dynamic map of its jurisdiction area tile-by-tile using data uploaded by vehicles. The network uses unique identifiers (HID) for each H3 tile in each resolution, and the geolocation agents' jurisdiction area HID is used as the basis for IPv6 endpoint identifiers (EIDs). The agents' EIDs are used as destination queues for vehicle uploads and source channels for map updates. The network uses algorithmic EID-based addressing of agents and vehicles, geospatial for agents and ephemeral for vehicles, as well as the LISP networking qualities to address issues such as geo- privacy, cache incoherency, context-switching, continuity, and scale of vehicles' subscriptions and notification replication.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-lisp-nexagon-47"/>
  <format type="TXT" target="https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-ietf-lisp-nexagon-47.txt"/>
</reference>