<reference anchor="I-D.tomlinson-epsfw">
  <front>
    <title>Extensible Proxy Services Framework
</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-tomlinson-epsfw-00"/>
    <author fullname="James Kempf" initials="J." surname="Kempf">
      <organization>Sun Microsystems</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Michael Condry" initials="M." surname="Condry">
      <organization>Sun Microsystems</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Hilarie Orman" initials="H." surname="Orman">
      <organization>Novell</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Gary Tomlinson" initials="G." surname="Tomlinson">
      <organization>Novell</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Dave A. Farber" initials="D. A." surname="Farber">
      <organization>Digital Island</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2000" month="July" day="17"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>In today's Internet, caching proxies that intermediate betweenHTTP (and increasingly streaming media) clients and serversprovide enhanced performance for Web page access. Both clientsand servers are increasingly looking to the network foradditional services that can't be provided directly on theclient or server, and Web proxies are an attractive place forlocating these services. In fact, some such services (contentassembly for advertising) are already being offered by Webproxies for servers, but in a nonstandard way. This documentdescribes the problem and solution requirements for astandardized, open and extensible service environment oncaching proxies which enables them to provide general servicesthat mediate, modify, and monitor object requests andresponses. It introduces an architectural framework along witha set of core requirements necessary to design standardizedimplementations for this application domain, taking intoaccount relevant IETF RFCs and IETF work-in-progress. Thearchitecture and requirements described here are mindful ofthe success of end-to-end nature of Internet client/serverinteractions, and the consequences of the proposedarchitectural changes on end-to-end semantics are discussed.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>