<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-lsr-dynamic-flooding-algorithm" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-ietf-lsr-dynamic-flooding-algorithm-03">
  <front>
    <title>An Algorithm for Computing Dynamic Flooding Topologies</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-lsr-dynamic-flooding-algorithm-03"/>
    <author initials="S." surname="Chen" fullname="Sarah Chen">
      <organization>Arista Networks</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="T." surname="Li" fullname="Tony Li">
      <organization>Hewlett Packard Enterprise</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="12" month="June" year="2026"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Link-state routing protocols suffer from excessive flooding in dense
   network topologies.  Dynamic flooding alleviates the problem by
   decoupling the flooding topology from the base topology.  Link-state
   protocol updates are flooded only on the sparse flooding topology
   while data traffic is still forwarded on the base topology.

   This document describes an algorithm to obtain a sparse subgraph from
   a dense graph.  The resulting subgraph has certain desirable
   properties and can be used as a flooding topology in dynamic
   flooding.

   This document discloses the algorithm that we have developed in order
   to make it easier for other developers to implement similar
   algorithms.  We do not claim that our algorithm is optimal, rather it
   is a pragmatic effort and we expect that further research and
   refinement can improve the results.

   We are not proposing that this algorithm be standardized, nor that
   the working group use this as a basis for further standardization
   work, however we have no objections if the working group chooses to
   do so.  This document is published as an Experimental RFC to gain
   operational and implementation experience with the specified dynamic
   flooding algorithm.  The intent is to assess the suitability of this
   algorithm for advancement to the Standards Track as a Proposed
   Standard, pending sufficient deployment experience and feedback from
   the community.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>