<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-mpls-tp-temporal-hitless-psm">
  <front>
    <title>Enhanced path segment monitoring</title>
    <author>
      <organization abbrev="IETF">Internet Engineering Task Force</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Alessandro D'Alessandro" initials="A." surname="D'Alessandro">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Loa Andersson" initials="L." surname="Andersson">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Manuel Paul" initials="M." surname="Paul">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Satoshi Ueno" initials="S." surname="Ueno">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Kaoru Arai" initials="K." surname="Arai">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Yoshinori Koike" initials="Y." surname="Koike">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <date year="2015" month="July" day="22"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>The MPLS transport profile (MPLS-TP) has been standardized to enable carrier-grade packet transport and complement converged packet network deployments. Among the most attractive features of MPLS-TP there are OAM functions, which enable network operators or service providers to provide various maintenance characteristics, such as fault location, survivability, performance monitoring and in-service/ out of service measurements. One of the most important mechanisms which is common for transport network operation is fault location. A segment monitoring function of a transport path is effective in terms of extension of the maintenance work and indispensable particularly when the OAM function is effective only between end points. However, the current approach defined for MPLS-TP for the segment monitoring (SPME) has some drawbacks. This document elaborates on the problem statement for the Sub-path Maintenance Elements (SPMEs) which provides monitoring of a portion of a set of transport paths (LSPs or MS-PWs). Based on the problems, this document specifies new requirements to consider a new improved mechanism of hitless transport path segment monitoring named Enhanced Path Segment Monitoring (EPSM).</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-mpls-tp-temporal-hitless-psm-07"/>
</reference>