<reference anchor="I-D.fuxh-mpls-delay-loss-te-framework">
  <front>
    <title>Traffic Engineering architecture for services aware MPLS</title>
    <author fullname="Qilei Wang" initials="Q." surname="Wang">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Vishwas Manral" initials="V." surname="Manral">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Spencer Giacalone" initials="S." surname="Giacalone">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Xihua Fu" initials="X." surname="Fu">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Malcolm Betts" initials="M." surname="Betts">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Dave McDysan" initials="D." surname="McDysan">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="John Drake" initials="J." surname="Drake">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Andrew G. Malis" initials="A. G." surname="Malis">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <date year="2011" month="November" day="13"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>With more and more enterprises using cloud based services, the distances between the user and the applications are growing. A lot of the current applications are designed to work across LAN's and have various inherent assumptions. For multiple applications such as High Performance Computing and Electronic Financial markets, the response times are critical as is packet loss, while other applications require more throughput. [RFC3031] describes the architecture of MPLS based networks. This draft extends the MPLS architecture to allow for latency, loss and jitter as properties. It describes requirements and control plane implication for latency and packet loss as a traffic engineering performance metric in today's network which is consisting of potentially multiple layers of packet transport network and optical transport network in order to make a accurate end-to-end latency and loss prediction before a path is established. Note MPLS architecture for Multicast will be taken up in a future version of the draft.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-fuxh-mpls-delay-loss-te-framework-03"/>
  <format type="TXT" target="https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-fuxh-mpls-delay-loss-te-framework-03.txt"/>
</reference>