<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-detnet-security">
  <front>
    <title>Deterministic Networking (DetNet) Security Considerations</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-detnet-security-04"/>
    <author>
      <organization abbrev="IETF">Internet Engineering Task Force</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Tal Mizrahi" initials="T." surname="Mizrahi">
      <organization>Huawei Network.IO Innovation Lab</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Ethan Grossman" initials="E." surname="Grossman">
      <organization>Dolby Laboratories, Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Andrew J. Hacker" initials="A. J." surname="Hacker">
      <organization>MistIQ Technologies, Inc</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Subir Das" initials="S." surname="Das">
      <organization>Applied Communication Sciences</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="John Dowdell" initials="J." surname="Dowdell">
      <organization>Airbus Defence and Space</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Henrik Austad" initials="H." surname="Austad">
      <organization>Cisco Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Kevin Stanton" initials="K." surname="Stanton">
      <organization>Intel</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Norman Finn" initials="N." surname="Finn">
      <organization>Huawei</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2019" month="March"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>A deterministic network is one that can carry data flows for real- time applications with extremely low data loss rates and bounded latency. Deterministic networks have been successfully deployed in real-time operational technology (OT) applications for some years (for example [ARINC664P7]). However, such networks are typically isolated from external access, and thus the security threat from external attackers is low. IETF Deterministic Networking (DetNet) specifies a set of technologies that enable creation of deterministic networks on IP-based networks of potentially wide area (on the scale of a corporate network) potentially bringing the OT network into contact with Information Technology (IT) traffic and security threats that lie outside of a tightly controlled and bounded area (such as the internals of an aircraft). These DetNet technologies have not previously been deployed together on a wide area IP-based network, and thus can present security considerations that may be new to IP- based wide area network designers. This draft, intended for use by DetNet network designers, provides insight into these security considerations. In addition, this draft collects all security- related statements from the various DetNet drafts (Architecture, Use Cases, etc) into a single location Section 7.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>