<reference anchor="I-D.pentikousis-icn-scenarios">
  <front>
    <title>ICN Baseline Scenarios</title>
    <author fullname="Kostas Pentikousis" initials="K." surname="Pentikousis">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Börje Ohlman" initials="B." surname="Ohlman">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Daniel Corujo" initials="D." surname="Corujo">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Gennaro Boggia" initials="G." surname="Boggia">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Gareth Tyson" initials="G." surname="Tyson">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Elwyn B. Davies" initials="E. B." surname="Davies">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Dorothy Gellert" initials="D." surname="Gellert">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Priya Mahadevan" initials="P." surname="Mahadevan">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <date year="2013" month="March" day="11"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document aims at establishing a common understanding about potential experimental setups where different information-centric networking (ICN) approaches can be tested and compared against each other while showcasing their advantages. Towards this end, we develop several scenarios in an iterative fashion, starting by reviewing pertinent ICN evaluations from the published literature. That is, the document includes scenarios which have all been considered in one or more performance evaluation studies and are already available to the community. The scenarios selected aim to exercise a variety of aspects that an ICN solution can address. On the one hand, we consider general aspects, such as, network efficiency, reduced complexity, increased scalability and reliability, mobility support, multicast and caching performance, real-time communication efficacy, energy consumption frugality, and disruption and delay tolerance. On the other hand, we focus on ICN- specific aspects, such as, information security and trust, persistence, availability, provenance, and location independence.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-pentikousis-icn-scenarios-02"/>
  <format type="TXT" target="https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-pentikousis-icn-scenarios-02.txt"/>
</reference>