<reference anchor="I-D.lourdelet-radext-ipv6-access">
  <front>
    <title>RADIUS attributes for IPv6 Access Networks</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-lourdelet-radext-ipv6-access-02"/>
    <author fullname="Benoit Lourdelet"/>
    <author fullname="Wojciech Dec"/>
    <author fullname="Behcet Sarikaya"/>
    <author fullname="Glen Zorn"/>
    <author fullname="David Miles"/>
    <date year="2009" month="December" day="17"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>IPv6 nodes can have configuration information provided to them usingDHCPv6 and/or Router Advertisements. This document specifies RADIUSattributes that complement RFC3162 for use with DHCPv6 and/or RouterAdvertisements (SLAAC) for use in network access scenarios.Status of this MemoThis Internet-Draft is submitted to IETF in full conformance with theprovisions of BCP 78 and BCP 79.Internet-Drafts are working documents of the Internet EngineeringTask Force (IETF), its areas, and its working groups. Note thatother groups may also distribute working documents as Internet-Drafts.Internet-Drafts are draft documents valid for a maximum of six monthsand may be updated, replaced, or obsoleted by other documents at anytime. It is inappropriate to use Internet-Drafts as referencematerial or to cite them other than as "work in progress."The list of current Internet-Drafts can be accessed athttp://www.ietf.org/ietf/1id-abstracts.txt.The list of Internet-Draft Shadow Directories can be accessed athttp://www.ietf.org/shadow.html.This Internet-Draft will expire on June 20, 2010.Copyright NoticeCopyright (c) 2009 IETF Trust and the persons identified as thedocument authors. All rights reserved.This document is subject to BCP 78 and the IETF Trust's LegalProvisions Relating to IETF Documents(http://trustee.ietf.org/license-info) in effect on the date ofpublication of this document. Please review these documentscarefully, as they describe your rights and restrictions with respectto this document. Code Components extracted from this document mustinclude Simplified BSD License text as described in Section 4.e ofthe Trust Legal Provisions and are provided without warranty asdescribed in the BSD License.This document may contain material from IETF Documents or IETFContributions published or made publicly available before November10, 2008. The person(s) controlling the copyright in some of thismaterial may not have granted the IETF Trust the right to allowmodifications of such material outside the IETF Standards Process.Without obtaining an adequate license from the person(s) controllingthe copyright in such materials, this document may not be modifiedoutside the IETF Standards Process, and derivative works of it maynot be created outside the IETF Standards Process, except to formatit for publication as an RFC or to translate it into languages otherthan English.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>