<reference anchor="I-D.kwbdgrr-tsvwg-net-collab-rqmts" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-kwbdgrr-tsvwg-net-collab-rqmts-00">
  <front>
    <title>Requirements for Network Collaboration Signaling</title>
    <author fullname="John Kaippallimalil" initials="J." surname="Kaippallimalil">
      <organization>Futurewei</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Dan Wing" initials="D." surname="Wing">
      <organization>Cloud Software Group Holdings, Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Sri Gundavelli" initials="S." surname="Gundavelli">
      <organization>Cisco</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Sridharan Rajagopalan" initials="S." surname="Rajagopalan">
      <organization>Cloud Software Group Holdings, Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Spencer Dawkins" initials="S." surname="Dawkins">
      <organization>Tencent America LLC</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Mohamed Boucadair" initials="M." surname="Boucadair">
      <organization>Orange</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Tirumaleswar Reddy.K" initials="T." surname="Reddy.K">
      <organization>Nokia</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2024" month="June" day="6"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Wireless networks (e.g., cellular or WLAN) experience significant but transient variations in link quality and have policy constraints (e.g., bandwidth) that affect user experience. Collaborative signaling (e.g., host-to-network and server-to-network) can improve the user experience by informing the network about the nature and relative importance of packets (frames, streams, etc.) without having to disclose the content of the packets. Moreover, the collaborative signalling may be enabled so that hosts are aware of the network's treatment of incoming packets. Also, host-to-network collaboration can be put in place without revealing the identity of the remote servers. This collaboration allows for differentiated services at the network (e.g., packet discard preference), the sender (e.g., adaptive transmission), or through cooperation of server / host and the network. This document lists some use cases that illustrate the need for a mechanism to share metadata and outlines requirements for both host- to-network (and vice versa) and server-to-network (and vice versa). The document focuses on intra-flow or flows bound to the same user.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-kwbdgrr-tsvwg-net-collab-rqmts-00"/>
</reference>