<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-anima-grasp-distribution">
  <front>
    <title>Information Distribution over GRASP</title>
    <author fullname="Xun Xiao" initials="X." surname="Xiao">
      <organization>MRC, Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Bing Liu" initials="B." surname="Liu">
      <organization>Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Artur Hecker" initials="A." surname="Hecker">
      <organization>MRC, Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Sheng Jiang" initials="S." surname="Jiang">
      <organization>Beijing University of Posts and
      Telecommunications</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2022" month="December" day="17"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Autonomic network infrastructure (ANI) is a generic platform for Autonomic Functions (AFs). In some scenarios, AFs may not only require communication capability supported from the infrastructure side, but also the capability the infrastructure can hold and re- distribute information on-demand. This document defines a set of solutions for information distribution in the ANI. Information distribution is categorized into two modes: 1) instantaneous distribution and 2) publishing for retrieval. In the former case, the information is sent, propagated and disposed of after reception. In the latter case, information needs to be stored in the network; additionally, conflict resolution is also needed when information stored in the network is updated with proposals from two different AFs. This document defines a series of extensions to GeneRic Autonomic Signaling Protocol (GRASP) in order to support such information distribution.the autonomic nodes and suggests an implementation based on GRASP. This document also describes typical use cases of them.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-anima-grasp-distribution-06"/>
  <format type="TXT" target="https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-ietf-anima-grasp-distribution-06.txt"/>
</reference>