<reference anchor="I-D.zhang-ioa-usage-accounting" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-zhang-ioa-usage-accounting-00">
  <front>
    <title>Verifiable Usage Accounting for Internet of Agents</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-zhang-ioa-usage-accounting-00"/>
    <author initials="L." surname="Zhang" fullname="Lianhua Zhang">
      <organization>AsiaInfo Technologies (China) Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="W." surname="Qiao" fullname="Wen Qiao">
      <organization>AsiaInfo Technologies (China) Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="W." surname="Zhang" fullname="Wei Zhang">
      <organization>AsiaInfo Technologies (China) Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="H." surname="Yang" fullname="Huiling Yang">
      <organization>AsiaInfo Technologies (China) Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="Y." surname="Li" fullname="Yun Li">
      <organization>AsiaInfo Technologies (China) Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="08" month="May" year="2026"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document describes a usage accounting and evidence framework for
   the Internet of Agents (IoA).  In cross-domain agent collaboration,
   agents may attach to gateways, discover capabilities, delegate
   subtasks, invoke tools, consume model or compute resources, and
   produce auditable outcomes.  Existing application logs or platform-
   specific billing interfaces are insufficient for interoperable
   accounting across agents, gateways, and administrative domains.

   This document defines requirements and a common object model for
   verifiable usage accounting, including Accounting Contexts, Metering
   Profiles, Measurement Dimensions, Usage Event Records, and Accounting
   Evidence References.  These objects are intended to support
   interoperable recording, correlation, export, verification,
   correction, and dispute handling for agent collaboration events.

   This document does not define pricing, charging policy, token
   issuance, financial settlement, revenue-sharing rules, invoices, or
   business support system interfaces.  It focuses on protocol-visible
   accounting records and evidence objects that may be used by other
   systems.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>