<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-mmusic-sdp-bundle-negotiation" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-ietf-mmusic-sdp-bundle-negotiation-46">
  <front>
    <title>Negotiating Media Multiplexing Using the Session Description Protocol (SDP)</title>
    <author fullname="Christer Holmberg" initials="C." surname="Holmberg">
      <organization>Ericsson</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Harald T. Alvestrand" initials="H. T." surname="Alvestrand">
      <organization>Google</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Cullen Fluffy Jennings" initials="C. F." surname="Jennings">
      <organization>Cisco</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2017" month="December" day="14"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This specification defines a new Session Description Protocol (SDP) Grouping Framework extension, 'BUNDLE'. The extension can be used with the SDP Offer/Answer mechanism to negotiate the usage of a single transport (5-tuple) for sending and receiving media described by multiple SDP media descriptions ("m=" sections). Such transport is referred to as a BUNDLE transport, and the media is referred to as bundled media. The "m=" sections that use the BUNDLE transport form a BUNDLE group. To assist endpoints in negotiating the use of bundle this specification defines a new SDP attribute, 'bundle-only', which can be used to request that specific media is only used if bundled. The specification also updates RFC 3264, to allow assigning a zero port value to a "m=" section without meaning that the media described by the "m=" section is disabled or rejected. When Real-time Transport Protocol (RTP)-based media is used, there are multiple ways to correlate bundled RTP packets with the appropriate "m=" section. This specification defines a new RTP Control Protocol (RTCP) source description (SDES) item and a new RTP header extension that provides an additional way to do this correlation by using them to carry a value that associates the RTP/ RTCP packets with a specific "m=" section.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-mmusic-sdp-bundle-negotiation-46"/>
</reference>