<reference anchor="I-D.conet-aeon-problem-statement" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-conet-aeon-problem-statement-01">
  <front>
    <title>Application Enabled Collaborative Networking: Problem Statement</title>
    <author fullname="Peng Fan" initials="P." surname="Fan">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="DENG Hui" initials="H." surname="Deng">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Mohamed Boucadair" initials="M." surname="Boucadair">
      <organization>France Telecom</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Tirumaleswar Reddy.K" initials="T." surname="Reddy.K">
      <organization>Cisco Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Charles Eckel" initials="C." surname="Eckel">
      <organization>Cisco Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Brandon Williams" initials="B." surname="Williams">
      <organization>Akamai, Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2014" month="July" day="3"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Identification and treatment of application flows are important to many application providers and network operators. They often rely on these capabilities to deploy and/or support a wide range of applications. These applications generate flows that may have specific connectivity requirements that can be met if made known to the network. Historically, this functionality has been implemented to the extent possible using heuristics, which inspect and infer flow characteristics. Heuristics may be based on port ranges, network separation (e.g. subnets or VLANs, Deep Flow Inspection (DFI), or Deep Packet Inspection (DPI). But many application flows in current usages are dynamic, adaptive, time-bound, encrypted, peer-to-peer, asymmetric, used on multipurpose devices, and have different priorities depending on direction of flow, user preferences, and other factors. Any combination of these properties renders heuristic based techniques less effective and may result in compromises to application security or user privacy.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-conet-aeon-problem-statement-01"/>
</reference>