<reference anchor="I-D.zhang-rvp-problem-statement" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-zhang-rvp-problem-statement-00">
  <front>
    <title>Problem Statements and Requirements of Real-Virtual Agent Protocol (RVP): Communication Protocol for Embodied Intelligence in Physical- Digital Continuum</title>
    <author fullname="Xiaoxun Zhang" initials="X." surname="Zhang">
      <organization>Hicagent</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Yunfei Zhang" initials="Y." surname="Zhang">
      <organization>China Telecom</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Chi Zhang" initials="C." surname="Zhang">
      <organization>China Telecom</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Min Zhang" initials="M." surname="Zhang">
      <organization>China Telecom</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Weijun Lu" initials="W." surname="Lu">
      <organization>SUPCON</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2025" month="October" day="21"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>The Real-Virtual Agent Protocol (RVP) enables seamless coordination between physical entities (robots, IoT devices, manufacturing systems and agents) and digital agents (AI systems, software agents, virtual twins) through unified composite identity management, physical/social/production relations graph-based coordination, and physical constraint integration. Unlike existing protocols that assume peer-to-peer digital relationships (A2A for agents, MCP for AI tools, ANP for agent networks), RVP unifies physical and digital agents communication and achieves physical data loop for online learning for embodied agents considering both hierarchical physical/social/production relations and physical world constraints. RVP is designed for immediate deployment in modern manufacturing, smart cities, autonomous mobility systems, and human-AI collaborative environments where non-peer, partially centralized relations and coordination is essential for real-world embodied intelligence networks.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-zhang-rvp-problem-statement-00"/>
</reference>