<reference anchor="I-D.opsawg-poweff" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-opsawg-poweff-00">
  <front>
    <title>Power and Energy Efficiency</title>
    <author fullname="Jan Lindblad" initials="J." surname="Lindblad">
      <organization>Cisco Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Snezana Mitrovic" initials="S." surname="Mitrovic">
      <organization>Cisco Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Marisol Palmero" initials="M." surname="Palmero">
      <organization>Cisco Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Gonzalo Salgueiro" initials="G." surname="Salgueiro">
      <organization>Cisco Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2023" month="October" day="20"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document motivates and specifies a data model to report power and energy efficiency of an asset. As highlighted during the IAB workshop on environmental impacts (https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-iab-ws-environmental- impacts-report-00), visibility is a very important first step (paraphrasing Peter Drucker's mantra of "You cannot improve what you don't measure"). During the workshop the need for standardized metrics was established, to avoid proprietary, double counting and even contradictory metrics across vendors. This Power and Energy Efficiency Telemetry Specification (POWEFF) is required to promote consistency across vendors and consumers, based on: 1. The definition of datasets and attributes defining a common data model utilized by the standard calculation to yield power and energy efficiency value for any asset or network element. 2. The standard calculations utilizing the specified datasets and attributes which will yield energy consumption and energy efficiency value for any asset or network element. The model provides information and data requirements for calculating the Power and Energy Efficiency for specific assets. Assets can include hardware (physical or virtual), software, applications, or services.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-opsawg-poweff-00"/>
</reference>