<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-netconf-ssh-client-server" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-ietf-netconf-ssh-client-server-21">
  <front>
    <title>YANG Groupings for SSH Clients and SSH Servers</title>
    <author fullname="Kent Watsen" initials="K." surname="Watsen">
      <organization>Watsen Networks</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Gary Wu" initials="G." surname="Wu">
      <organization>Cisco Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2020" month="July" day="10"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document defines three YANG modules: the first defines groupings for a generic SSH client, the second defines groupings for a generic SSH server, and the third defines common identities and groupings used by both the client and the server. It is intended that these groupings will be used by applications using the SSH protocol. Editorial Note (To be removed by RFC Editor) This draft contains placeholder values that need to be replaced with finalized values at the time of publication. This note summarizes all of the substitutions that are needed. No other RFC Editor instructions are specified elsewhere in this document. Artwork in this document contains shorthand references to drafts in progress. Please apply the following replacements: * "AAAA" --&gt; the assigned RFC value for draft-ietf-netconf-crypto- types * "BBBB" --&gt; the assigned RFC value for draft-ietf-netconf-trust- anchors * "CCCC" --&gt; the assigned RFC value for draft-ietf-netconf-keystore * "DDDD" --&gt; the assigned RFC value for draft-ietf-netconf-tcp- client-server * "EEEE" --&gt; the assigned RFC value for this draft Artwork in this document contains placeholder values for the date of publication of this draft. Please apply the following replacement: * "2020-07-10" --&gt; the publication date of this draft The following Appendix section is to be removed prior to publication: * Appendix A. Change Log</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-netconf-ssh-client-server-21"/>
</reference>