<reference anchor="I-D.davis-ccamp-photonic-plug-control-arch" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-davis-ccamp-photonic-plug-control-arch-02">
  <front>
    <title>Control Architecture of Optical Pluggables in Packet Devices Under ACTN POI Framework</title>
    <author fullname="Nigel Davis" initials="N." surname="Davis">
      <organization>Ciena</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Reza Rokui" initials="R." surname="Rokui">
      <organization>Ciena</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Praveen Maheshwari" initials="P." surname="Maheshwari">
      <organization>Airtel</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Uday Joshi" initials="U." surname="Joshi">
      <organization>Jio Reliance</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Bhavit Vadhadiya" initials="B." surname="Vadhadiya">
      <organization>Vi</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Xitiz Harshad Dave" initials="X. H." surname="Dave">
      <organization>Vi</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Aihua Guo" initials="A." surname="Guo">
      <organization>Futurewei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2023" month="September" day="29"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This draft presents an additional architectural option for control of packet over optical networks by extending and complementing the IETF draft-poidt-ccamp-actn-poi-pluggable and by introducing an additional approach for control of optical plugs in packet devices. It provides the direct read/write access of coherent plugs to the optical controller, thereby allowing the end-to-end optical service management. The approach, introduced in this draft, can be further generalized to support other uses cases. The architectural option for control of packet over optical networks, introduced by this draft, also provides a clear separation between control of packet functions and control of optical functions. The packet and optical controls are partitioned so that the functions specializing in control of the optical capabilities can control corresponding functions in packet devices, optical devices or both without interfering with packet control functions.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-davis-ccamp-photonic-plug-control-arch-02"/>
</reference>