<reference anchor="I-D.mozleywilliams-dnsop-dnsaid" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-mozleywilliams-dnsop-dnsaid-02">
  <front>
    <title>DNS for AI Discovery</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-mozleywilliams-dnsop-dnsaid-02"/>
    <author initials="J." surname="Mozley" fullname="Jim Mozley">
      <organization>Infoblox, Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="N." surname="Williams" fullname="Nic Williams">
      <organization>Infoblox, Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="B." surname="Sarikaya" fullname="Behcet Sarikaya">
      <organization>Unaffiliated</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="R." surname="Schott" fullname="Roland Schott">
      <organization>Deutsche Telekom</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="J." surname="Damick" fullname="Jeffrey Damick">
      <organization>Amazon</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="27" month="May" year="2026"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>The document standardizes an approach for publishing AI agents in the
   Domain Name System (DNS) so that other agents can discover them.
   Discovery is then initiated based on one of three generic use cases,
   in increasing computational and latency cost: (1) the requestor knows
   both the organization and agent (2) the requestor knows the
   organization that provides a capability, but not the specific agent
   (3) the requestor knows the required capability, but not the
   organization or agent.  Of these use cases only (1) and (2) are in
   scope for this document, although (3) can be derived from this
   specification.

   DNS for AI Discovery (DNS-AID) is designed so that, once a client has
   learned an organization's agents, subsequent transactions can utilize
   the first use case with the benefit of cacheable connectivity
   information that is learnable as an agentic skill.  The mechanism
   uses Service Binding (SVCB) records for connectivity information and
   key meta data, a well known entry point using DNS-Based Service
   Discovery (DNS-SD) labels into an organization's agent index, and
   optionally DNS Security Extensions (DNSSEC) and DNS-Based
   Authentication of Named Entities (DANE) TLSA records for trust and
   security.  DNS-AID provides consumers of agent services with a direct
   connection method for agentic workloads not mediated by a third
   party.  Organizations can use the same approach across public and
   private networks networks, providing consistency and common
   operational models, including publishing agents that are hosted in
   service provider domains.

   This document introduces no new resource record types, opcodes, or
   response codes.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>