<reference anchor="I-D.nieminen-core-service-discovery">
  <front>
    <title>Constrained Application Autoconfiguration</title>
    <author fullname="Johanna Nieminen" initials="J." surname="Nieminen">
      <organization>Nokia</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Basavaraj Patil" initials="B." surname="Patil">
      <organization>Nokia</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Teemu Savolainen" initials="T." surname="Savolainen">
      <organization>Nokia</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Markus Isomaki" initials="M." surname="Isomaki">
      <organization>Nokia</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Zach Shelby" initials="Z." surname="Shelby">
      <organization>Sensinode</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Carles Gomez" initials="C." surname="Gomez">
      <organization>Universitat Politecnica de</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Mehmet Ersue" initials="M." surname="Ersue">
      <organization>Nokia Siemens Networks</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2012" month="March" day="12"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>The number and types of devices that are Internet connected continues to grow. Sensors, appliances, utility meters, medical devices etc. are Internet connected for various reasons. Many of these newer devices are constrained in terms of processing power, memory, communication capability and, available power. Devices such as sensors and similar very small devices often lack a proper user interface and hence configuring even the most basic parameters for enabling Internet connectivity on these is extremely difficult. Some of the existing configuration protocols can help in autoconfiguring various parameters of the IP stack needed for Internet connectivity. However this is not sufficient if the devices are using a web service application. There is a need for additional information such as service provider name and username/password etc. for authentication etc. A configuration protocol solution for resource constrained devices is needed in order to enable the potential enabled by Internet connectivity. This document outlines the use cases and requirements for user friendly configuration of such information on a constrained device, and specifies a Constrained Application Protocol (CoAP) based mechanism to meet the requirements.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-nieminen-core-service-discovery-02"/>
  <format type="TXT" target="https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-nieminen-core-service-discovery-02.txt"/>
</reference>