<reference anchor="I-D.xu-nmrg-idp-framework" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-xu-nmrg-idp-framework-00">
  <front>
    <title>Intelligent Data Plane (IDP): Framework and Protocol Considerations</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-xu-nmrg-idp-framework-00"/>
    <author initials="K." surname="Xu" fullname="Ke Xu">
      <organization>Tsinghua University &amp; Zhongguancun Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="L." surname="Zhu" fullname="Liang Zhu">
      <organization>Zhongguancun Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="X." surname="&#x9AD8;&#x7FD4;&#x5B87;" fullname="&#x9AD8;&#x7FD4;&#x5B87;">
      <organization>Tsinghua University</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="Y." surname="Zhang" fullname="Yinchao Zhang">
      <organization>Tsinghua University</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="31" month="May" year="2026"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document describes a framework and protocol considerations for
   an Intelligent Data Plane (IDP).  An IDP enables data-plane nodes to
   perform bounded, policy-constrained, and observable packet, flow,
   state, telemetry, or service processing based on standardized signals
   and locally executable decision functions.

   The document defines terminology, a reference architecture, signal
   and result models, decision function abstractions, and communication
   patterns for IDP systems.  It focuses on the interfaces and data
   formats through which IDP nodes expose signals, features, and results
   to AI for Network Management (AI-NM) systems, and through which they
   receive models, policies, and configuration from control and
   management entities in a self-driving and self-managing network (SD/
   MN) context.

   This document does not define a specific AI or ML algorithm, nor does
   it require data-plane nodes to perform model training.  Instead, it
   focuses on the interoperable communication patterns and data
   representations required to integrate intelligent data-plane
   processing into AI-NM and self-managing network architectures.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>