<reference anchor="I-D.fz-spring-srv6-alt-mark" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-fz-spring-srv6-alt-mark-12">
  <front>
    <title>Application of the Alternate Marking Method to the Segment Routing Header</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-fz-spring-srv6-alt-mark-12"/>
    <author initials="G." surname="Fioccola" fullname="Giuseppe Fioccola">
      <organization>Huawei</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="T." surname="Zhou" fullname="Tianran Zhou">
      <organization>Huawei</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="M." surname="Cociglio" fullname="Mauro Cociglio">
      <organization>Telecom Italia</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="G. S." surname="Mishra" fullname="Gyan Mishra">
      <organization>Verizon Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="X." surname="wang" fullname="xuewei wang">
      <organization>Ruijie</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="G." surname="Zhang" fullname="Geng Zhang">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="06" month="June" year="2025"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>   The Alternate Marking Method is a passive performance measurement
   method based on marking consecutive batches of packets, which can be
   used to measure packet loss, latency, and jitter of live traffic.
   This method requires a packet marking method so that packet flows can
   be distinguished and identified.

   A mechanism to carry suitable packet marking in the Hop-by-Hop Header
   and the Destination Options Header of an IPv6 packet is described in
   RFC 9343 and is also applicable to Segment Routing for IPv6 (SRv6).

   This document describes an alternative experimental approach that
   uses a new TLV in the Segment Routing Header (SRH) of an SRv6 packet.
   This approach has been implemented and has potential scaling and
   simplification benefits over the technique described in RFC 9343.
   The experiment is to determine whether those benefits are significant
   and attractive to the community: if they are, the work may be brought
   back for IETF consideration.

   This protocol extension has been developed outside the IETF as an
   alternative to the IETF’s standards track specification RFC 9343 and
   it does not have IETF consensus.  It is published here to guide
   experimental implementation, ensure interoperability among
   implementations to better determine the value of this approach.

	 </t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>