<reference anchor="I-D.many-ip-optical-framework" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-many-ip-optical-framework-03">
  <front>
    <title>IP over Optical Networks - A Framework</title>
    <author fullname="Dr. Bala Rajagopalan" initials="B." surname="Rajagopalan">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Dr. James V. Luciani" initials="J. V." surname="Luciani">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Daniel O. Awduche" initials="D. O." surname="Awduche">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Bradley Cain" initials="B." surname="Cain">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Bilel Jamoussi" initials="B." surname="Jamoussi">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Dr. Debanjan Saha" initials="D." surname="Saha">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <date year="2001" month="March" day="5"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>The Internet transport infrastructure is moving towards a model of high-speed routers interconnected by optical core networks. A consensus is emerging in the industry on utilizing IP-centric protocols for the optical control plane [9, 10], as well as for dynamic bandwidth provisioning for IP services. Also, there has recently been significant activity in defining models for IP transport over optical networks, specifically, the routing and signaling aspects [2,6,7]. This draft attempts to define a framework for IP over Optical networks, considering both the IP control plane for optical networks as well as IP transport over optical networks (together referred to as 'IP over optical networks'). Within this framework, we develop a common set of terms and concepts which allows to discuss these IP over optical technologies in a consistent fashion. Additionally, this draft surveys some architectural frameworks that might be useful and appropriate for the deployment of IP over hybrid optical networks that contain IP routers, WDM multiplexers, and optical cross-connects (OXCs). This document is complementary to the framework of Multiprotocol Lambda Switching proposed in [2].</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-many-ip-optical-framework-03"/>
</reference>