<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-rap-frameworkpib">
  <front>
    <title>Framework Policy Information Base</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-rap-frameworkpib-09"/>
    <author>
      <organization abbrev="IETF">Internet Engineering Task Force</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Kwok Ho Chan" initials="K. H." surname="Chan">
      <organization>Nortel Networks</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Scott D. Hahn" initials="S. D." surname="Hahn">
      <organization>Intel Labs</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Ravi Sahita" initials="R." surname="Sahita">
      <organization>Intel Labs</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Keith McCloghrie" initials="K." surname="McCloghrie">
      <organization>Cisco Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2002" month="June" day="10"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document defines a set of PRovisioning Classes (PRCs) and textual conventions that are common to all clients that provision policy using Common Open Policy Service (COPS) protocol for Provisioning. Structure of Policy Provisioning Information (SPPI) describes a structure for specifying policy information that can then be transmitted to a network device for the purpose of configuring policy at that device. The model underlying this structure is one of well-defined (PRCs) and instances of these classes (PRIs) residing in a virtual information store called the Policy Information Base (PIB). One way to provision policy is by means of the (COPS) protocol with the extensions for provisioning. This protocol supports multiple clients, each of which may provision policy for a specific policy domain such as QoS, virtual private networks, or security. As described in COPS usage for Policy Provisioning (COPS-PR), each client supports a non-overlapping and independent set of PIB modules. However, some PRovisioning Classes are common to all subject-categories (client-types) and need to be present in each.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>