<reference anchor="I-D.birrane-dtn-rel" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-birrane-dtn-rel-02">
  <front>
    <title>Reliability Considerations for Delay-Tolerant Networks</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-birrane-dtn-rel-02"/>
    <author initials="E. J." surname="Birrane" fullname="Edward J. Birrane">
      <organization>JHU/APL</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="S. L." surname="Pellegrini" fullname="Sabrina Lidia Pellegrini">
      <organization>JHU/APL</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="A." surname="White" fullname="Alex White">
      <organization>JHU/APL</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="06" month="July" year="2026"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>The Delay-Tolerant Networking (DTN) architecture describes a type of
   challenged network in which communications may be significantly
   affected by long signal propagation delays, frequent link
   disruptions, or both.  These unique and challenging characteristics
   require adapted approaches for data transport, security, management,
   routing, and other networking functions.  Using new approaches, DTNs
   can offer data services in environments that would be considered
   neither reliable nor resilient as these concepts are understood for
   unchallenged networks.

   This document identifies adapted definitions and concepts for DTN
   reliability and resiliency that can be applied even when there is no
   simultaneous, reliable, end-to-end path between sources and
   destinations in the network.  These definitions and concepts are
   suitable for any challenged environment but, in particular, those
   communicating using the DTN Bundle Protocol (BP).  The ability to
   overlay BP across multiple discontinuous underlay networks, to store-
   and-forward data where and as necessary, and the structure and
   security of the BPv7 bundle itself provide novel ways to identify,
   implement, signal, and otherwise consider guarantees associated with
   data exchange in the DTN environment.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>