<reference anchor="I-D.huang-rtgwg-us-standalone-sid" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-huang-rtgwg-us-standalone-sid-00">
  <front>
    <title>Use Cases-Standalone Service ID in Routing Network</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-huang-rtgwg-us-standalone-sid-00"/>
    <author initials="D." surname="Huang" fullname="Daniel Huang">
      <organization>ZTE Corporation</organization>
    </author>
    <author surname="陈戈" fullname="陈戈">
      <organization>China Telecom</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="J." surname="Liang" fullname="Jie Liang">
      <organization>China Telecom</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="Y." surname="Zhang" fullname="Yan Zhang">
      <organization>China Unicom</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="F." surname="Yang" fullname="Feng Yang">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="D." surname="Yang" fullname="Dong Yang">
      <organization>Beijing Jiaotong University</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="D." surname="Yuan" fullname="Dongyu Yuan">
      <organization>ZTE Corporation</organization>
    </author>
    <author surname="付华楷" fullname="付华楷">
      <organization>ZTE Corporation</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="C." surname="Huang" fullname="Cheng Huang">
      <organization>ZTE Corporation</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="Y." surname="Guo" fullname="Yong Guo">
      <organization>ZTE Corporation</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="28" month="January" year="2024"></date>
    <abstract>
      <t>   More and more emerging applications have raised the demand for
   establishing networking connections anywhere and anytime, alongside
   the availability of highly distributive any-cloud services.  Such a
   demand motivates the need to efficiently interconnect heterogeneous
   entities, e.g., different domains of network and cloud owned by
   different providers, with the goal of reducing cost, e.g., overheads
   and end-to-end latency, while ensuring the overall performance
   satisfies the requirements of the applications.  Considering that
   different network domains and cloud providers may adopt different
   types of technologies, the key of interconnection and efficient
   coordination is to employ a unified interface that can be understood
   by heterogeneous parties which could derive the consistent
   requirements of the same service and treat the service traffic
   appropriately by their proprietary policies and technologies.

   This document provides use cases and problem statements from two main
   Internet traffic categories: one is the traditional north-south
   traffic which is defined from clients to entities (such as servers or
   DCs), and the other is east-west traffic which refers to traffic
   between entities (such as inter-server or inter-service).The
   requirements for a standalone Service ID are also derived.

	 </t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>