<reference anchor="I-D.kompella-rtgwg-mlnwsched" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-kompella-rtgwg-mlnwsched-01">
  <front>
    <title>Scheduling Network Resources for Machine Learning Clusters</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-kompella-rtgwg-mlnwsched-01"/>
    <author initials="K." surname="Kompella" fullname="Kireeti Kompella">
      <organization>Juniper Networks</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="V. P." surname="Beeram" fullname="Vishnu Pavan Beeram">
      <organization>Juniper Networks</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="A." surname="Mahale" fullname="Aditya Mahale">
      <organization>Cerebras Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="R." surname="Bhargava" fullname="Raghav Bhargava">
      <organization>Crusoe</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="02" month="November" year="2025"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Large Language Models (LLMs) are pushing the boundaries of
   technology.  The scale that they have reached currently vastly
   exceeds the capacity of any single compute unit (XPU); this requires
   a distributed approach where multiple XPUs are connected via a
   "backend" network, sometimes in a single data center, but
   increasingly in multiple data centers connected by a "data center
   interconnect" (DCI).  We are approaching the point where the scale
   exceeds that of a single data center, thus requiring multiple such
   data centers connected via a "data center interconnect" network.
   Training and inferencing are expensive and critical operations, thus
   they are typically scheduled, i.e., the (compute) resources they need
   are carefully estimated, allocated and deployed so that these
   resources are efficiently used.  However, while compute investment in
   these LLM processing clusters dwarfs that of networks, it is becoming
   increasingly clear that the latter can greatly impact the former.
   This has been the focus of recent conferences, including the fantel
   Birds of a Feather meeting in IETF 123, @Scale: Networking 2025 and
   Open Compute Project 2025.

   This memo proposes that the same care that is taken regarding
   allocation of compute resources to jobs be taken with networking
   resources: that they are estimated, allocated and deployed alongside
   compute resources; that they have contingency plans in case of
   network glitches; and that a holistic view be taken in order to
   optimize job completion times of training and inferencing jobs.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>