<reference anchor="I-D.lai-bmwg-istn-methodology">
  <front>
    <title>Problems and Requirements of Evaluation Methodology for Integrated Space and Terrestrial Networks</title>
    <author>
      <organization abbrev="IETF">Internet Engineering Task Force</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Zeqi Lai">
      <organization>Tsinghua University</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Hewu Li">
      <organization>Tsinghua University</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Yangtao Deng">
      <organization>Tsinghua University</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Qian Wu">
      <organization>Tsinghua University</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jun Liu">
      <organization>Tsinghua University</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2021" month="October" day="25"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>With the rapid evolution of the aerospace industry, many "NewSpace" upstarts are actively deploying their mega-constellations in low Earth orbits (LEO) and building integrated space and terrestrial networks (ISTN), promising to provide pervasive, low-latency, and high-throughput Internet service globally. Due to the high manufacturing, launching, and updating cost of LEO mega- constellations, it is expected that ISTNs can be well designed and evaluated before the launch of satellites. However, the progress of designing, assessing, and understanding new network functionalities and protocols for futuristic ISTNs faces a substantial obstacle: lack of standardized evaluation methodology with acceptable realism, flexibility, and cost that can involve the unique dynamic behaviors of ISTNs. This memo first reviews the unique characteristics of LEO mega-constellations. Further, it analyzes the limitation of existing network evaluation and analysis methodologies under ISTN environments. Finally, it outlines the key requirements of future evaluation methodology tailored for ISTNs.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-lai-bmwg-istn-methodology-00"/>
</reference>