<reference anchor="I-D.gupta-emu-eap-wsim" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-gupta-emu-eap-wsim-00">
  <front>
    <title>EAP-WSIM: A SIM-Based EAP Method Using the MILENAGE-ECDH-FWD Authentication Construction</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-gupta-emu-eap-wsim-00"/>
    <author initials="P." surname="Gupta" fullname="Praveen Gupta">
      <organization>MobileStack</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="24" month="April" year="2026"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>   This document specifies EAP-WSIM, a new EAP authentication method
   for enterprise wireless networks that performs offline mutual
   authentication without contacting any Mobile Network Operator (MNO)
   Home Subscriber Server (HSS), Home Location Register (HLR), or
   Unified Data Management (UDM) function during the authentication
   exchange.

   EAP-WSIM uses a new cryptographic construction called MILENAGE-
   ECDH-FWD, which combines the MILENAGE authentication and key
   agreement algorithm [TS35.205] with an ephemeral Elliptic Curve
   Diffie-Hellman (ECDH) exchange.  This construction simultaneously
   provides mutual authentication via MILENAGE challenge-response and
   forward secrecy via ephemeral ECDH, such that compromise of long-
   term key material does not expose keys from prior sessions.

   The key distinction from all existing SIM-based EAP methods --
   EAP-SIM [RFC4186], EAP-AKA [RFC4187], EAP-AKA' [RFC9048], and
   EAP-AKA' FS [RFC9678] -- is that EAP-WSIM requires no MNO backend
   contact during authentication.  The EAP server holds a SIM card
   (the WSIM) that functions as a self-contained Authentication Centre,
   enabling deployment in air-gapped enterprise environments without
   MNO infrastructure dependency.

   This document specifies the protocol core: the four-round EAP-WSIM
   exchange, message formats, attribute encodings, and key derivation.
   Key slot selection [WSIM-KEY-SELECT] and IEEE 802.11r Fast
   Transition integration [WSIM-FT] will be submitted as additional
   specifications only if required based on review and comments on
   this document.

   This document does not update any existing RFC.

	 </t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>