<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-mpls-mna-nrp-selector" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-ietf-mpls-mna-nrp-selector-04">
  <front>
    <title>MPLS Network Actions for Network Resource Partition Selector</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-mpls-mna-nrp-selector-04"/>
    <author initials="T." surname="Li" fullname="Tony Li">
      <organization>HPE</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="V. P." surname="Beeram" fullname="Vishnu Pavan Beeram">
      <organization>HPE</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="J." surname="Drake" fullname="John Drake"/>
    <author initials="T." surname="Saad" fullname="Tarek Saad">
      <organization>Cisco Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="I." surname="Meilik" fullname="Israel Meilik">
      <organization>Broadcom</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="08" month="April" year="2026"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>An IETF Network Slice service provides connectivity coupled with a
   set of network resource commitments and is expressed in terms of one
   or more connectivity constructs.  A Network Resource Partition (NRP)
   is a collection of resources identified in the underlay network to
   support IETF Network Slice services.  A Slice-Flow Aggregate refers
   to the set of traffic streams from one or more connectivity
   constructs belonging to one or more IETF Network Slices that are
   mapped to a specific NRP and provide the same forwarding treatment.
   The packets associated with a Slice-Flow Aggregate may carry a
   marking in the packet's network layer header to identify this
   association and this marking is referred to as NRP Selector.  The NRP
   Selector is used to map the packet to the associated NRP and provides
   the corresponding forwarding treatment to the packet.

   MPLS Network Actions (MNA) technologies are used to indicate actions
   for Label Switched Paths (LSPs) and/or MPLS packets and to transfer
   data needed for these actions.  This document specifies options for
   using MPLS Network Actions (MNAs) to carry the NRP Selector in MPLS
   packets.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>