<reference anchor="I-D.crawley-rsvp-over-atm">
  <front>
    <title>Issues for RSVP and Integrated Services over ATM</title>
    <author fullname="Fred Baker" initials="F." surname="Baker">
      <organization>Cisco Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Dr. Marty Borden" initials="M." surname="Borden">
      <organization>E. Crawley</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="John J. Krawczyk" initials="J. J." surname="Krawczyk">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Steven Berson" initials="S." surname="Berson">
      <organization>ISI</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Eric S. Crawley" initials="E. S." surname="Crawley">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <date year="1996" month="March" day="12"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>The RSVP and Integrated Services working groups have been working towards the goal of an 'Integrated Services Internet' where applications can request a Quality of Service (QoS) from the network in order to meet their end-to- end service requirements. Simultaneously, the IP-over-ATM working group has been specifying the requirements and interactions between IP and Asynchronous Transfer Mode (ATM) technology. The internals and interoperability of ATM devices are specified by the ATM Forum and its working groups. One of the features of ATM technology is the ability to request a virtual circuit (VC) with a specified QoS. Obviously, it would be useful for the work of the Integrated Services Internet to be able to take advantage of the QoS abilities of ATM. This document outlines the issues related to running RSVP and Integrated Service models over ATM and presents an initial attempt at dividing up the issues between the various working groups and organizations. This is intended as a starting point for the discussions in the joint IP-ATM, RSVP, and Int-Serv meeting to be held at the Los Angeles IETF meeting in March, 1996.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-crawley-rsvp-over-atm-00"/>
</reference>