<reference anchor="I-D.leeking-teas-actn-problem-statement" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-leeking-teas-actn-problem-statement-00">
  <front>
    <title>Problem Statement for Abstraction and Control of Transport Networks</title>
    <author fullname="Young Lee" initials="Y." surname="Lee">
      <organization>Huawei</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Daniel King" initials="D." surname="King">
      <organization>Lancaster University</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Mohamed Boucadair" initials="M." surname="Boucadair">
      <organization>France Telecom</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Ruiquan Jing" initials="R." surname="Jing">
      <organization>China Telecom</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Luis M. Contreras" initials="L. M." surname="Contreras">
      <organization>Telefonica</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2015" month="June" day="9"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Transport networks that provide connectivity and bandwidth for customer services have typically been static, lacking flexibility, and requiring long planning times when deploying new services. Network Providers and Service Providers have embraced technologies that allow separation of data plane and control plane, distributed signaling for path setup and protection, and centralized path computation for service planning and traffic engineering. Although these technologies provide significant benefits, they do not meet the growing need for network programmability, automation, resource sharing, and service elasticity necessary to meet operators' requirements for virtual network operation. Virtual network operation refers to the creation of a virtualized environment allowing operators to view the abstraction of the underlying multi-administration, multi- vendor, multi-technology networks and to operate, control, and manage these multiple networks as if a single virtualized network. Another dimension of virtual network operation is the use of common core transport network resources by multi-tenant service networks as a way of providing a virtualized infrastructure to flexibly offer new services and applications. The work effort investigating this problem space is known as Abstraction and Control of Transport Networks (ACTN). This document provides an ACTN problem description, a scope of work, and outlines the core objectives and requirements to facilitate virtual network operation.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-leeking-teas-actn-problem-statement-00"/>
</reference>