<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-spirits-lucentocc">
  <front>
    <title>On a pre-SPIRITS Implementation in the Lucent Technologies Online Communications Center</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-spirits-lucentocc-00"/>
    <author fullname="John Voelker" initials="J." surname="Voelker">
      <organization>Lucent Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Mark Weissman" initials="M." surname="Weissman">
      <organization>Lucent Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Hui-Lan Lu" initials="H." surname="Lu">
      <organization>Lucent Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Igor Faynberg" initials="I." surname="Faynberg">
      <organization>Lucent Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Weizhong Zhang" initials="W." surname="Zhang">
      <organization>Lucent Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2000" month="February" day="16"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document describes the pre-SPIRITS Implementation of theSPIRITS-like services in the Lucent Technologies OnlineCommunications Center (OCC). To this end, this document is acontribution to the future Informational RFC, which is to bepublished by the SPIRITS WG as indicated in its charter.On the PSTN side, the OCC platform systematically uses theIntelligent Network (IN) solutions, which were industry-proven to bereliable, scalable, and compatible with the existing PSTNinfrastructure and services, yet easily adaptable to the Internetrequirements. Other essential elements of the platform include theuse of1) Session Initiation Protocol (SIP) messaging services2) Point-to-Point (PPP) Protocol3) Interactions with the Voice-over-IP (VoIP) Gateway and Gatekeeperfor establishing the combined voice path through PSTN and Internet4) Microsoft NetMeeting (tm) software at the end-users' PCs (orInternet appliances)5) Java (tm) Run-Time Environment (JRE), and6) 1.2 Java Native Interface (JNI) for certain security capabilities</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>