<reference anchor="I-D.irtf-nfvrg-gaps-network-virtualization" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-irtf-nfvrg-gaps-network-virtualization-01">
  <front>
    <title>Gap Analysis on Network Virtualization Activities</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-irtf-nfvrg-gaps-network-virtualization-01"/>
    <author initials="C. J." surname="Bernardos" fullname="Carlos J. Bernardos"/>
    <author initials="A." surname="Rahman" fullname="Akbar Rahman"/>
    <author initials="J. C." surname="Z&#xFA;&#xF1;iga" fullname="Juan-Carlos Z&#xFA;&#xF1;iga"/>
    <author initials="L. M." surname="Contreras" fullname="Luis M. Contreras"/>
    <author initials="P. A." surname="Aranda" fullname="Pedro A. Aranda"/>
    <date day="08" month="July" year="2016"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>   This document describes open research challenges for network
   virtualization.  Network virtualization is following a similar path
   as previously taken by Cloud computing.  Specifically, Cloud
   computing popularized migration of computing functions (e.g.,
   applications) and storage from local, dedicated, physical resources
   to remote virtual functions accessible through the Internet.  In a
   similar manner, network virtualization is encouraging migration of
   networking functions from dedicated physical hardware nodes to a
   virtualized pool of resources.  However, network virtualization can
   be considered to be a more complex problem than Cloud computing as it
   not only involves virtualization of computing and storage functions
   but also involves abstraction of the network itself.  This document
   describes current research challenges in network virtualization
   including service guarantees, energy efficiency, supporting multiple
   domains, network slicing, self-management, privacy and security.  In
   addition, some proposals are made for new activities in IETF/IRTF
   that could address some of these challenges.

	 </t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>