<reference anchor="I-D.huitema-megaco-mgcp-v0r1">
  <front>
    <title>Media Gateway Control Protocol (MGCP)</title>
    <author>
      <organization abbrev="IETF">Internet Engineering Task Force</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Christian Huitema" initials="C." surname="Huitema">
      <organization>Bellcore</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Mauricio Arango" initials="M." surname="Arango">
      <organization>RSL COM</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Isaac K. Elliott" initials="I. K." surname="Elliott">
      <organization>Level3 Communications</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Andrew Dugan" initials="A." surname="Dugan">
      <organization>Level3 Communications</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Scott Pickett" initials="S." surname="Pickett">
      <organization>Vertical Networks</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="1999" month="February" day="22"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document describes an application programming interface and a corresponding protocol (MGCP) for controlling Voice over IP (VoIP) Gate- ways from external call control elements. MGCP assumes a call control architecture where the call control 'intelligence' is outside the gateways and handled by external call control elements. The document is structured in 6 main sections: * The introduction presents the basic assumptions and the relation to other protocols such as H.323, RTSP, SAP or SIP. * The interface section presents a conceptual overview of the MGCP, presenting the naming conventions, the usage of the session description protocol SDP, and the procedures that compose MGCP: Notifications Request, Notification, Create Connection, Modify Con- nection, Delete Connection, AuditEndpoint, AuditConnection and Res- tartInProgress. * The protocol description section presents the MGCP encodings, which are based on simple text formats, and the transmission procedure over UDP. * The security section presents the security requirement of MGCP, and its usage of IP security services (IPSEC). * The event packages section provides an initial definition of pack- ages and event names. * The description of the changes made in combining SGCP 1.1 and IPDC to create MGCP 0.1.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-huitema-megaco-mgcp-v0r1-05"/>
</reference>