<reference anchor="I-D.wu-model-driven-management-virtualization">
  <front>
    <title>A Framework for Automating Service and Network Management with YANG</title>
    <author fullname="Qin Wu" initials="Q." surname="Wu">
      <organization>Huawei</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Mohamed Boucadair" initials="M." surname="Boucadair">
      <organization>Orange</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Christian Jacquenet" initials="C." surname="Jacquenet">
      <organization>Orange</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Luis M. Contreras" initials="L. M." surname="Contreras">
      <organization>Telifonica</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Diego Lopez" initials="D." surname="Lopez">
      <organization>Telefonica I+D</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Chongfeng Xie" initials="C." surname="Xie">
      <organization>China Telecom</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Weiqiang Cheng" initials="W." surname="Cheng">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Liang Geng" initials="L." surname="Geng">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Young Lee" initials="Y." surname="Lee">
      <organization>Futurewei</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2019" month="October" day="10"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Data models for service and network management provides a programmatic approach for representing (virtual) services or networks and deriving (1) configuration information that will be communicated to network and service components that are used to build and deliver the service and (2) state information that will be monitored and tracked. Indeed, data models can be used during various phases of the service and network management life cycle, such as service instantiation, service provisioning, optimization, monitoring, and diagnostic. Also, data models are instrumental in the automation of network management. They also provide closed-loop control for the sake of adaptive and deterministic service creation, delivery, and maintenance. This document provides a framework that describes and discusses an architecture for service and network management automation that takes advantage of YANG modeling technologies. This framework is drawn from a network provider perspective irrespective of the origin of a data module; it can accommodate even modules that are developed outside the IETF. The document aims to exemplify an approach that specifies the journey from technology-agnostic services to technology-specific actions.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-wu-model-driven-management-virtualization-06"/>
  <format type="TXT" target="https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-wu-model-driven-management-virtualization-06.txt"/>
</reference>