<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-bess-evpn-irb-extended-mobility" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-ietf-bess-evpn-irb-extended-mobility-19">
  <front>
    <title>Extended Mobility Procedures for EVPN-IRB</title>
    <author fullname="Neeraj Malhotra" initials="N." surname="Malhotra">
      <organization>Cisco Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Ali Sajassi" initials="A." surname="Sajassi">
      <organization>Cisco Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Aparna Pattekar" initials="A." surname="Pattekar">
      <organization>Cisco Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jorge Rabadan" initials="J." surname="Rabadan">
      <organization>Nokia</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Avinash Reddy Lingala" initials="A. R." surname="Lingala">
      <organization>AT&amp;T</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="John Drake" initials="J." surname="Drake">
      <organization>Juniper Networks</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2024" month="December" day="2"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document specifies extensions to Ethernet VPN (EVPN) Integrated Routing and Bridging (IRB) procedures specified in RFC7432 and RFC9135 to enhance the mobility mechanisms for EVPN-IRB based networks. The proposed extensions improve the handling of host mobility and duplicate address detection in EVPN-IRB networks to cover a broader set of scenarios where a host's unicast IP address to MAC bindings may change across moves. These enhancements address limitations in the existing EVPN-IRB mobility procedures by providing more efficient and scalable solutions. The extensions are backward compatible with existing EVPN-IRB implementations and aim to optimize network performance in scenarios involving frequent IP address mobility. NOTE TO IESG (TO BE DELETED BEFORE PUBLISHING): This draft lists six authors which is above the required limit of five. Given significant and active contributions to the draft from all six authors over the course of six years, we would like to request IESG to allow publication with six authors. Specifically, the three Cisco authors are the original inventors of these procedures and contributed heavily to rev 0 draft, most of which is still intact. AT&amp;T is also a key contributor towards defining the use cases that this document addresses as well as the proposed solution. Authors from Nokia and Juniper have further contributed to revisions and discussions steadily over last six years to enable respective implementations and a wider adoption.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-bess-evpn-irb-extended-mobility-19"/>
</reference>