<reference anchor="I-D.iab-marnew-report">
  <front>
    <title>Report from the IAB Workshop on Managing Radio Networks in an Encrypted World (MaRNEW)</title>
    <author fullname="Natasha Rooney">
      <organization>GSMA</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Spencer Dawkins">
      <organization>Wonder Hamster</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2018" month="May" day="25"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>The Internet Architecture Board (IAB) and GSM Association (GSMA) held a joint workshop on Managing Radio Networks in an Encrypted World (MaRNEW), on September 24-25, 2015. This workshop aimed to discuss solutions for bandwidth optimization on mobile networks for encrypted content, as current solutions rely on unencrypted content, which is not indicative of the security needs of today's Internet users. The workshop gathered IETF attendees, IAB members, and participants from various organizations involved in the telecommunications industry including original equipment manufacturers, content providers, and mobile network operators. The group discussed Internet encryption trends and deployment issues identified within the IETF and the privacy needs of users that should be adhered to. Solutions designed around sharing data from the network to the endpoints and vice versa were then discussed; in addition, issues experienced when using current transport-layer protocols were also discussed. Content providers and Content Delivery Networks (CDNs) gave their own views of their experiences delivering their content with mobile network operators. Finally, technical responses to regulation were discussed to help the regulated industries relay the issues of impossible-to-implement or bad-for-privacy technologies back to regulators. A group of suggested solutions were devised, which will be discussed in various IETF groups moving forward.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-iab-marnew-report-02"/>
  <format type="TXT" target="https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-iab-marnew-report-02.txt"/>
</reference>