<reference anchor="I-D.dong-lsr-sr-enhanced-vpn" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-dong-lsr-sr-enhanced-vpn-10">
  <front>
    <title>IGP Extensions for Scalable Segment Routing based Virtual Transport Network (VTN)</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-dong-lsr-sr-enhanced-vpn-10"/>
    <author initials="J." surname="Dong" fullname="Jie Dong">
      <organization>Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="Z." surname="Hu" fullname="Zhibo Hu">
      <organization>Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="Z." surname="Li" fullname="Zhenbin Li">
      <organization>Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="X." surname="Tang" fullname="Xiongyan Tang">
      <organization>China Unicom</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="R." surname="Pang" fullname="Ran Pang">
      <organization>China Unicom</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="S." surname="Bryant" fullname="Stewart Bryant">
      <organization>University of Surrey</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="23" month="October" year="2023"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Enhanced VPN (VPN+) aims to provide enhanced VPN services to support
   some application's needs of enhanced isolation and stringent
   performance requirements.  VPN+ requires integration between the
   overlay VPN connectivity and the characteristics provided by the
   underlay network.  A Virtual Transport Network (VTN) is a virtual
   underlay network which has a customized network topology and a set of
   network resources allocated from the physical network.  A VTN could
   be used to support one or a group of VPN+ services.  In the context
   of network slicing, a VTN could be instantiated as a network resource
   partition (NRP).

   This document specifies the IGP mechanisms with necessary extensions
   to advertise the associated topology and resource attributes for
   scalable Segment Routing (SR) based NRPs.  Each NRP can have a
   customized topology and a set of network resources allocated from the
   physical network.  Multiple NRPs may shared the same topology, and
   multiple NRPs may share the same set of network resources on some
   network segments.  This allows flexible combination of the network
   topology and network resource attributes to build a relatively large
   number of NRPs with a relatively small number of logical topologies.
   A group of resource-aware SIDs and SRv6 Locators can be assigned to
   each NRP.  The proposed mechanism is applicable to both Segment
   Routing with MPLS data plane (SR-MPLS) and Segment Routing with IPv6
   data plane (SRv6).  This document also describes the mechanism of
   using dedicated NRP ID in the data plane instead of the per-NRP
   resource-aware SIDs and SRv6 Locators to further reduce the control
   plane and data plane overhead of maintaining a large number of NRPs.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>