<reference anchor="I-D.dong-teas-nrp-scalability">
  <front>
    <title>Scalability Considerations for Network Resource Partition</title>
    <author fullname="Jie Dong" initials="J." surname="Dong">
      <organization>Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Zhenbin Li" initials="Z." surname="Li">
      <organization>Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Liyan Gong" initials="L." surname="Gong">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Guangming Yang" initials="G." surname="Yang">
      <organization>China Telecom</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jim Guichard" initials="J." surname="Guichard">
      <organization>Futurewei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Gyan Mishra" initials="G. S." surname="Mishra">
      <organization>Verizon Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Fengwei Qin" initials="F." surname="Qin">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2021" month="December" day="17"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>IETF network slice service aims to meet the connectivity demands of a network slice customer with specific Service Level Objectives (SLOs) and Service Level Expectations (SLEs) over a common underlay network. A Network Resource Partition is a set of network resources that are allocated from the underlay network to carry a specific set of network traffic and meet the required SLOs and SLEs. One or multiple IETF network slice services can be mapped to one network resource partition. With the demand for IETF network slice services increases, scalability would become an important factor for the large scale deployment of IETF network slices. Although the scalability of IETF network slices can be improved by mapping a group of IETF network slices to one network resource partition, there are concerns about the scalability of network resource partitions. This document describes the scalability considerations about network resource partition in the network control plane and data plane, and some optimization mechanisms are proposed.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-dong-teas-nrp-scalability-00"/>
  <format type="TXT" target="https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-dong-teas-nrp-scalability-00.txt"/>
</reference>