<reference anchor="I-D.zhao-pce-pcep-extension-pce-controller-sr">
  <front>
    <title>PCEP Procedures and Protocol Extensions for Using PCE as a Central Controller (PCECC) of SR-LSPs</title>
    <author fullname="Quintin Zhao" initials="Q." surname="Zhao">
      <organization>Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Zhenbin Li" initials="Z." surname="Li">
      <organization>Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Mahendra Singh Negi" initials="M. S." surname="Negi">
      <organization>Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Chao Zhou" initials="C." surname="Zhou">
      <organization>Cisco Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2019" month="February"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>The Path Computation Element (PCE) is a core component of Software- Defined Networking (SDN) systems. It can compute optimal paths for traffic across a network and can also update the paths to reflect changes in the network or traffic demands. PCE was developed to derive paths for MPLS Label Switched Paths (LSPs), which are supplied to the head end of the LSP using the Path Computation Element Communication Protocol (PCEP). But SDN has a broader applicability than signaled (G)MPLS traffic-engineered (TE) networks, and the PCE may be used to determine paths in a range of use cases. PCEP has been proposed as a control protocol for use in these environments to allow the PCE to be fully enabled as a central controller. A PCE-based central controller (PCECC) can simplify the processing of a distributed control plane by blending it with elements of SDN and without necessarily completely replacing it. Thus, the LSP can be calculated/setup/initiated and the label forwarding entries can also be downloaded through a centralized PCE server to each network devices along the path while leveraging the existing PCE technologies as much as possible. This document specifies the procedures and PCEP protocol extensions when a PCE-based controller is also responsible for configuring the forwarding actions on the routers, in addition to computing the paths for packet flows in a segment routing network and telling the edge routers what instructions to attach to packets as they enter the network.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-zhao-pce-pcep-extension-pce-controller-sr-04"/>
  <format type="TXT" target="https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-zhao-pce-pcep-extension-pce-controller-sr-04.txt"/>
</reference>