<reference anchor="I-D.huang-rtgwg-us-standalone-sid" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-huang-rtgwg-us-standalone-sid-01">
  <front>
    <title>Use Cases-Standalone Service ID in Routing Network</title>
    <author fullname="Daniel Huang" initials="D." surname="Huang">
      <organization>ZTE Corporation</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jie Liang" initials="J." surname="Liang">
      <organization>China Telecom</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Feng Yang" initials="F." surname="Yang">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Yan Zhang" initials="Y." surname="Zhang">
      <organization>China Unicom</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Dong Yang" initials="D." surname="Yang">
      <organization>Beijing Jiaotong University</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2024" month="July" day="1"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>More and more emerging applications have raised the demand for establishing networking connections anywhere and anytime, alongside the availability of highly distributive any-cloud services. Such a demand motivates the need to efficiently interconnect heterogeneous entities, e.g., different domains of network and cloud owned by different providers to reduce cost, e.g., overheads and end-to-end latency, while ensuring the overall performance satisfies the requirements of the applications. Considering that different network domains and cloud providers may adopt different types of technologies, the key to interconnection and efficient coordination is to employ a unified interface that can be understood by heterogeneous parties, which could derive the consistent requirements of the same service and treat the service traffic appropriately by their proprietary policies and technologies. This document provides use cases and problem statements from two main Internet traffic categories: one is the traditional north-south traffic which is defined from clients to entities (such as servers or DCs), and the other is east-west traffic, which refers to traffic between entities (such as inter-server or inter- service).Furthermore,the requirements for a standalone Service ID are also detailed in this document.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-huang-rtgwg-us-standalone-sid-01"/>
</reference>