<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-simple-rpid" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-ietf-simple-rpid-10">
  <front>
    <title>RPID: Rich Presence Extensions to the Presence Information Data Format (PIDF)</title>
    <author fullname="Paul Kyzivat" initials="P." surname="Kyzivat">
      <organization>Cisco</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Vijay K. Gurbani" initials="V. K." surname="Gurbani">
      <organization>Lucent</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Henning Schulzrinne" initials="H." surname="Schulzrinne">
      <organization>Columbia U.</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jonathan Rosenberg" initials="J." surname="Rosenberg">
      <organization>Cisco</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2005" month="December" day="21"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>The Presence Information Data Format (PIDF) defines a basic format for representing presence information for a presentity. This format defines a textual note, an indication of availability (open or closed) and a Uniform Resource Identifier (URI) for communication. The Rich Presence Information Data format (RPID) described here is an extension that adds optional elements to the Presence Information Data Format (PIDF). These extensions provide additional information about the presentity and its contacts. The information is designed so that much of it can be derived automatically, e.g., from calendar files or user activity. This extension includes information about what the person is doing, a grouping identifier for a tuple, when a service or device was last used, the type of place a person is in, what media communications might remain private, the relationship of a service tuple to another presentity, the person's mood, the time zone it is located in, the type of service it offers, an icon reflecting the presentity's status, and the overall role of the presentity. These extensions include presence information for persons, services (tuples), and devices. [STANDARDS-TRACK]</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-simple-rpid-10"/>
</reference>