<reference anchor="I-D.wang-netmod-yang-policy-dm">
  <front>
    <title>A Network Policy Framework using YANG Data Models</title>
    <author fullname="Daniel King" initials="D." surname="King">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Zitao Wang" initials="Z." surname="Wang">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Linda Dunbar" initials="L." surname="Dunbar">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Qin Wu" initials="Q." surname="Wu">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <date year="2015" month="March"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>The purpose of a Network Policy System is to manage and control a network as a whole. To achieve this purpose, network operators need to control the behavior of the individual entities that comprise the network, and this control needs to be harmonized across multiple entities. For example, to control the access to a network, the operator must control the behavior at all of network elements at the edge of the network, and must apply consistent policies at those elements. Network Services are provided by network operators to their customers using the resources of the network. To effectively control a network, the operator must have knowledge of network services supported by the network, as well as knowledge of the network resource utilization and the capabilities of each network entity. Control of the network to deliver the network services will involve applying policy at individual network entities and across the whole network, as well as controlling and allocating the resources within the network. This document describes a common framework and common core YANG data model for network policies. The framework can be applied to deliver various different network services by controlling the policies that enable features such as Constraint-based Routing, Network QoS, Traffic engineering, network management, etc. In future, the core data model could be augmented by additional YANG data modules modeling and configuring policy-related protocols and functions. The policy data model described in this document provides common building blocks for such extensions.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-wang-netmod-yang-policy-dm-01"/>
  <format type="TXT" target="https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-wang-netmod-yang-policy-dm-01.txt"/>
</reference>