<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-opsawg-ntf" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-ietf-opsawg-ntf-04">
  <front>
    <title>Network Telemetry Framework</title>
    <author fullname="Haoyu Song" initials="H." surname="Song">
      <organization>Futurewei</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Fengwei Qin" initials="F." surname="Qin">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Pedro Martinez-Julia" initials="P." surname="Martinez-Julia">
      <organization>NICT</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Laurent Ciavaglia" initials="L." surname="Ciavaglia">
      <organization>Nokia</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Aijun Wang" initials="A." surname="Wang">
      <organization>China Telecom</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2020" month="September" day="21"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Network telemetry is the technology for gaining network insight and facilitating efficient and automated network management. It engages various techniques for remote data collection, correlation, and consumption. This document provides an architectural framework for network telemetry, motivated by the network operation challenges and requirements. As evidenced by some key characteristics and industry practices, network telemetry covers technologies and protocols beyond the conventional network Operations, Administration, and Management (OAM). It promises better flexibility, scalability, accuracy, coverage, and performance and allows automated control loops to suit both today's and tomorrow's network operation. This document clarifies the terminologies and classifies the modules and components of a network telemetry system from several different perspectives. The framework and taxonomy help to set a common ground for the collection of related work and provide guidance for related technique and standard developments.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-opsawg-ntf-04"/>
</reference>