<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-opsec-misc-cap">
  <front>
    <title>Miscellaneous Capabilities for IP Network Infrastructure
</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-opsec-misc-cap-00"/>
    <author fullname="Ross Callon" initials="R." surname="Callon">
      <organization>Juniper Networks</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="George M. Jones" initials="G. M." surname="Jones">
      <organization>The Mitre Corporation</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2006" month="February" day="22"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>The Framework for Operational Security Capabilities [11] outlines theproposed effort of the IETF OPSEC working group. This includesproducing a series of drafts to codify knowledge gained throughoperational experience about feature sets that are needed to securelydeploy and operate managed network elements providing transitservices at the data link and IP layers. Current plans includeseparate capabilities documents for Packet Filtering; Event Logging;In-Band and Out-of-Band Management; Configuration and ManagementInterfaces; AAA; and Documentation and Assurance. This documentdescribes some additional miscellaneous capabilities which do not fitinto any of these specific catagories, and whose descriptions arebrief enough that it does not seem appropriate to create a separatedocument for each.Operational Security Current Practices [12] lists current operatorpractices related to securing networks. This document listsmiscellaneous capabilities needed to support those practices.Capabilities are defined without reference to specific technologies.This is done to leave room for deployment of new technologies thatimplement the capability. Each capability cites the practices itsupports. Current implementations that support the capability may becited. Special considerations are discussed as appropriate listingoperational and resource constraints, limitations of currentimplementations, tradeoffs, etc.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>