<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-suit-mti" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-ietf-suit-mti-23">
  <front>
    <title>Cryptographic Algorithms for Internet of Things (IoT) Devices</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-suit-mti-23"/>
    <author initials="B." surname="Moran" fullname="Brendan Moran">
      <organization>Arm Limited</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="O." surname="Rønningstad" fullname="Øyvind Rønningstad">
      <organization>Nordic Semiconductor</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="A." surname="Tsukamoto" fullname="Akira Tsukamoto">
      <organization>Openchip &amp; Software Technologies, S.L.</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="22" month="July" year="2025"></date>
    <abstract>
      <t>   The SUIT manifest, as defined in "A Manifest Information Model for
   Firmware Updates in Internet of Things (IoT) Devices" (RFC 9124),
   provides a flexible and extensible format for describing how firmware
   and software updates are to be fetched, verified, decrypted, and
   installed on resource-constrained devices.  To ensure the security of
   these update processes, the manifest relies on cryptographic
   algorithms for functions such as digital signature verification,
   integrity checking, and confidentiality.

   This document defines cryptographic algorithm profiles for use with
   the Software Updates for Internet of Things (SUIT) manifest.  These
   profiles specify sets of algorithms to promote interoperability
   across implementations.

   Given the diversity of IoT deployments and the evolving cryptographic
   landscape, algorithm agility is essential.  This document groups
   algorithms into named profiles to accommodate varying levels of
   device capabilities and security requirements.  These profiles
   support the use cases laid out in the SUIT architecture, published in
   "A Firmware Update Architecture for Internet of Things" (RFC 9019).

	 </t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>