<reference anchor="I-D.irtf-mm-prob-stmt">
  <front>
    <title>Micromobility Problem Statement</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-irtf-mm-prob-stmt-00"/>
    <author fullname="John A. Loughney" initials="J. A." surname="Loughney">
      <organization>Nokia Research Center</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Alper E. Yegin" initials="A. E." surname="Yegin">
      <organization>DoCoMo USA Labs</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Carl Williams" initials="C." surname="Williams">
      <organization>DoCoMo USA Labs</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jare T. Malinen" initials="J. T." surname="Malinen">
      <organization>Nokia Research Center</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2002" month="June" day="26"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Mobile IP [1] has been developed in the IETF for a number of years already.It's simplicity and scalability give it a growing success within the IETF as several Internet drafts are proposed to extend various improvements for Mobile IP and its counterpart designed for IPv6, Mobile IPv6 [2]. Mobile IP suffers from several well-known weaknesses that have led to the definition of the macro/micro-mobility architecture. Such an architecture implies the division of the mobility architecture into two different parts: mobility management at a large scale, between the different domains (macro-mobility), and, on the other hand, at a local scale, inside these domains (micro-mobility). Each type of mobility is then managed by specific mechanisms and protocols. The macro-micro approach results in many advantages that all micro-mobility protocols will have; thereby effectively addressing weaknesses that plague Mobile IP.This document discusses the micro-mobility problem, and is an attempt toenumerate some of the concepts and approaches defining the micromobilityproblem space. This draft will serve to document the problemspace and definition of micro-mobility for discussion in the IRTFmicro-mobility working group.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>