<reference anchor="I-D.chen-green-transport-network-ucs" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-chen-green-transport-network-ucs-00">
  <front>
    <title>Transport Network Level Use Cases</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-chen-green-transport-network-ucs-00"/>
    <author initials="X." surname="Chen" fullname="Xinyu Chen">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="M." surname="Wang" fullname="Minxue Wang">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="J." surname="Zhou" fullname="Jin Zhou">
      <organization>ZTE Corporation</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="J." surname="Yan" fullname="Jinjie Yan">
      <organization>ZTE Corporation</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="07" month="July" year="2025"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>   With the continuous growth of business volume, the transmission rate
   and number of network elements have increased sharply, and energy
   consumption of transport network has increased accordingly.  Rising
   power costs due to significant energy consumption in transport
   networks necessitate energy-saving measures.  To address this,
   adjusting energy consumption strategies according to different
   service requirements to optimize efficiency, ensuring quality while
   eliminating waste.  Furthermore, regular network optimization and
   energy efficiency assessments enhance equipment performance and
   extend lifespan, thereby controlling long-term operational costs.
   Integrating energy-saving concepts into transport network operations
   proactively supports sustainable development.

   This document presents two transport network level GREEN use cases,
   aiming to facilitate discussions within the GREEN Working Group on
   the potential benefits, challenges, and requirements.  The use cases
   follow a structured template that is proposed for all GREEN use
   cases, ensuring consistency and comparability across different
   scenarios.

	 </t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>