<reference anchor="I-D.li-savnet-intra-domain-od-sav" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-li-savnet-intra-domain-od-sav-00">
  <front>
    <title>Intra-Domain On-Demand Source Address Validation(SAV) Mechanism</title>
    <author fullname="Xueting Li" initials="X." surname="Li">
      <organization>China Telecom</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Aijun Wang" initials="A." surname="Wang">
      <organization>China Telecom</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Yuanyuan Zhang" initials="Y." surname="Zhang">
      <organization>Zhongguancun Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2025" month="July" day="20"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Source Address Validation (SAV) mechanisms, such as unicast Reverse Path Forwarding (uRPF), Access Control Lists (ACLs), and Best-Match Shortest Path Filtering (BM-SPF), are widely deployed to prevent IP source address spoofing. However, these mechanisms are typically designed for static routing scenarios and deployed at fixed network boundaries. With the increasing adoption of dynamic forwarding technologies such as SRv6 Policy and Fast Reroute (TI-FRR), the network's actual forwarding path may change frequently due to policy-based traffic steering or link failures. In such cases, statically deployed SAV rules may fail to validate traffic on newly activated or alternate paths, creating validation blind spots or even leading to false positives that block legitimate traffic. This draft proposes an On-Demand Source Address Validation Activation mechanism. It enables routers to dynamically activate or update SAV rules on specific interfaces only when the interface becomes part of an active forwarding path due to policy or failover triggers. This approach enhances SAV coverage, avoids unnecessary resource consumption, and ensures SAV correctness under dynamic path switching scenarios driven by SRv6-policy and TI-FRR.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-li-savnet-intra-domain-od-sav-00"/>
</reference>