<reference anchor="I-D.yang-alto-deliver-functions-over-networks">
  <front>
    <title>Delivering Functions over Networks: Traffic and Performance Optimization for Edge Computing using ALTO</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-yang-alto-deliver-functions-over-networks-00"/>
    <author>
      <organization abbrev="IETF">Internet Engineering Task Force</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Shu Yang" initials="S." surname="Yang">
      <organization>Shenzhen University</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Laizhong Cui" initials="L." surname="Cui">
      <organization>Shenzhen University</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Mingwei Xu" initials="M." surname="Xu">
      <organization>Tsinghua University</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Hongfei Shen" initials="H." surname="Shen">
      <organization>China Telecom</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Lu Chen" initials="L." surname="Chen">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2019" month="November" day="29"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>With development of Internet of Thing (IoT), artificial intelligence, huge amount of data are generated and need to be processed. To satisfy the user demands, service providers are deploying edge computing across lots of data centers, which are closer to users. In order to achieve better performances, computing functions need to be scheduled properly over networks. However, it is challenging to deploy functions to the distributed edge servers efficiently due to the lack of network traffic information. [RFC5693] and [RFC7285] introduce and define the Application-Layer Traffic Optimization, or ALTO, to compute and provide the network information for the distributed applications using the ALTO protocol. In this document, we employ the ALTO protocol to deliver functions in edge computing platform, where the protocol will provide the network information for the distributed edge computing servers and guide the delivery process. The usage of ALTO will improve the efficiency of function delivering in edge computing.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>