<reference anchor="I-D.cuspdt-rtgwg-cu-separation-infor-model">
  <front>
    <title>Information Model of Control-Plane and User-Plane separation BNG</title>
    <author fullname="Shujun Hu" initials="S." surname="Hu">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Zitao Wang" initials="Z." surname="Wang">
      <organization>Huawei</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Victor Lopez" initials="V." surname="Lopez">
      <organization>Telefonica</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Fengwei Qin" initials="F." surname="Qin">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Zhenqiang Li" initials="Z." surname="Li">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2018" month="July" day="2"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>To improve network resource utilization and reduce the operation expense, the Control-Plane and User-Plane separation conception is raised [TR-384]. This document describes the information model for the interface between Control-Plane and User-Plane separation BNG. This information model may involve both control channel interface and configuration channel interface. The interface for control channel allows the Control-Plane to send several flow tables to the User- Plane, such as user's information table, user's interface table, and user's QoS table, etc. And it also allows the User-Plane to report the resources and statistics information to the Control-Plane. The interface for configuration channel is in charge of the version negotiation of protocols between the Control-Plane and User-Plane, the configuration for devices of Control-Plane and User-Plane, and the reports of User-Plane's capabilities, etc. The information model defined in this document enables defining a standardized data model. Such a data model can be used to define an interface to the CU separation BNG.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-cuspdt-rtgwg-cu-separation-infor-model-01"/>
  <format type="TXT" target="https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-cuspdt-rtgwg-cu-separation-infor-model-01.txt"/>
</reference>