<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-ippm-responsiveness" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-ietf-ippm-responsiveness-08">
  <front>
    <title>Responsiveness under Working Conditions</title>
    <author fullname="Christoph Paasch" initials="C." surname="Paasch">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Randall Meyer" initials="R." surname="Meyer">
      <organization>Apple Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Stuart Cheshire" initials="S." surname="Cheshire">
      <organization>Apple Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Will Hawkins" initials="W." surname="Hawkins">
      <organization>University of Cincinnati</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2025" month="October" day="20"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>For many years, a lack of responsiveness, variously called lag, latency, or bufferbloat, has been recognized as an unfortunate, but common, symptom in today's networks. Even after a decade of work on standardizing technical solutions, it remains a common problem for the end users. Everyone "knows" that it is "normal" for a video conference to have problems when somebody else at home is watching a 4K movie or uploading photos from their phone. However, there is no technical reason for this to be the case. In fact, various queue management solutions have solved the problem. Our network connections continue to suffer from an unacceptable amount of delay, not for a lack of technical solutions, but rather a lack of awareness of the problem and deployment of its solutions. We believe that creating a tool that measures the problem and matches people's everyday experience will create the necessary awareness, and result in a demand for solutions. This document specifies the "Responsiveness Test" for measuring responsiveness. It uses common protocols and mechanisms to measure user experience specifically when the network is under working conditions. The measurement is expressed as "Round-trips Per Minute" (RPM) and should be included with goodput (up and down) and idle latency as critical indicators of network quality.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-ippm-responsiveness-08"/>
</reference>