<reference anchor="I-D.mahajan-rpcp-protocol">
  <front>
    <title>RPCP Resource Pool Control Protocol</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-mahajan-rpcp-protocol-00"/>
    <author fullname="Sunil Mahajan" initials="S." surname="Mahajan"/>
    <date year="1999" month="February" day="9"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>RPCP is a generic interface protocol between two entities, whereone entity acting as Resource Pool (RP) and other being theResource Pool Controller (RPC). The RP entity in turn may beacting as RPC for other RPs in a hierarchical manner. The resourcebeing defined can be any hardware/software, physical/virtualresource.In today's telecommunication world, the intelligence is beingmoved away from the hardware (the embedded platform) or theswitching fabric to a more generic computing resource (high-endservers). These computing resources controls the call logic,service logic and the network signalling part. This implies thatthere is a need for an open interface protocol by which callagents or signalling agents can control this rather dumb hardwareas resource pools. This helps in easy and smooth integration ofthese entities even if they come from different vendors.The Interworking and Gateway market is a very big market today.The network architecture proposed for these solutions carries theintelligence away from the resource pools (also called mediagateways) to call agents or pool controllers (also called mediagateway controllers). With such network architectures the needfor such a protocol is more prominent.There are many other needs and use of such a protocol which willbe discussed in detail in this white paper. This paper does nottry to define the complete protocol, however the basic definitionand the protocol architecture will be defined.The document first describes the application of Resource PoolControl protocol, followed by requirements from this Protocol andthen defines the Protocol Architecture with basic protocoldefinition. The annexure of the document gives few examples onRPCP usage.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>