<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-sidrops-cms-signing-time" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-ietf-sidrops-cms-signing-time-03">
  <front>
    <title>On the use of the CMS signing-time attribute in RPKI Signed Objects</title>
    <author fullname="Job Snijders" initials="J." surname="Snijders">
      <organization>Fastly</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Tom Harrison" initials="T." surname="Harrison">
      <organization>Asia Pacific Network Information Centre</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2024" month="January" day="18"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>In the Resource Public Key Infrastructure (RPKI), Signed Objects are defined as Cryptographic Message Syntax (CMS) protected content types by way of a standard template (RFC 6488). That template includes an optional CMS signing-time attribute, representing the purported time at which the object was signed by its issuer. At the time when the standard template was defined, rsync was the only distribution mechanism for RPKI repositories. Since the publication of the standard template, a new, additional protocol for distribution of RPKI repositories has been developed: the RPKI Repository Delta Protocol (RRDP). While RPKI repository operators must provide rsync service, RRDP is typically deployed alongside it as well, and preferred by default by most Relying Party (RP) implementations. However, RP implementations also support fallback to rsync in the event of problems with the RRDP service. As deployment experience with RRDP has increased, the usefulness of optimizing switchovers by RPs from one mechanism to the other has become apparent. This document describes how Publishers and RPs can use the CMS signing-time attribute to minimize the burden of switching over from RRDP to rsync. Additionally, this document updates RFC 6488 by mandating the presence of the CMS signing-time attribute and disallowing the use of the binary-signing-time attribute.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-sidrops-cms-signing-time-03"/>
</reference>