<reference anchor="I-D.song-opsawg-ifit-framework">
  <front>
    <title>In-situ Flow Information Telemetry</title>
    <author fullname="Haoyu Song" initials="H." surname="Song">
      <organization>Futurewei</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Zhenbin Li" initials="Z." surname="Li">
      <organization>Huawei</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Tianran Zhou" initials="T." surname="Zhou">
      <organization>Huawei</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Fengwei Qin" initials="F." surname="Qin">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Huanan Chen" initials="H." surname="Chen">
      <organization>China Telecom</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jaewhan Jin" initials="J." surname="Jin">
      <organization>LG U+</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jongyoon Shin" initials="J." surname="Shin">
      <organization>SK Telecom</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2019" month="October" day="21"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>For efficient network operation, most operators rely on traditional Operation, Administration and Maintenance (OAM) methods, which include proactive and reactive techniques, running in active and passive modes. As networks increase in scale they become more susceptible to measurement accuracy and misconfiguration errors. With the advent of programmable data-plane emerging on-path OAM techniques, such as flow telemetry, provide unprecedented insight and fast notification of network issues (e.g., jitter, increased latency, packet loss, significant bit error variations, and unequal load- balancing). In-situ Flow Information Telemetry (iFIT) provides a method for efficiently applying underlying on-path flow telemetry techniques, applicable across various network environments. This document outlines an iFIT framework, which enumerates several critical functional components and describes how these components are assembled together to achieve a complete and closed-loop working solution for on-path flow telemetry.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-song-opsawg-ifit-framework-06"/>
</reference>