<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-webdav-binding-protocol">
  <front>
    <title>WebDAV Bindings</title>
    <author fullname="James R. Davis" initials="J. R." surname="Davis">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="John Crawford" initials="J." surname="Crawford">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Judith Slein" initials="J." surname="Slein">
      <organization>Xerox</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Charles R. Fay" initials="C. R." surname="Fay">
      <organization>FileNet</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Geoffrey M. Clemm" initials="G. M." surname="Clemm">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <date year="1999" month="December" day="22"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This is one of a pair of specifications that extend the WebDAV Distributed Authoring Protocol to enable clients to create new access paths to existing resources. The two protocol extensions have very different characteristics that make them useful for different sorts of applications. The present specification defines bindings, and the BIND method for creating them. Creating a new binding to a resource indirectly creates one or more new URIs mapped to that resource, which can then be used to access it. Servers are required to insure the integrity of any bindings that they allow to be created. The related specification, RFC xxxx, defines redirect reference resources. A redirect reference resource is a resource whose default response is an HTTP/1.1 302 (Found) status code, redirecting the client to a different resource, the target resource. A redirect reference makes it possible to access the target resource indirectly, through any URI mapped to the redirect reference resource. There are no integrity guarantees associated with redirect reference resources.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-webdav-binding-protocol-02"/>
  <format type="TXT" target="https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-ietf-webdav-binding-protocol-02.txt"/>
</reference>