<reference anchor="I-D.boro-opsawg-teas-attachment-circuit">
  <front>
    <title>YANG Service Data Models for Attachment Circuits</title>
    <author fullname="Mohamed Boucadair" initials="M." surname="Boucadair">
      <organization>Orange</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Richard Roberts" initials="R." surname="Roberts">
      <organization>Juniper</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Oscar Gonzalez de Dios" initials="O. G." surname="de Dios">
      <organization>Telefonica</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Samier Barguil" initials="S." surname="Barguil">
      <organization>Nokia</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Bo Wu" initials="B." surname="Wu">
      <organization>Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2023" month="January" day="20"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document specifies a YANG service data model for Attachment Circuits (ACs). The model can be used for the provisioning of ACs prior or during service provisioning (e.g., Network Slice Service). The document specifies also a module that updates other service and network modules with the required information to bind specific services to ACs that are created using the AC service model. The AC service model is designed with the intent to be reusable. Whether a service model reuses structures defined in the AC service model or simply include an AC reference is a design choice of these service models. Relying upon the AC model to manage ACs over which a service is delivered has the merit to decorrelate the management of a service vs. upgrade the AC components to reflect recent AC technologies or features. Each AC is identified with a unique identifier within a domain. The mapping between this AC and a PE that terminates the AC is hidden to the application/customer that makes use of the AC service model. Such an information is internal to the network controller. Thus, the details about the (network node-specific) attachment interfaces are not exposed in this service model.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-boro-opsawg-teas-attachment-circuit-01"/>
  <format type="TXT" target="https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-boro-opsawg-teas-attachment-circuit-01.txt"/>
</reference>