<reference anchor="I-D.li-apn6-problem-statement-usecases" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-li-apn6-problem-statement-usecases-00">
  <front>
    <title>Problem statement and use cases of Application-aware IPv6 Networking (APN6)</title>
    <author fullname="Zhenbin Li" initials="Z." surname="Li">
      <organization>Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Shuping Peng" initials="S." surname="Peng">
      <organization>Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Daniel Voyer" initials="D." surname="Voyer">
      <organization>Bell Canada</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Chongfeng Xie" initials="C." surname="Xie">
      <organization>China Telecom</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Peng Liu" initials="P." surname="Liu">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Chang Liu" initials="C." surname="Liu">
      <organization>China Unicom</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Kentaro Ebisawa" initials="K." surname="Ebisawa">
      <organization>Toyota Motor Corporation</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Yukito Ueno" initials="Y." surname="Ueno">
      <organization>NTT Communications Corporation</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Stefano Previdi" initials="S." surname="Previdi">
      <organization>Individual</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jim Guichard" initials="J." surname="Guichard">
      <organization>Futurewei Technologies Ltd.</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2019" month="September" day="25"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Operators are facing the challenges of providing better network services for users. As the ever-developing 5G and industrial verticals evolve, more and more services that have diverse network requirements such as ultra-low latency and high reliability are emerging and accessing the network, differentiated service treatments are desired by users. However, operators are still not aware of applications, which cause that only coarse-grained services can be provided to users. As a result, operators are only evolving to be large but dumb pipes without corresponding revenue increase. As the network technologies evolve including deployments of IPv6 and SRv6, the programmability provided by IPv6 and SRv6 encapsulations can be augmented by conveying the application related information into the network. Adding application knowledge to the network layer, allow applications to specify finer granularity requirements, which eventually bridges network and applications. This document analyzes the existing problems of the current operators in the application awareness, and outlines various use cases that could benefit from the Application-aware IPv6 Networking (APN6).</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-li-apn6-problem-statement-usecases-00"/>
</reference>