<reference anchor="I-D.chen-green-transport-network-ucs" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-chen-green-transport-network-ucs-00">
  <front>
    <title>Transport Network Level Use Cases</title>
    <author fullname="Xinyu Chen" initials="X." surname="Chen">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Minxue Wang" initials="M." surname="Wang">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jin Zhou" initials="J." surname="Zhou">
      <organization>ZTE Corporation</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jinjie Yan" initials="J." surname="Yan">
      <organization>ZTE Corporation</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2025" month="July" day="7"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>With the continuous growth of business volume, the transmission rate and number of network elements have increased sharply, and energy consumption of transport network has increased accordingly. Rising power costs due to significant energy consumption in transport networks necessitate energy-saving measures. To address this, adjusting energy consumption strategies according to different service requirements to optimize efficiency, ensuring quality while eliminating waste. Furthermore, regular network optimization and energy efficiency assessments enhance equipment performance and extend lifespan, thereby controlling long-term operational costs. Integrating energy-saving concepts into transport network operations proactively supports sustainable development. This document presents two transport network level GREEN use cases, aiming to facilitate discussions within the GREEN Working Group on the potential benefits, challenges, and requirements. The use cases follow a structured template that is proposed for all GREEN use cases, ensuring consistency and comparability across different scenarios.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-chen-green-transport-network-ucs-00"/>
</reference>