<reference anchor="I-D.diem-fainchtein-use-cases" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-diem-fainchtein-use-cases-00">
  <front>
    <title>Digital Emblem (DIEM) Use Cases</title>
    <author fullname="Rahel Fainchtein" initials="R. A." surname="Fainchtein">
      <organization>JHU/APL</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Casey Deccio" initials="C." surname="Deccio">
      <organization>Brigham Young University</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Brian Haberman" initials="B." surname="Haberman">
      <organization>Fastly</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Bill Woodcock" initials="B." surname="Woodcock">
      <organization>PCH</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Allison Mankin" initials="A." surname="Mankin">
      <organization>PCH</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Alex Rosenberg" initials="A." surname="Rosenberg">
      <organization>Veridigo</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2025" month="July" day="4"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>International law defines a number of emblems, such as the blue helmets of United Nations peacekeeping forces, the blue and white shield of UNESCO, and the Red Cross of the International Committee of the Red Cross, as indicative of special protections under the Geneva Conventions. Similar protections attach to journalists who wear "Press" protective emblems on the battlefield, under Article 79 of Protocol I of the Geneva Conventions and Resolution 2222 of the United Nations Security Council. The emblems of national governments and inter-governmental organizations protect diplomatic pouches, couriers, and envoys under the Vienna Convention on Diplomatic Relations. Other marks enjoy protections against mis-use under the Paris Convention, the Madrid Protocol, and the Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual Property Rights. This document provides an initial summary of problems placing emblems into digital use cases and documents identified requirements from a number of stakeholders with active or potential interests in digital emblems. TODO align abstract and document with the WG charter.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-diem-fainchtein-use-cases-00"/>
</reference>