<reference anchor="I-D.hopley-x402-retention-chain" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-hopley-x402-retention-chain-05">
  <front>
    <title>Self-Verifiable Retention Chain for Payment Receipts</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-hopley-x402-retention-chain-05"/>
    <author initials="H. C." surname="Mr" fullname="MR CHRISTOPHER HOPLEY">
      <organization>AlgoVoi</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="19" month="June" year="2026"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document specifies five cryptographic constructions for
   self-verifiable agentic payment records.  The first, the Retention
   Chain Reference (retention_chain_ref), enables tamper-evident audit
   chains linking payment receipts without requiring external
   infrastructure.  The second, the Payment Action Lifecycle, defines
   a content-addressed model for the exactly-once execution of payment
   actions, including an action reference primitive (action_ref) and a
   per-state transition hash (transition_hash) with a provable SKIP-on-
   retry idempotency guarantee.  The third, the Settlement-Action
   Binding (binding_ref), binds a settled payment to the verified agent
   action it paid for and to the retention chain entry recording it, so
   that a settlement attestation proves not only that a payment occurred
   but which verified action it corresponds to.  The fourth, the Policy
   Binding (policy_bound_ref), binds a content-addressed snapshot of the
   governing policy to an existing binding or chain reference, so that a
   decision is verifiable against the exact policy version that admitted
   it and a policy rotation is detectable by recomputation.  The fifth,
   the Compliance Gate Binding (gate_ref), binds a categorical
   ALLOW/REFER/DENY compliance verdict and a no-PII payer reference to a
   policy or binding reference, so that a screening decision is provably
   tied to the policy in force when it was made and carries no personal
   data in the bound record.  All
   constructions use only SHA-256 and the JSON Canonicalization Scheme
   (JCS, RFC 8785),
   and are verifiable by any party holding the relevant receipts without
   contacting the issuer.  The constructions satisfy the transaction
   recording and audit trail obligations of MiCA Article 80, DORA
   Article 14, and AMLR Article 56.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>