<reference anchor="I-D.ash-qos-routing">
  <front>
    <title>QoS Resource Management in MPLS-Based Networks</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ash-qos-routing-01"/>
    <author fullname="Bilel Jamoussi" initials="B." surname="Jamoussi"/>
    <author fullname="Osama Aboul-Magd" initials="O." surname="Aboul-Magd"/>
    <author fullname="Gerald Ash" initials="G." surname="Ash"/>
    <date year="1999" month="March" day="1"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Efficient QoS resource management is needed for a host of existing andever-increasing new services. For service performance, flexibility, andreduced cost it is preferable to provide integration of these services on ashared network. Such integration and sharing is facilitated by QoS resourcemanagement techniques described in the draft which are applicable toMPLS-based networks. Such QoS resource management techniques are used inPSTNs to standardize service classification, bandwidth allocation, bandwidthprotection, and priority routing treatment for all network services. In thedraft we illustrate the principles of QoS resource management and describetheir application to MPLS-based networks. In the proposed QoS resourcemanagement method, bandwidth is allocated in discrete changes to each ofthree virtual networks (VNs) corresponding to high-priority key services,normal priority services, and best-effort lower priority services.Bandwidth changes in VN bandwidth capacity are determined by edgeswitch/routers based on an overall aggregated bandwidth demand for VNcapacity (not on a per-connection demand basis). Based on the aggregatedbandwidth demand, these edge switch/routers make periodic discrete changesin bandwidth allocation, that is, either increase or decrease bandwidth onthe constraint-based routing label switched paths (CRLSPs) constituting theVN bandwidth capacity. We propose to add optional parameters in theconstraint-based routing label distribution protocol (CRLDP) for QoSresource management. In particular, we propose an optional depth-of-search(DoS) type/length/value (TLV) parameter in the CRLDP label request messageto control the bandwidth allocation on individual links in a CRLSP. Inaddition, we propose an optional modify-TLV parameter in the CRLDP labelrequest message to allow modification of the assigned traffic parameters(such as peak data rate, committed data rate, etc.) of an already existingCRL</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>