<reference anchor="I-D.narajala-ans" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-narajala-ans-00">
  <front>
    <title>Agent Name Service (ANS): A Universal Directory for Secure AI Agent Discovery and Interoperability</title>
    <author fullname="Ken Huang" initials="K." surname="Huang">
      <organization>DistributedApps.ai</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Vineeth Sai Narajala" initials="V. S." surname="Narajala">
      <organization>Amazon Web Services</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Idan Habler" initials="I." surname="Habler">
      <organization>Intuit</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Akram Sheriff" initials="A." surname="Sheriff">
      <organization>Cisco Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2025" month="May" day="16"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>The proliferation of AI agents requires robust mechanisms for secure discovery. This document introduces the Agent Name Service (ANS), a novel architecture based on DNS addressing the lack of a public agent discovery framework. ANS provides a protocol-agnostic registry mechanism that leverages Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) certificates for verifiable agent identity and trust. The architecture features several key innovations: a formalized agent registration and renewal mechanism for lifecycle management; DNS-inspired naming conventions with capability-aware resolution; a modular Protocol Adapter Layer supporting diverse communication standards (A2A, MCP, ACP, etc.); and precisely defined algorithms for secure resolution. This specification describes structured communication using JSON Schema and includes a comprehensive threat analysis. The result is a foundational agent directory service protocol addressing the core challenges of secure discovery and interaction in multi-agent systems, paving the way for future interoperable, trustworthy, and scalable agent ecosystems.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-narajala-ans-00"/>
</reference>