<reference anchor="I-D.yang-alto-deliver-functions-over-networks" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-yang-alto-deliver-functions-over-networks-00">
  <front>
    <title>Delivering Functions over Networks: Traffic and Performance Optimization for Edge Computing using ALTO</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-yang-alto-deliver-functions-over-networks-00"/>
    <author initials="S." surname="Yang" fullname="Shu Yang">
      <organization>Shenzhen University</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="L." surname="Cui" fullname="Laizhong Cui">
      <organization>Shenzhen University</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="M." surname="Xu" fullname="Mingwei Xu">
      <organization>Tsinghua University</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="H." surname="Shen" fullname="Hongfei Shen">
      <organization>China Telecom</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="L." surname="Chen" fullname="Lu Chen">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="29" month="November" year="2019"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>   With development of Internet of Thing (IoT), artificial intelligence,
   huge amount of data are generated and need to be processed.  To
   satisfy the user demands, service providers are deploying edge
   computing across lots of data centers, which are closer to users.  In
   order to achieve better performances, computing functions need to be
   scheduled properly over networks.  However, it is challenging to
   deploy functions to the distributed edge servers efficiently due to
   the lack of network traffic information.  [RFC5693] and [RFC7285]
   introduce and define the Application-Layer Traffic Optimization, or
   ALTO, to compute and provide the network information for the
   distributed applications using the ALTO protocol.  In this document,
   we employ the ALTO protocol to deliver functions in edge computing
   platform, where the protocol will provide the network information for
   the distributed edge computing servers and guide the delivery
   process.  The usage of ALTO will improve the efficiency of function
   delivering in edge computing.

	 </t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>