<reference anchor="I-D.skyfire-oauth-using-kyapay-tokens" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-skyfire-oauth-using-kyapay-tokens-00">
  <front>
    <title>Using KYAPay Tokens</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-skyfire-oauth-using-kyapay-tokens-00"/>
    <author initials="A." surname="Agarwal" fullname="Ankit Agarwal">
      <organization>Skyfire Systems Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="M. B." surname="Jones" fullname="Michael B. Jones">
      <organization>Self-Issued Consulting</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="" surname="Srinivasa" fullname="Srinivasa">
      <organization>Akamai</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="19" month="July" year="2026"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>The KYAPay Token is a JSON Web Token (JWT) that carries verified
   identity ("Know Your Agent", KYA) and payment (PAY) information for
   requests made by software agents on behalf of human principals.  This
   document describes how security intermediaries -- bot managers, fraud
   managers, account-takeover (ATO) protection systems, and customer
   identity and access management (CIAM) systems -- consume KYAPay
   tokens to answer a question that traditional bot detection cannot:
   "did a verified human authorize this agent?", rather than "is this a
   human?".  It specifies how KYAPay tokens are carried in HTTP
   requests, how they are validated (including in combination with
   request-signing layers such as HTTP Message Signatures), and how the
   verified, layered identity in a token is used to make access,
   routing, fraud detection, account-lifecycle, and step-up decisions.
   It defines the token-consuming "verifier" role that the KYAPay Token
   leaves unspecified.  It is intentionally non-prescriptive about how
   tokens are created, because agent architectures, agent-identity
   technologies, and agent-communication protocols are diverse and still
   emerging; the token itself is the interoperability contract.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>