<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-asid-ldap-c-api">
  <front>
    <title>The C LDAP Application Program Interface</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-asid-ldap-c-api-00"/>
    <author fullname="Chris Weider" initials="C." surname="Weider">
      <organization>Microsoft Corp.</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Tim Howes" initials="T." surname="Howes">
      <organization>Netscape Communications Corp.</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Mark C. Smith" initials="M. C." surname="Smith">
      <organization>Netscape Communications Corp.</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Mark Wahl" initials="M." surname="Wahl">
      <organization>Critical Angle</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Andrew Herron" initials="A." surname="Herron">
      <organization>Microsoft Corp.</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="1997" month="July" day="31"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document defines a C language application program interface to thelightweight directory access protocol (LDAP). This document replaces theprevious definition of this API, defined in RFC 1823, updating it toinclude support for features found in version 3 of the LDAP protocol.New extended operation functions were added to support LDAPv3 featuressuch as controls. In addition, other LDAP API changes were made tosupport information hiding and thread safety. The C LDAP API is designed to be powerful, yet simple to use. It definescompatible synchronous and asynchronous interfaces to LDAP to suit awide variety of applications. This document gives a brief overview ofthe LDAP model, then an overview of how the API is used by an applica-tion program to obtain LDAP information. The API calls are described indetail, followed by an appendix that provides some example code demon-strating the use of the API. This document provides information to theInternet community. It does not specify any standard.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>