<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-bess-evpn-mvpn-seamless-interop">
  <front>
    <title>Seamless Multicast Interoperability between EVPN and MVPN PEs</title>
    <author fullname="Ali Sajassi" surname="Ali Sajassi">
      <organization>Cisco</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Kesavan Thiruvenkatasamy" surname="Kesavan Thiruvenkatasamy">
      <organization>Cisco</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Samir Thoria" surname="Samir Thoria">
      <organization>Cisco</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Ashutosh Gupta" surname="Ashutosh Gupta">
      <organization>VMware</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Luay Jalil" surname="Luay Jalil">
      <organization>Verizon</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2022" month="June" day="28"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Ethernet Virtual Private Network (EVPN) solution is becoming pervasive for Network Virtualization Overlay (NVO) services in data center (DC) networks and as the next generation VPN services in service provider (SP) networks. As service providers transform their networks in their Central Offices (COs) towards the next generation data center with Software Defined Networking (SDN) based fabric and Network Function Virtualization (NFV), they want to be able to maintain their offered services including Multicast VPN (MVPN) service between their existing network and their new Service Provider Data Center (SPDC) network seamlessly without the use of gateway devices. They want to have such seamless interoperability between their new SPDCs and their existing networks for a) reducing cost, b) having optimum forwarding, and c) reducing provisioning. This document describes a unified solution based on RFCs 6513 &amp; 6514 for seamless interoperability of Multicast VPN between EVPN and MVPN PEs. Furthermore, it describes how the proposed solution can be used as a routed multicast solution in data centers with only EVPN PEs.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-bess-evpn-mvpn-seamless-interop-04"/>
  <format type="TXT" target="https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-ietf-bess-evpn-mvpn-seamless-interop-04.txt"/>
</reference>