<reference anchor="I-D.pan-bgrp-framework">
  <front>
    <title>BGRP: A Framework for Scalable Resource Reservation
</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-pan-bgrp-framework-00"/>
    <author fullname="Henning Schulzrinne" initials="H." surname="Schulzrinne">
      <organization>Bell Labs/Columbia U.</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Ping Pan" initials="P." surname="Pan">
      <organization>Bell Labs/Columbia U.</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Dr. Ellen L. Hahne" initials="E. L." surname="Hahne">
      <organization>Bell Labs/Columbia U.</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2000" month="January" day="19"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Resource reservation needs to accommodate the rapidly growing sizeand increasing service diversity of the Internet. This memo firstdefines the scaling problem in today's Internet backbone, and brieflydiscusses several existing resource management approaches. Then wewill present a distributed approach and introduce a protocol, calledthe Border Gateway Reservation Protocol (BGRP), for inter-domainresource reservation that can scale in terms of message processingload, state storage and control message bandwidth.The main idea of our approach is to build a sink tree for each domainnetwork. Each sink tree aggregates reservations from all datasources in the network. Sink tree initiation, maintenance andtermination involve only backbone border routers. Within each domain,the network service providers manage network resource and direct usertraffic independently. At the border routers, the service providerscan use BGRP to setup domain-level reservation trunks base on bi-lateral agreement. Since routers only maintain the sink treeinformation, the total number of reservation states at each routerscales, in the worst case, linearly with the number of domains in theInternet.For bandwidth reservation, BGRP relies on differentiated services fordata forwarding. As a result, the number of packet classifier entriesis small. To reduce the protocol message traffic, routers mayreserve domain bandwidth beyond the current load so that sources canjoin or leave the tree or change their reservation without having tosend messages all the way to the root for every such change.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>