<reference anchor="I-D.yan-dmm-man" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-yan-dmm-man-13">
  <front>
    <title>Mobility Capability Negotiation</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-yan-dmm-man-13"/>
    <author initials="Z." surname="Yan" fullname="Zhiwei Yan">
      <organization>CNNIC</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="T." surname="Jiang" fullname="Tianji Jiang">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="J." surname="Guan" fullname="Jianfeng Guan">
      <organization>BUPT</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="T." surname="Huang" fullname="Tao Huang">
      <organization>BUPT</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="J." surname="Lee" fullname="Jong-Hyouk Lee">
      <organization>Sejong University</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="22" month="February" year="2024"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Mobile peers exchange signals with networks, for both wireline and
   wireless domains, to negotiate capabilities for mobile registration,
   connection management, session establishment, service provisioning,
   etc.  Generally, mobility capabilities include the supported and
   provisioned resources along with associated protocols for certain
   mobility management scenarios.  While devices in the mobile wireline
   (IP) domain would mostly focus on the IP-related negotiation, devices
   in the wireless domain, e.g., the 5G system (5GS), embrace both
   mobile IP-related resources as well as wireless-specific
   capabilities.  Regarding both the mobile-IP and wireless domains, we
   have generalized two protocol categories for mobility capability
   negotiation &amp; management, i.e., the host-initiated category that
   involves the direct &amp; active engagement of mobile end devices vs. the
   network-based category over which mobile endpoints play almost no
   role in the process.  The classification and then the application of
   the two categories help us analyze the mobility capability
   negotiation for both the mobile IPv6 and the 3GPP 5G system.  The
   comparison of the capability negotiation under both the Home-Routed
   (HR) and the Local BreakOut (LBO) roaming cases in 5GS further
   reflects the feasibility of the protocol dichotomy.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>