<reference anchor="I-D.hongcs-t2trg-rsvwm">
  <front>
    <title>Resource Sharing in Virtualized Wireless Networks: A Two-Layer Game Approach</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-hongcs-t2trg-rsvwm-00"/>
    <author fullname="Choong Seon Hong">
      <organization>Kyung Hee University</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Yan Kyaw Tun">
      <organization>Kyung Hee University</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Ki Tae Kim">
      <organization>Kyung Hee University</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Seok Won Kang">
      <organization>Kyung Hee University</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Shashi Raj Pandey">
      <organization>Kyung Hee University</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2020" month="October" day="13"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Wireless network virtualization is one of the auspiciousapproach to address the increasingdemand of mobile data services. It enables logically decouplingthe traditional cellular network into infrastructure providers(InPs) and mobile virtual network operators (MVNOs). It alsooffers a virtualized wireless network (VWN), efficient resourceutilization, and isolation between network slices (i.e., MVNOs). Inthis paper, we consider wireless network slicing fora single InPwho owns radio resources and multiple MVNOs who need radioresources to provide specific services to their mobile users. Oneof the challenges in wireless network slicing is how toefficiently allocate the limited radio resources available at theInP to the MVNOs. In this paper, we addressthe problem of efficient allocation of the InP radioresources to the MVNOs which aims to maximize thetotal network capacity of the InP. To this end,we decompose our considered problem into two phases. Thefirst phase is an efficient allocation of the InP radioresources (bandwidth) to the MVNOs, and the second phaseis an optimal allocation of MVNOs resources gained fromthe InP to their mobile users. We then proposea Generalized Kelly Mechanism framework and the Karush-Kuhn-Tucker (KKT) conditions to solve the first and thesecond phase of our resource allocation problem, respectively.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>