<reference anchor="I-D.mackay-aacp" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-mackay-aacp-01">
  <front>
    <title>Agent Action Compression Protocol (AACP) Version 1.1</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-mackay-aacp-01"/>
    <author initials="A." surname="Mackay" fullname="Andrew Mackay">
      <organization>Independent</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="30" month="May" year="2026"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document defines the Agent Action Compression Protocol (AACP), a
   pipe-delimited coordination format for agent-to-agent communication
   in multi-agent large language model (LLM) systems.  AACP transforms
   verbose natural language coordination instructions into
   deterministic, typed, machine-parseable packets that can be validated
   before transmission, logged as structured audit records, and replayed
   consistently across workflow runs.

   For known workflow types, a rule-based encoder produces AACP packets
   deterministically at zero LLM cost.  A three-tier fallback encoder
   extends this to novel instructions: exact matches are served from a
   local registry cache at zero cost; pattern matches route to rule-
   based encoding at zero cost; novel instructions are encoded via LLM
   and logged to the registry, ensuring each novel pattern incurs at
   most one LLM encoding call regardless of how many times it
   subsequently appears.

   As a secondary benefit, AACP reduces coordination token usage by
   approximately 23 percent versus equivalent natural language
   instructions, measured against live API tokenisation on Claude Sonnet
   4.5 and GPT-4o.  Consistent token reduction has been validated across
   four models: Claude Sonnet 4.5, GPT-4o, GPT-4.1, and GPT-4.1-mini.

   AACP operates above transport protocols such as the Model Context
   Protocol (MCP) and Agent-to-Agent Protocol (A2A), compressing message
   payload content rather than addressing routing or delivery.  The
   protocol is transport-agnostic, model-agnostic, and designed to
   complement rather than replace existing agent coordination
   infrastructure.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>