<reference anchor="I-D.nichols-iotops-defined-trust-transport" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-nichols-iotops-defined-trust-transport-04">
  <front>
    <title>Defined-Trust Transport (DeftT) Protocol for Limited Domains</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-nichols-iotops-defined-trust-transport-04"/>
    <author initials="K." surname="Nichols" fullname="Kathleen Nichols">
      <organization>Pollere LLC</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="V." surname="Jacobson" fullname="Van Jacobson">
      <organization>UCLA</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="R." surname="King" fullname="Randy King">
      <organization>Operant Networks Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="31" month="March" year="2024"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document describes a broadcast-oriented, many-to-many Defined-
   trust Transport (DeftT) framework that makes it simple to express and
   enforce application and deployment specific integrity,
   authentication, access control and behavior constraints directly in
   the protocol stack.  DeftT enables secure and completely self-
   contained (e.g., no external identity servers or certificate
   authorities) overlay networks where credentialed members can join and
   leave at any time.  DeftT is part of a Defined-trust Communications
   approach with a specific example implementation available.  Combined
   with IPv6 multicast and modern hardware-based methods for securing
   keys and code, it provides an easy to use foundation for secure and
   efficient communications in Limited Domains (RFC8799), in particular
   for Operational Technology (OT) networks.

   Conventional IP transports create optionally secured one-to-one
   sessions.  Where member identities exist, they must either be
   validated via external servers or all member identities must be be
   preconfigured in each member during enrollment.  Synchronization of
   data across a domain is carried out through multiple two-party
   transport sessions.  In contrast, DeftT is a multi-party transport
   that synchronizes collections of secured information across all
   enrolled members of a domain.  Security in DeftT is not optional and
   members are preconfigured only with their own identities and the
   secured rules to authenticate other member identities.

   This document describes an architecture that is not a standard and
   does not enjoy IETF consensus.  (The community is invited to consider
   standardizing its concepts and the specification.)</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>