<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-pce-pcep-extension-pce-controller-srv6" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-ietf-pce-pcep-extension-pce-controller-srv6-03">
  <front>
    <title>PCE Communication Protocol (PCEP) Extensions for Using the PCE as a Central Controller (PCECC) for Segment Routing over IPv6 (SRv6) Segment Identifier (SID) Allocation and Distribution.</title>
    <author fullname="Zhenbin Li" initials="Z." surname="Li">
      <organization>Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Shuping Peng" initials="S." surname="Peng">
      <organization>Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Xuesong Geng" initials="X." surname="Geng">
      <organization>Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Mahendra Singh Negi" initials="M. S." surname="Negi">
      <organization>RtBrick Inc</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2024" month="August" day="18"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>The PCE is a core component of Software-Defined Networking (SDN) systems. A PCE-based Central Controller (PCECC) can simplify the processing of a distributed control plane by blending it with elements of SDN without necessarily completely replacing it. Segment Routing (SR) technology leverages the source routing and tunneling paradigms. Each path is specified as a set of "segments" encoded in the header of each packet as a list of Segment Identifiers (SIDs). This document specifies the procedures and Path Computation Element Communication Protocol (PCEP) extensions when a PCE-based controller is also responsible for configuring the forwarding actions on the routers, in addition to computing the paths for packet flows in the SRv6 (SR in IPv6) network and telling the edge routers what instructions to attach to packets as they enter the network. PCECC is further enhanced for SRv6 SID allocation and distribution.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-pce-pcep-extension-pce-controller-srv6-03"/>
</reference>