<reference anchor="I-D.irtf-nfvrg-gaps-network-virtualization">
  <front>
    <title>Gap Analysis on Network Virtualization Activities</title>
    <author fullname="Carlos J. Bernardos" initials="C. J." surname="Bernardos">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Akbar Rahman" initials="A." surname="Rahman">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Juan-Carlos Zúñiga" initials="J. C." surname="Zúñiga">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Luis M. Contreras" initials="L. M." surname="Contreras">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Pedro A. Aranda" initials="P. A." surname="Aranda">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <date year="2016" month="July"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document describes open research challenges for network virtualization. Network virtualization is following a similar path as previously taken by Cloud computing. Specifically, Cloud computing popularized migration of computing functions (e.g., applications) and storage from local, dedicated, physical resources to remote virtual functions accessible through the Internet. In a similar manner, network virtualization is encouraging migration of networking functions from dedicated physical hardware nodes to a virtualized pool of resources. However, network virtualization can be considered to be a more complex problem than Cloud computing as it not only involves virtualization of computing and storage functions but also involves abstraction of the network itself. This document describes current research challenges in network virtualization including service guarantees, energy efficiency, supporting multiple domains, network slicing, self-management, privacy and security. In addition, some proposals are made for new activities in IETF/IRTF that could address some of these challenges.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-irtf-nfvrg-gaps-network-virtualization-01"/>
</reference>