<reference anchor="I-D.cha-manet-extended-support-globalv6">
  <front>
    <title>Extended Support for Global Connectivity for IPv6 Mobile Ad Hoc Networks</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-cha-manet-extended-support-globalv6-00"/>
    <author fullname="Hyun-Wook Cha" initials="H." surname="Cha"/>
    <author fullname="Park Jung-Soo" initials="J." surname="Jung-Soo"/>
    <author fullname="Hyoung-Jun Kim" initials="H." surname="Kim"/>
    <date year="2003" month="October" day="23"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document describes how to provide enhanced Internet connectivityto mobile ad hoc networks. To achieve this goal, we borrow theconcept of Mobile IPv6 and make the most use of available multiplegateways. Specifically, our scheme makes a global address being usedby Upper layer reachable by peer Internet node by registering anotherglobal address as a locator with corresponding gateway for theaddress being cared while the gateway can not obtain host routeinformation for the cared address because of frequent partitions.We introduce stateful auto-configuration for acquisition of globaladdress in mobile ad-hoc networks because it can avoid duplicateaddress problem and help prevent traffics from going outside a manetor unnecessary control traffic by route discovery of reactive routingprotocols from being issued. In addition, it can support for ourscheme since our scheme requires some security guarantee to registera locator with a gateway as Mobile IPv6 requires for Binding Updates.Basically, our extended support and stateful configuration of globaladdress are devised to extend AODV, but the concept is alsoapplicable for proactive routing protocols such as OLSR, TBRPF.Further, our extended support can be useful for a mobile node(MN) inMobile IPv6 to maintain its reachability from the Internet byutilizing multi-hop manet extension as a virtual link since it canhelp determine intelligently when current CoA should be changed andBinding Update with new CoA be performed while it can make thecurrent CoA reachable from Internet even when the GW which assignedthe CoA is not reachable from the manet node any more.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>