<reference anchor="I-D.larmouth-oid-iri">
  <front>
    <title>An IRI/URI Namespace for International Object Identifiers (OIDs)</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-larmouth-oid-iri-04"/>
    <author fullname="John Larmouth"/>
    <author fullname="Olivier Dubuisson"/>
    <date year="2010" month="January" day="20"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This internet draft defines the IRI/URI scheme for InternationalObject Identifiers. The syntax and semantics of the IRI is specifiedbelow using the International Object Identifier tree specified inITU-T X.660: "International Object Identifiers".Status of this MemoThis Internet-Draft is submitted to IETF in full conformance with theprovisions of BCP 78 and BCP 79.Internet-Drafts are working documents of the Internet EngineeringTask Force (IETF), its areas, and its working groups. Note thatother groups may also distribute working documents as Internet-Drafts.Internet-Drafts are draft documents valid for a maximum of six monthsand may be updated, replaced, or obsoleted by other documents at anytime. It is inappropriate to use Internet-Drafts as referencematerial or to cite them other than as "work in progress."The list of current Internet-Drafts can be accessed athttp://www.ietf.org/ietf/1id-abstracts.txt.The list of Internet-Draft Shadow Directories can be accessed athttp://www.ietf.org/shadow.html.This Internet-Draft will expire on July 24, 2010.Copyright NoticeCopyright (c) 2010 IETF Trust and the persons identified as thedocument authors. All rights reserved.This document is subject to BCP 78 and the IETF Trust's LegalProvisions Relating to IETF Documents(http://trustee.ietf.org/license-info) in effect on the date ofpublication of this document. Please review these documentscarefully, as they describe your rights and restrictions with respectto this document. Code Components extracted from this document mustinclude Simplified BSD License text as described in Section 4.e ofthe Trust Legal Provisions and are provided without warranty asdescribed in the BSD License.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>