<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-idr-bgpls-sr-vtn-mt" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-ietf-idr-bgpls-sr-vtn-mt-11">
  <front>
    <title>Applicability of Border Gateway Protocol - Link State (BGP-LS) with Multi-Topology (MT) for Segment Routing based Network Resource Partitions (NRPs)</title>
    <author fullname="Chongfeng Xie" initials="C." surname="Xie">
      <organization>China Telecom</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Cong Li" initials="C." surname="Li">
      <organization>China Telecom</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jie Dong" initials="J." surname="Dong">
      <organization>Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Zhenbin Li" initials="Z." surname="Li">
      <organization>Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2025" month="June" day="13"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>An NRP is a subset of the network resources and associated policies on each of a connected set of links in the underlay network. An NRP could be used as the underlay to support one or a group of enhanced VPN services, which provide advanced features such as guaranteed resources, bounded latency or jitter to meet specific customer connectivity requirements. When Segment Routing (SR) is used for building NRPs, each NRP can be allocated with a group of Segment Identifiers (SIDs) to identify the topology and resource attributes of network segments in the NRP. In some network scenarios, each NRP can be associated with a unique logical network topology. When a centralized network controller is used for NRP-specific constraint-based path computation, especially when an NRP spans multiple IGP areas or multiple Autonomous Systems (ASes), BGP-LS is needed to advertise the NRP topology and associated resource information to the network controller. This document describes a mechanism to distribute the information of SR based NRPs using BGP-LS with MT.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-idr-bgpls-sr-vtn-mt-11"/>
</reference>