<reference anchor="I-D.mendes-icnrg-dabber" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-mendes-icnrg-dabber-01">
  <front>
    <title>Information-centric Routing for Opportunistic Wireless Networks</title>
    <author fullname="Paulo Mendes" initials="P." surname="Mendes">
      <organization>COPELABS/University Lusofona</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Rute C. Sofia" initials="R. C." surname="Sofia">
      <organization>Senception/COPELABS/University Lusofona</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Vassilis Tsaoussidis" initials="V." surname="Tsaoussidis">
      <organization>Democritus University of Thrace</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Sotiris Diamantopoulos" initials="S." surname="Diamantopoulos">
      <organization>Democritus University of Thrace</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Christos-Alexandros Sarros" initials="C." surname="Sarros">
      <organization>Democritus University of Thrace</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2018" month="August" day="27"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This draft describes the Data reAchaBility BasEd Routing (DABBER) protocol, which has been developed to extend the reached of Named Data Networking based routing approaches to opportunistic wireless networks. By "opportunistic wireless networks" it is meant multi-hop wireless networks where finding an end-to-end path between any pair of nodes at any moment in time may be a challenge. The goal is to assist in better defining opportunities for the transmission of Interest packets towards the most suitable data source, based on metrics that provide information about: i) the availability of different data sources; ii) the availability and centrality of neighbor nodes; iii) the time lapse between forwarding Interest packets and receiving the corresponding data packets. The document presents an architectural overview of DABBER followed by specification options related to the dissemination of name-prefix information to support the computation of next hops, and the ranking of forwarding options based on the best set of neighbors to ensure a short time-to-completion.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-mendes-icnrg-dabber-01"/>
</reference>