<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-ospf-ospfv2-hbit">
  <front>
    <title>Host Router Support for OSPFv2</title>
    <author fullname="Keyur Patel" initials="K." surname="Patel">
      <organization>Arrcus</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Padma Pillay-Esnault" initials="P." surname="Pillay-Esnault">
      <organization>Futurewei</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Manish Bhardwaj" initials="M." surname="Bhardwaj">
      <organization>Cisco Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Serpil Bayraktar" initials="S." surname="Bayraktar">
      <organization>Cisco Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2019" month="July" day="8"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>The OSPFv2 specifies an SPF algorithm that identifies transit vertices based on their adjacencies. Therefore, OSPFv2 does not have a mechanism to prevent traffic transiting a participating node if it is a transit vertex in the only existing or shortest path to the destination. The use of metrics to make the node undesirable can only help to repel traffic if an alternative better route exists. This document defines the Host-bit functionality to prevent other OSPFv2 routers from using the router for transit traffic in OSPFv2 routing domains. This document updates the Open Shortest Path First v2 specification (OSPFv2 rfc2328) by assigning a new bit (Host-bit) in the OSPF Router-LSA bit registry. In addition, if the Host-bit is set, the calculation of the shortest-path tree for an area, as described in OSPFv2, is modified by including a new check to verify that transit vertices have the Host-bit clear. In addition, this document updates OSPF Stub Router Advertisement (rfc6987) to advertise for type-2 External and NSSA LSAs with a high cost in order to repel traffic effectively.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-ospf-ospfv2-hbit-08"/>
  <format type="TXT" target="https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-ietf-ospf-ospfv2-hbit-08.txt"/>
</reference>