<reference anchor="I-D.usama-tls-risks-of-mlkem" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-usama-tls-risks-of-mlkem-02">
  <front>
    <title>Potential Risks of Standalone ML-KEM in TLS 1.3</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-usama-tls-risks-of-mlkem-02"/>
    <author initials="M. U." surname="Sardar" fullname="Muhammad Usama Sardar">
      <organization>TU Dresden, Germany</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="04" month="June" year="2026"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>We attest that standalone ML-KEM in TLS 1.3 breaks the existing
   formal proofs of TLS in state-of-the-art symbolic security analysis
   tool, ProVerif.  We believe this requires a new symbolic proof in
   ProVerif.  To help inform the analysis, we share our understanding of
   *exactly* where the ProVerif proofs break, namely transition from
   symmetric DHKE to asymmetric KEM.  More specifically, our
   understanding is that the existing proofs of TLS in ProVerif are
   based on commutativity property, whereas commutativity does not apply
   to standalone ML-KEM in TLS.

   In general, we see no reason to believe that hybrid key exchanges are
   not _at least_ as strong as the stronger of the two components.  We
   invite collaborations or independent analysis to extend the ProVerif
   models to perform such analysis and offer a statement for security
   considerations of [I-D.ietf-tls-mlkem].  In our understanding, a
   couple of WG participants have already started formal analysis in
   ProVerif.

   We also attest that from a formal analysis perspective, this is a
   much bigger change than RFC8773bis, which indeed went for FATT review
   (cf. [TLS-FATT]).  We, therefore, formally request the chairs to
   initiate the FATT review of standalone ML-KEM in TLS.

   This draft also offers some preliminary discussion to help the
   developers and policy makers make informed choices.  Finally, the
   draft also aims to reduce the endless repitition of arguments from
   both sides presented on several lists by documenting these arguments
   so they can simply be referred to.  We sincerely believe this will
   help to focus the discussion on technical matters, such as system
   model, threat model, security properties, and deployments.

   We acknowledge several IETF participants who have contributed to this
   draft with their insights.  This draft captures what _we_ understand
   them to be saying.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>