<reference anchor="I-D.zhang-ccamp-transport-yang-gap-analysis">
  <front>
    <title>YANG Models for the Northbound Interface of a Transport Network Controller: Requirements and Gap Analysis</title>
    <author fullname="Xian Zhang" initials="X." surname="Zhang">
      <organization>Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="ansharma@infinera.com" initials="" surname="ansharma@infinera.com">
      <organization>Infinera</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Sergio Belotti" initials="S." surname="Belotti">
      <organization>Nokia</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Tara Cummings" initials="T." surname="Cummings">
      <organization>Ericsson</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2016" month="October" day="30"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>A transport network is a lower-layer network designed to provide connectivity services for a higher-layer network to carry the traffic opaquely across the lower-layer network resources. A transport network may be constructed from equipment utilizing any of a number of different transport technologies such as the optical transport infrastructure (Synchronous Optical Networking (SONET) / Synchronous Digital Hierarchy (SDH) and Optical Transport Network (OTN)) or packet transport as epitomized by the MPLS Transport Profile (MPLS- TP). All transport networks have high benchmarks for reliability and operational simplicity. This suggests a common, technology- independent management/control paradigm that can be extended to represent and configure specific technology attributes. This document describes the high-level requirements facing transport networks in order to provide open interfaces for resource programmability and control/management automation. Furtheremore, gap analysis against existing models are also provided so that it can used as the guidance to separate efforts/drafts proposing new models or augmentation models based on existing models.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-zhang-ccamp-transport-yang-gap-analysis-01"/>
  <format type="TXT" target="https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-zhang-ccamp-transport-yang-gap-analysis-01.txt"/>
</reference>