<reference anchor="I-D.irtf-icnrg-icniot">
  <front>
    <title>Design Considerations for Applying ICN to IoT</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-irtf-icnrg-icniot-01"/>
    <author fullname="Ravi Ravindran" initials="R." surname="Ravindran">
      <organization>Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Yanyong Zhang" initials="Y." surname="Zhang">
      <organization>WINLAB, Rutgers University</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Luigi Alfredo Grieco" initials="L. A." surname="Grieco">
      <organization>Politecnico di Bari (DEI)</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Anders Lindgren" initials="A." surname="Lindgren">
      <organization>RISE SICS</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Dipankar Raychadhuri" initials="D." surname="Raychadhuri">
      <organization>WINLAB, Rutgers University</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Emmanuel Baccelli" initials="E." surname="Baccelli">
      <organization>INRIA</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jeff Burke" initials="J." surname="Burke">
      <organization>UCLA REMAP</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Guoqiang Wang" initials="G." surname="Wang">
      <organization>Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Bengt Ahlgren" initials="B." surname="Ahlgren">
      <organization>RISE SICS</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Olov Schelen" initials="O." surname="Schelen">
      <organization>Lulea University of Technology</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2018" month="February" day="16"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>The Internet of Things (IoT) promises to connect billions of objects to the Internet. After deploying many stand-alone IoT systems in different domains, the current trend is to develop a common, "thin waist" of protocols to enable a horizontally unified IoT architecture. The objective of such an architecture is to make resource objects securely accessible to applications across organizations and domains. Towards this goal, quite a few proposals have been made to build an application-layer based unified IoT platform on top of today's host-centric Internet. However, there is a fundamental mismatch between the host-centric nature of today's Internet and mostly information-centric nature of the IoT system. To address this mismatch the common set of protocols and network services offered by an information-centric network (ICN) architecture can be leveraged to realize ICN-IoT architectures. These ICN-IoT solutions leverages the salient features of ICN, and taking advantage of naming, security, mobility and efficient content and service delivery support. This draft summarizes general IoT demands, and covers the challenges and design to realize ICN-IoT frameworks based on ICN architecture. Beyond this, the goal of this draft is not to offer any specific ICN- IoT architectural proposals.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>