<reference anchor="I-D.koch-openpgp-2015-rfc4880bis" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-koch-openpgp-2015-rfc4880bis-00">
  <front>
    <title>OpenPGP Message Format</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-koch-openpgp-2015-rfc4880bis-00"/>
    <author initials="W." surname="Koch" fullname="Werner Koch">
      <organization>GnuPG e.V.</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="B. M." surname="carlson" fullname="brian m. carlson"/>
    <author initials="R. H." surname="Tse" fullname="Ronald Henry Tse">
      <organization>Ribose</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="D." surname="Atkins" fullname="Derek Atkins"/>
    <author initials="D. K." surname="Gillmor" fullname="Daniel Kahn Gillmor"/>
    <date day="06" month="September" year="2022"></date>
    <abstract>
      <t>   { Work in progress to update the OpenPGP specification from RFC4880 }

   { This version is on the Git head with rfc4880bis-10 before the great
   refactoring.  That refactoring, dubbed crypto-refresh, basically
   started from scratch with lots of re-formatting and switching to a
   Gitlab based approach with merge requests mainly prepared in advance
   by one of the chairs.  This was done despite that -10 was basically
   ready for last call after a long iterative process adding feature by
   feature with rough consent from the WG.

   Due to the IETF submission system the draft has a new name but
   nevertheless is the direct successor of draft-ietf-openpgp-
   rfc4880bis-10 }

   This document specifies the message formats used in OpenPGP.  OpenPGP
   provides encryption with public-key or symmetric cryptographic
   algorithms, digital signatures, compression and key management.

   This document is maintained in order to publish all necessary
   information needed to develop interoperable applications based on the
   OpenPGP format.  It is not a step-by-step cookbook for writing an
   application.  It describes only the format and methods needed to
   read, check, generate, and write conforming packets crossing any
   network.  It does not deal with storage and implementation questions.
   It does, however, discuss implementation issues necessary to avoid
   security flaws.

	 </t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>