<reference anchor="I-D.lee-dns-hidns" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-lee-dns-hidns-00">
  <front>
    <title>DNS-based Resolution of Heterogeneous Identifiers (Hi-DNS)</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-lee-dns-hidns-00"/>
    <author initials="X." surname="Lee" fullname="XiaoDong Lee">
      <organization>Institute of Computing Technology, Chinese Academy of Sciences</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="B." surname="Peng" fullname="Botao Peng">
      <organization>Institute of Computing Technology, Chinese Academy of Sciences</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="J." surname="Lee" fullname="Jingwen Lee">
      <organization>Institute of Computing Technology, Chinese Academy of Sciences</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="09" month="November" year="2025"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>   Formally, the Domain Name System (DNS) has the capability to resolve
   any registered name to its associated data.  However, current
   heterogeneous identifiers (such as DOI, Handle, Ecode, etc.) rely on
   isolated and incompatible resolution systems, leading to fragmented
   client implementations and failing to fully leverage the existing
   Internet infrastructure.  This specification defines an operational
   practice that achieves DNS-based heterogeneous identifier resolution
   by mapping identifier values to dedicated DNS namespaces under the
   authority of their respective identifier systems.  This mapping
   follows standardized rules compatible with the Internationalized
   Domain Names in Applications (IDNA) framework, allowing identifiers
   to be converted into domain names that can be resolved through
   standard DNS queries (for A, AAAA, or CNAME records).  This approach
   establishes a unified semantic scope for identifier resolution,
   providing clients with a single, consistent access interface.  Its
   primary advantage lies in integrating diverse identifier systems into
   the robust, scalable, and globally deployed DNS infrastructure,
   thereby simplifying client development and improving overall
   resolution efficiency.

	 </t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>