<reference anchor="I-D.yang-dmsc-gateway-mediation-layer" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-yang-dmsc-gateway-mediation-layer-00">
  <front>
    <title>Gateway Mediation Layer for AI Agent Collaboration</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-yang-dmsc-gateway-mediation-layer-00"/>
    <author initials="H." surname="Yang" fullname="Huiling Yang">
      <organization>AsiaInfo Technologies (China) Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="G." surname="Dong" fullname="Guozhen Dong">
      <organization>China Telecom</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="L." surname="Zhang" fullname="Lianhua Zhang">
      <organization>AsiaInfo Technologies (China) Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="Y." surname="Li" fullname="Yun Li">
      <organization>AsiaInfo Technologies (China) Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="S." surname="Wang" fullname="Shoufeng Wang">
      <organization>AsiaInfo Technologies (China) Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="05" month="July" year="2026"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Cross-domain and policy-controlled agent collaboration can require
   mediation decisions that are not always suitable for an agent client
   or an agent server alone.  A collaboration request may need to
   combine a stated goal, capability profiles, tenant or domain policy,
   trust evidence, disclosure limits, operational constraints, and
   handoff context before a concrete interaction mechanism is used.

   This document identifies gateway-side interaction mediation as a
   distinct interoperability gap in many AI Agent Gateway deployments.
   It does not claim that every agent collaboration requires a gateway.
   Rather, it explains why many deployments need a mediation point where
   request goals, capability profiles, policy, trust, and handoff
   constraints can be evaluated before interaction proceeds.

   The document describes a Gateway Mediation Layer as a decision-
   support and interface layer between application-level goals and
   concrete agent interaction mechanisms.  It focuses on the role,
   inputs, outputs, and narrow set of interoperable artifacts that may
   require further work, such as Mediation Requests, Mediation
   Responses, Handoff Contexts, Failure Records, and Evidence
   References.  It does not propose standardizing internal matching
   algorithms, domain ontologies, prompt engineering, or model-specific
   decision logic.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>