<reference anchor="I-D.dannewitz-ppsp-secure-naming">
  <front>
    <title>Secure naming structure and p2p application interaction</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-dannewitz-ppsp-secure-naming-02"/>
    <author fullname="Christian Dannewitz"/>
    <author fullname="Teemu Rautio"/>
    <author fullname="Ove Strandberg"/>
    <author fullname="Borje Ohlman"/>
    <date year="2011" month="March" day="14"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Today, each application typically uses its own way to identify data.The lack of a common naming scheme prevents applications frombenefiting from available copies of the same data distributed viadifferent P2P and CDN systems. The main proposal presented in thisdraft is idea that there should be a secure and applicationindependent way of naming information objects that are transportedover the Internet. The draft defines a set of requirements for sucha naming structure. It also presents a proposal for such a namingstructure that could relevant for a number of work groups (existingand potential), e.g. PPSP, DECADE and CDNI. In addition, today'sP2P naming schemes lack important security aspects that would allowthe user to check the data integrity and build trust in data and datapublishers. This is especially important in P2P applications as datais received from untrusted peers. Providing a generic naming schemefor P2P systems so that multiple P2P systems can use the same dataregardless of data location and P2P system increases the efficiencyand data availability of the overall data dissemination process. Thesecure naming scheme is providing self-certification such that thereceiver can verify the data integrity, i.e., that the correct datahas been received, without requiring a trusted third party. It alsoenables owner authentication to build up trust in (potentiallyanonymous) data publishers. The secure naming structure should bebeneficial as potential design principle in defining the twoprotocols identified as objectives in the PPSP charter. Thisdocument enumerates a number of design considerations to impact thedesign and implementation of the tracker-peer signaling and peer-peerstreaming signaling protocols.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>