<reference anchor="I-D.veridom-omp-aiins" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-veridom-omp-aiins-00">
  <front>
    <title>OMP Domain Profile: AI Liability Insurance Underwriting and Parametric Claims Evidence</title>
    <author fullname="Tolulope Adebayo" initials="T." surname="Adebayo">
      <organization>Veridom Ltd</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Oluropo Apalowo" initials="O." surname="Apalowo">
      <organization>Veridom Ltd</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Festus Makanjuola" initials="F." surname="Makanjuola">
      <organization>Veridom Ltd</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2026" month="April" day="5"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document defines a domain profile of the Operating Model Protocol (OMP) for AI systems deployed in contexts covered by AI liability insurance policies, including AI performance warranties, AI errors and omissions coverage, and coordinated AI liability structures. The profile -- designated InsureMark -- specifies how OMP's deterministic routing invariant, Watchtower enforcement framework, and three-layer cryptographic integrity architecture generate per-decision Proof-Points that function as objective parametric trigger data for AI liability insurance claims, and provide independently verifiable underwriting evidence that reduces claims ambiguity and supports premium differentiation. The InsureMark profile addresses the primary gap in current AI liability insurance underwriting: policies are currently issued based on model-level performance assessments, but claims arise at the level of individual AI decisions. No current AI liability insurance product requires or receives per-decision cryptographic evidence. This profile specifies the technical architecture by which OMP Proof- Points close this gap. The OMP core specification is defined in the Operating Model Protocol Internet-Draft (draft-veridom-omp).</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-veridom-omp-aiins-00"/>
</reference>