<reference anchor="I-D.johnston-rtcweb-zrtp">
  <front>
    <title>Using ZRTP to Secure WebRTC</title>
    <author fullname="Alan Johnston" initials="A." surname="Johnston">
      <organization>Avaya</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Philip Zimmermann" initials="P." surname="Zimmermann">
      <organization>Silent Circle</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jon Callas" initials="J." surname="Callas">
      <organization>Silent Circle</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Travis Cross" initials="T." surname="Cross">
      <organization>OfficeTone</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="John Yoakum" initials="J." surname="Yoakum">
      <organization>Avaya</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2015" month="July" day="6"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>WebRTC, Web Real-Time Communications, is a set of protocols and APIs used to enable web developers to add real-time communications into their web pages and applications with a few lines of JavaScript. WebRTC media flows are encrypted and authenticated by SRTP, the Secure Real-time Transport Protocol while the key agreement is provided by DTLS-SRTP, Datagram Transport Layer Security for Secure Real-time Transport Protocol. However, without some third party identity service or certificate authority, WebRTC media flows have no protection against a man-in-the-middle (MitM) attack. ZRTP, Media Path Key Agreement for Unicast Secure RTP, RFC 6189, does provide protection against MitM attackers using key continuity augmented with a Short Authentication String (SAS). This specification describes how ZRTP can be used over the WebRTC data channel to provide MitM protection for WebRTC media flows keyed using DTLS-SRTP. This provides users protection against MitM attackers without requiring browsers to support ZRTP or users to download a plugin or extension to implement ZRTP.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-johnston-rtcweb-zrtp-02"/>
  <format type="TXT" target="https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-johnston-rtcweb-zrtp-02.txt"/>
</reference>