<reference anchor="I-D.veridom-omp-sacco" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-veridom-omp-sacco-00">
  <front>
    <title>OMP Domain Profile: Kenya Deposit-Taking SACCOs -- SASRA Supervision and Cooperative Governance Accountability</title>
    <author fullname="Tolulope Adebayo" initials="T." surname="Adebayo">
      <organization>Veridom Ltd</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Festus Makanjuola" initials="F." surname="Makanjuola">
      <organization>Veridom Ltd</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2026" month="March" day="22"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document defines the OMP domain profile for deposit-taking SACCOs (Savings and Credit Cooperative Organisations) operating under SASRA supervision in Kenya. It specifies the Intent Class configuration, routing threshold ranges, Watchtower definitions, and Audit Trace extensions required to satisfy board-level principal accountability requirements under the SACCO Societies Act and the Cooperatives Bill 2024. The PricewaterhouseCoopers forensic audit of KUSCCO [KUSCCO-PWC-2025] (Kenya Union of Savings and Credit Co-operatives), presented to the Cabinet Secretary for Cooperatives and MSMEs in 2025, identified KES 13.3 billion in misappropriated funds. Every specific failure identified -- forged auditor signatures, unauthorised executive loans, fraudulent commission rate changes, unlicensed operations -- was undetectable because no evidence trail connected board authorisation to operational outcome. This profile specifies the OMP architecture that closes each of those specific failure modes. The Cooperatives Bill 2024 [COOPERATIVES-BILL-2024] (Bill No. 7 of 2024), currently before the Kenyan Senate, introduces criminal penalties for SACCO board directors who cannot produce governance evidence. This profile REQUIRES implementation of the core OMP protocol as defined in [I-D.veridom-omp]. The full specification is also available at [ZENODO-OMP].</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-veridom-omp-sacco-00"/>
</reference>