<reference anchor="I-D.siddiqui-rmonmib-raqmon-framework">
  <front>
    <title>Real-time Application Quality of Service Monitoring (RAQMON) Framework</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-siddiqui-rmonmib-raqmon-framework-00"/>
    <author fullname="Anwar A. Siddiqui" initials="A. A." surname="Siddiqui">
      <organization>Avaya Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Dan Romascanu" initials="D." surname="Romascanu">
      <organization>Avaya Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Eugene Golovinsky" initials="E." surname="Golovinsky">
      <organization>BMC Software</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2002" month="October" day="23"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>There is a need to extend the RMON framework [RFC2819] to monitor enddevices such as IP phones, pagers, Instant Message Clients, mobilephones, and PDA devices. This memo proposes an extension of RMONFramework to allow Real-time Application QoS information of thesetypes of end devices to be retrieved with SNMP, independent of thetechnology used to perform the measurements. An end-to-end userexperience of the quality of service (QoS) and performance for suchan application is a combination of device performance, transportnetwork performance and specific application context.The memo also defines a common framework to identify a set ofapplication QoS parameters and a reporting mechanism using a commonprotocol data unit (PDU) format used between RAQMON Data Source (RDS)and RAQMON Report Collector (RRC) to report QOS statistics using RTCPand SNMP as underlying transport protocol.The original RAQMON draft &lt;draft-siddiqui-rmonmib-raqmon-mib-01.txt&gt;is split into 3 parts namely RAQMON Framework, RAQMON QOS PDU andRAQMON MIB. This memo only defines the RAQMON Framework along withcompanion drafts &lt;draft-siddiqui-rmonmib-raqmon-mib-02.txt&gt; thatdefines a portion of the Management Information Base (MIB) and&lt;draft-siddiqui-rmonmib-raqmon-pdu-00.txt&gt; that defines RAQMON PDUs.Distribution of this memo is unlimited.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>