<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-tsvwg-nqb" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-ietf-tsvwg-nqb-22">
  <front>
    <title>A Non-Queue-Building Per-Hop Behavior (NQB PHB) for Differentiated Services</title>
    <author fullname="Greg White" initials="G." surname="White">
      <organization>CableLabs</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Thomas Fossati" initials="T." surname="Fossati">
      <organization>Linaro</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Ruediger Geib" initials="R." surname="Geib">
      <organization>Deutsche Telekom</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2024" month="February" day="16"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document specifies characteristics of a Non-Queue-Building Per- Hop Behavior (NQB PHB). The NQB PHB provides a shallow-buffered, best-effort service as a complement to a Default deep-buffered best- effort service for Internet services. The purpose of this NQB PHB is to provide a separate queue that enables smooth (i.e. non-bursty), low-data-rate, application-limited traffic microflows, which would ordinarily share a queue with bursty and capacity-seeking traffic, to avoid the latency, latency variation and loss caused by such traffic. This PHB is implemented without prioritization and can be implemented without rate policing, making it suitable for environments where the use of these features is restricted. The NQB PHB has been developed primarily for use by access network segments, where queuing delays and queuing loss caused by Queue-Building protocols are manifested, but its use is not limited to such segments. In particular, applications to cable broadband links, Wi-Fi links, and mobile network radio and core segments are discussed. This document recommends a specific Differentiated Services Code Point (DSCP) to identify Non-Queue-Building microflows. [NOTE (to be removed by RFC-Editor): This document references an ISE submission draft (I-D.briscoe-docsis-q-protection) that is approved for publication as an RFC. This draft should be held for publication until the queue protection RFC can be referenced.]</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-tsvwg-nqb-22"/>
</reference>