<reference anchor="I-D.hood-agtp-composition" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-hood-agtp-composition-01">
  <front>
    <title>AGTP Composition Profiles: Agent Group Messaging Protocols, External Identity Providers, and HTTP Gateways</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-hood-agtp-composition-01"/>
    <author initials="C." surname="Hood" fullname="Chris Hood">
      <organization>Nomotic, Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="28" month="June" year="2026"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>The Agent Transfer Protocol (AGTP) operates as a substrate beneath
   several adjacent layers: Agent Group Messaging Protocols (AGMPs) such
   as the Model Context Protocol (MCP), the Agent-to-Agent Protocol
   (A2A), and the Agent Communication Protocol (ACP); external identity
   providers (OAuth, OIDC, enterprise IdPs); and HTTP-based clients that
   interact with agents through translation gateways.  This document
   specifies the composition profiles for each of these adjacent layers,
   defining normative mapping rules between the adjacent layer and AGTP.

   Three composition families are specified.  The AGMP composition
   profile specifies how MCP, A2A, and ACP messages are carried over
   AGTP, with mapping rules for identity, authority scope, delegation,
   and session fields between the AGMP and AGTP layers.  The External
   Identity Provider composition profile specifies how AGTP agent
   identity composes with externally-issued credentials, treating "which
   agent" and "on whose behalf" as orthogonal axes.  The HTTP Gateway
   composition profile specifies the translation surface for accepting
   HTTP traffic into AGTP- served agents as a REST adoption ramp.

   Across all three families, AGTP headers take precedence over
   equivalent adjacent-layer fields for all infrastructure-level
   routing, enforcement, and audit operations.  Agents gain transport-
   level governance, observability, and identity without modification to
   the adjacent layers.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>