<reference anchor="I-D.lopes-rank" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-lopes-rank-00">
  <front>
    <title>Rank, a Resource Management Protocol for Allocation</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-lopes-rank-00"/>
    <author initials="R. E." surname="Lopes" fullname="Rui Eduardo Lopes">
      <organization>Universidade de Aveiro and Instituto de Telecomunicações</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="D." surname="Raposo" fullname="Duarte Raposo">
      <organization>Instituto de Telecomunicações</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="S." surname="Sargento" fullname="Susana Sargento">
      <organization>Universidade de Aveiro and Instituto de Telecomunicações</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="29" month="June" year="2026"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document specifies Rank, a comprehensive resource management
   protocol designed for modern edge-to-cloud computing infrastructures.
   While traditional network protocols focus primarily on managing link
   bandwidth and router buffer space, the shift toward decentralized
   services demands a broader approach to resource allocation.  Rank
   addresses this gap by simultaneously managing computing capabilities
   (such as CPU, memory, and storage), network capacity, and time-
   sensitive constraints (such as clock synchronization and task
   scheduling) within a unified framework.

   Operating primarily as a fully distributed protocol, Rank enables
   dynamic resource discovery, estimation, allocation, and sharing.  It
   works by establishing a path between a source ("talker") and a
   destination ("listener") node, actively negotiating resource
   requirements across all intermediate nodes.  Because it is fully
   distributed, all participating nodes carry equal responsibility in
   handling a session, such as processing requests, evaluating their own
   capacity to meet the resource demands, and strategically forwarding
   messages to ensure an optimized, end-to-end connection without
   relying on a centralized controller.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>