<reference anchor="I-D.thomson-geopriv-indoor-location">
  <front>
    <title>Locations with Locally-Defined Coordinate Reference Systems for the Presence Information Data Format - Location Object (PIDF-LO)</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-thomson-geopriv-indoor-location-01"/>
    <author fullname="Martin Thomson"/>
    <author fullname="James Winterbottom"/>
    <date year="2009" month="November" day="30"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>A method is described for constructing a Presence Information DataFormat - Location Object (PIDF-LO) document that contains locationinformation using a locally-defined coordinate reference system(CRS). This form of representation allows for use of locally-definedcoordinates with potential advantages for improved accuracy andusability in local context, in particular location applications thatoperate indoors. A framework for defining a local CRS is provided.A process for transformation of coordinates defined in the local CRSand the widely used World Geodetic System 1984 (WGS84) CRS isdefined.Status of This MemoThis Internet-Draft is submitted to IETF in full conformance with theprovisions of BCP 78 and BCP 79.Internet-Drafts are working documents of the Internet EngineeringTask Force (IETF), its areas, and its working groups. Note thatother groups may also distribute working documents as Internet-Drafts.Internet-Drafts are draft documents valid for a maximum of six monthsand may be updated, replaced, or obsoleted by other documents at anytime. It is inappropriate to use Internet-Drafts as referencematerial or to cite them other than as "work in progress."The list of current Internet-Drafts can be accessed athttp://www.ietf.org/ietf/1id-abstracts.txt.The list of Internet-Draft Shadow Directories can be accessed athttp://www.ietf.org/shadow.html.This Internet-Draft will expire on June 3, 2010.Copyright NoticeCopyright (c) 2009 IETF Trust and the persons identified as thedocument authors. All rights reserved.This document is subject to BCP 78 and the IETF Trust's LegalProvisions Relating to IETF Documents(http://trustee.ietf.org/license-info) in effect on the date ofpublication of this document. Please review these documentscarefully, as they describe your rights and restrictions with respectto this document. Code Components extracted from this document mustinclude Simplified BSD License text as described in Section 4.e ofthe Trust Legal Provisions and are provided without warranty asdescribed in the BSD License.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>