<reference anchor="I-D.sogomonian-aiip-native-access-architecture" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-sogomonian-aiip-native-access-architecture-01">
  <front>
    <title>AIIP: Native Access Architecture for Autonomous Systems A Problem Statement and Architectural Exploration</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-sogomonian-aiip-native-access-architecture-01"/>
    <author initials="A." surname="Sogomonian" fullname="Aram Sogomonian">
      <organization>AIIF</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="10" month="June" year="2026"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>The Internet evolved around human interaction and information
   exchange.  Technologies such as DNS, HTTP, and the World Wide Web
   created a universal access layer that enables people to discover
   resources, retrieve information, and interact with services through
   common protocols and interfaces.

   As autonomous systems become increasingly capable of acting on behalf
   of users and organizations, new interoperability challenges emerge.
   Agents, robots, tools, and autonomous services must discover
   resources, invoke actions, delegate authority, execute tasks, enforce
   policy, and obtain verifiable outcomes across independently developed
   implementations.

   This document explores the concept of a native Internet access
   architecture for autonomous systems.  It examines whether autonomous
   systems require a dedicated access layer analogous to the role that
   DNS, HTTP, and the Web played for human information exchange.  The
   document clarifies the relationship between AIIP and existing
   Internet protocols, describes the architectural position of AIIP
   as a native access layer rather than a profile of HTTP, and
   provides context for
   AIIP-related work including identifiers, discovery, invocation,
   execution, delegation, policy enforcement, and execution outcome
   verification.

   This document is a problem statement and architectural exploration.
   It does not define protocol mechanisms.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>