<reference anchor="I-D.eckert-ietf-and-energy-overview" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-eckert-ietf-and-energy-overview-11">
  <front>
    <title>An Overview of Energy-related Efforts within the IETF, IRTF, and IAB</title>
    <author fullname="Toerless Eckert" initials="T. T." surname="Eckert">
      <organization>Futurewei Technologies USA</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Mohamed Boucadair" initials="M." surname="Boucadair">
      <organization>Orange</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Pascal Thubert" initials="P." surname="Thubert">
      <organization>Cisco Systems, Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jeff Tantsura" initials="J." surname="Tantsura">
      <organization>NVIDIA</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Carlos Pignataro" initials="C." surname="Pignataro">
      <organization>NC State University</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2025" month="September" day="16"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This memo provides a compilation of existing work performed by or proposed within the IETF, the IRTF, and the IAB that relates to energy and sustainability: awareness, management, control, or reduction of energy consumption. The principal goal of this document is to help IETF, IRTF, and IAB participants, especially newcomers and future contributors, become familiar with the body of work already published on energy-related topics. It provides the first consolidated catalog of such efforts, serving as an internal reference and orientation guide. In addition, the document raises awareness of the Internet’s role in energy efficiency and energy-related activities within the IETF, IRTF, and IAB more broadly. This helps continue identifying gaps and investigating solutions where further work may be needed, and also offers background for readers outside the IETF community who may be less familiar with how networking technologies contribute to energy savings. The scope of this document includes selected work from the IETF, IRTF, and IAB where relevant. This document is descriptive in nature and does not propose new work items. This document captures work until December 2022, when the "IAB workshop on Environmental Impact of Internet Applications and Systems" contextualized renewed community interest and discussion of the topic. This memo itself does not recommend or direct future work.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-eckert-ietf-and-energy-overview-11"/>
</reference>