<reference anchor="I-D.fossati-seat-early-attestation" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-fossati-seat-early-attestation-02">
  <front>
    <title>Using Attestation in Transport Layer Security (TLS) and Datagram Transport Layer Security (DTLS)</title>
    <author fullname="Yaron Sheffer" initials="Y." surname="Sheffer">
      <organization>Intuit</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Ionuț Mihalcea" initials="I." surname="Mihalcea">
      <organization>Arm Limited</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Yogesh Deshpande" initials="Y." surname="Deshpande">
      <organization>Arm Limited</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Thomas Fossati" initials="T." surname="Fossati">
      <organization>Linaro</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Tirumaleswar Reddy.K" initials="T." surname="Reddy.K">
      <organization>Nokia</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2026" month="January" day="13"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>The TLS handshake protocol allows authentication of one or both peers using static, long-term credentials. In some cases, it is also desirable to ensure that the peer runtime environment is in a secure state. Such an assurance can be achieved using remote attestation which is a process by which an entity produces Evidence about itself that another party can use to appraise whether that entity is found in a secure state. This document describes a series of protocol extensions to the TLS 1.3 handshake that enable the binding of the TLS authentication key to a remote attestation session. This enables an entity capable of producing attestation Evidence, such as a confidential workload running in a Trusted Execution Environment (TEE), or an IoT device that is trying to authenticate itself to a network access point, to present a more comprehensive set of security metrics to its peer. These extensions have been designed to allow the peers to use any attestation technology, in any remote attestation topology, and to use them mutually.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-fossati-seat-early-attestation-02"/>
</reference>