<reference anchor="I-D.sinnreich-interdomain-sip-qos-osp">
  <front>
    <title>Interdomain IP Communications with QoS, Authorization and Usage Reporting</title>
    <author fullname="Dr. Henry Sinnreich" initials="H." surname="Sinnreich">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Stephen Thomas" initials="S." surname="Thomas">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Steve Donovan" initials="S." surname="Donovan">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Diana J. Rawlins" initials="D. J." surname="Rawlins">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <date year="2000" month="March" day="14"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Commercial grade IP telephony requires linkage between call setup, end-to-end QoS setup, interdomain authorization and accounting. This draft considers the network model for inter-domain QoS for access and transit networks, the service models and policy implementation options. Also, interdomain authorization and accounting may require the trust services of a clearinghouse, to which the local policy server may outsource authorization for support for inter-domain accounting. The draft defines two options for QoS support for telephony: PSTN- style 'QoS Assured' or Internet-style 'QoS Enabled' service. Implementing the local policy or QoS deployment can also have two options: The more usual policy 'Pull Model' and the policy 'Push Model' that may be advantageous for large IP telephony gateway deployments. The draft illustrates the various combinations of QoS service and policy implementation for interdomain QoS with authorization and accounting. The inter-process communications between the SIP, SDP, RSVP and OSP protocol engines is illustrated. Future work for SIP/SDP and other extensions, QoS metric and policy is outlined to make interdomain QoS for IP telephony possible.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-sinnreich-interdomain-sip-qos-osp-02"/>
  <format type="TXT" target="https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-sinnreich-interdomain-sip-qos-osp-02.txt"/>
</reference>