<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-dtn-dtnma">
  <front>
    <title>DTN Management Architecture</title>
    <author fullname="Edward J. Birrane" initials="J." surname="Edward Birrane">
      <organization>Johns Hopkins Applied Physics Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Emery Annis" surname="Emery Annis">
      <organization>Johns Hopkins Applied Physics Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Sarah E. Heiner" initials="E." surname="Sarah Heiner">
      <organization>Johns Hopkins Applied Physics Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2022" month="March" day="6"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document describes a management architecture suitable for deployment in the Delay-Tolerant Networking (DTN) architecture. The DTN environment is characterized by a lack of end-to-end connectivity and communications delays that are both long-lives and unpredictable. A DTN Management Architecture (DTNMA) is needed that can operate without human- or system-in-the-loop synchronous interactivity and without reliance on transport-layer sessions. Within a DTNMA, nodes must provide both eventual data exchange and in-time local protection. This can be accomplished with the use of autonomous and asynchronous configuration and reporting. Despite the significant challenges to data transport, nodes must exhibit behavior that is both determinable and autonomous while maintaining as much compatibility with non-challenged-network operations concepts as possible. The DTNMA is supported by two types of asynchronous behavior. First, the DTNMA does not presuppose any synchronized transport behavior between managed and managing devices. Second, the DTNMA does not support any query-response semantics. In this way, the DTNMA allows for operation in extremely challenging conditions, to include over uni-directional links and cases where delays/disruptions prevent operation over traditional transport layers.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-dtn-dtnma-00"/>
  <format type="TXT" target="https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-ietf-dtn-dtnma-00.txt"/>
</reference>