<reference anchor="I-D.narajala-courtney-ansv2" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-narajala-courtney-ansv2-01">
  <front>
    <title>Agent Name Service v2 (ANS): A Domain-Anchored Trust Layer for Autonomous AI Agent Identity</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-narajala-courtney-ansv2-01"/>
    <author initials="S." surname="Courtney" fullname="Scott Courtney">
      <organization>GoDaddy</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="V. S." surname="Narajala" fullname="Vineeth Sai Narajala">
      <organization>OWASP</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="K." surname="Huang" fullname="Ken Huang">
      <organization>DistributedApps.ai</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="I." surname="Habler" fullname="Idan Habler">
      <organization>OWASP</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="A." surname="Sheriff" fullname="Akram Sheriff">
      <organization>Cisco Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="13" month="April" year="2026"></date>
    <abstract>
      <t>   Autonomous AI agents execute transactions across organizational
   boundaries.  No single agent platform provides the trust
   infrastructure they need.  This document defines the Agent Name
   Service (ANS) v2 protocol, which anchors every agent identity to a
   DNS domain name.  A Registration Authority (RA) verifies domain
   ownership via ACME, issues dual certificates (a Server Certificate
   from a public CA and an Identity Certificate from a private CA
   binding a version-specific ANSName), and seals every lifecycle event
   into an append-only Transparency Log aligned with IETF SCITT.  Three
   verification tiers -- Bronze (PKI), Silver (PKI + DANE), and Gold
   (PKI + DANE + Transparency Log) -- let clients choose assurance
   levels appropriate to transaction risk.  The architecture decouples
   identity from discovery: the RA publishes sealed events; independent
   Discovery Services build competitive indexes.  A three-layer trust
   framework separates foundational identity (Layer 1, this protocol),
   operational maturity (Layer 2, third-party attestors), and behavioral
   reputation (Layer 3, real-time scoring).

	 </t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>