<reference anchor="I-D.mishra-bess-deployment-guide-ipv4nlri-ipv6nh">
  <front>
    <title>Deployment Guidelines for Edge Peering IPv4-NLRI with IPv6-NH</title>
    <author fullname="Gyan Mishra" initials="G. S." surname="Mishra">
      <organization>Verizon Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Mankamana Prasad Mishra" initials="M. P." surname="Mishra">
      <organization>Cisco Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jeff Tantsura" initials="J." surname="Tantsura">
      <organization>Juniper Networks, Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Lili Wang" initials="L." surname="Wang">
      <organization>Juniper Networks, Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Qing Yang" initials="Q." surname="Yang">
      <organization>Arista Networks</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Adam Simpson" initials="A." surname="Simpson">
      <organization>Nokia</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Shuanglong Chen" initials="S." surname="Chen">
      <organization>Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2021" month="March" day="23"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>As Enterprises and Service Providers upgrade their brown field or green field MPLS/SR core to an IPv6 transport, Multiprotocol BGP (MP- BGP)now plays an important role in the transition of the core as well as edge from IPv4 to IPv6. Operators can now continue to support legacy IPv4, VPN-IPv4, and Multicast VPN-IPv4 customers. This document describes the critical use case and OPEX savings of being able to leverage the MP-BGP capability exchange usage as a pure transport, allowing both IPv4 and IPv6 to be carried over the same BGP TCP session. By doing so, allows for the elimination of Dual Stacking on the PE-CE connections. Thus making the eBGP peering IPv6-ONLY to now carry both IPv4 and IPv6 Network Layer Reachability Information (NLRI). This document now provides a solution for IXPs (Internet Exchange points) that are facing IPv4 address depletion at these peering points to use BGP-MP capability exchange defined in [RFC8950] to carry IPv4 (Network Layer Reachability Information) NLRI in an IPv6 next hop using the [RFC5565] softwire mesh framework.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-mishra-bess-deployment-guide-ipv4nlri-ipv6nh-02"/>
  <format type="TXT" target="https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-mishra-bess-deployment-guide-ipv4nlri-ipv6nh-02.txt"/>
</reference>