<reference anchor="I-D.barguil-teas-network-slices-instantation" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-barguil-teas-network-slices-instantation-10">
  <front>
    <title>Applicability of IETF-Defined Service and Network Data Models for Network Slice Service Management</title>
    <author fullname="Samier Barguil" initials="S." surname="Barguil">
      <organization>Nokia</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Luis M. Contreras" initials="L. M." surname="Contreras">
      <organization>Telefonica</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Victor Lopez" initials="V." surname="Lopez">
      <organization>Nokia</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Oscar Gonzalez de Dios" initials="O. G." surname="de Dios">
      <organization>Telefonica</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Mohamed Boucadair" initials="M." surname="Boucadair">
      <organization>Orange</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Reza Rokui" initials="R." surname="Rokui">
      <organization>Ciena</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2024" month="July" day="8"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document exemplifies how the various data models that are produced in the IETF can be combined in the context of Network Slice Services delivery. Specifically, this document describes the relationship between the Network Slice Service models for requesting Network Slice Services and both Service (e.g., the L3VPN Service Model, the L2VPN Service Model) and Network (e.g., the L3VPN Network Model, the L2VPN Network Model) models used during their realizations. In addition, this document describes the communication between a Network Slice Controller (NSC) and the network controllers for the realization of Network Slices. The Network Slice Service YANG model provides a customer-oriented view of the intended Network slice Service. Thus, once an NSC receives a request for a Slice Service request, the NSC has to map it to accomplish the specific objectives expected by the network controllers. Existing YANG network models are analyzed against Network Slice requirements, and the gaps in existing models are identified.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-barguil-teas-network-slices-instantation-10"/>
</reference>