<reference anchor="I-D.tschofenig-rats-psa-token" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-tschofenig-rats-psa-token-18">
  <front>
    <title>Arm's Platform Security Architecture (PSA) Attestation Token</title>
    <author fullname="Hannes Tschofenig" initials="H." surname="Tschofenig">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Simon Frost" initials="S." surname="Frost">
      <organization>Arm Limited</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Mathias Brossard" initials="M." surname="Brossard">
      <organization>Arm Limited</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Adrian L. Shaw" initials="A. L." surname="Shaw">
      <organization>HP Labs</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Thomas Fossati" initials="T." surname="Fossati">
      <organization>Linaro</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2023" month="December" day="4"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>The Platform Security Architecture (PSA) is a set of hardware and firmware specifications, backed by reference implementations and a security certification program (PSA Certified). The security specifications have been published by Arm, while the certification program and reference implementations are the result of a collaborative effort by companies from multiple sectors, including evaluation laboratories, semiconductor IP and security consultancy. The main objective of the PSA initiative is to assist device manufacturers and chip makers in incorporating best-practice security measures into their products. Devices that are PSA compliant can produce attestation tokens as described in this memo, which are the basis for many different protocols, including secure provisioning and network access control. This document specifies the PSA attestation token structure and semantics. The PSA attestation token is a profiled Entity Attestation Token (EAT). This specification describes what claims are used in an attestation token generated by PSA compliant systems, how these claims get serialized to the wire, and how they are cryptographically protected. This document is produced through the Independent RFC Stream and was not subject to the IETF's approval process.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-tschofenig-rats-psa-token-18"/>
</reference>