<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-netconf-over-quic" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-ietf-netconf-over-quic-07">
  <front>
    <title>NETCONF over QUIC</title>
    <author fullname="Jinyou Dai" initials="J." surname="Dai">
      <organization>Fiberhome Telecom LTD./CICT.</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Shaohua Yu" initials="S." surname="Yu">
      <organization>China PCL.</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Weiqiang Cheng" initials="W." surname="Cheng">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Marc Blanchet" initials="M." surname="Blanchet">
      <organization>Viagenie</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Per Andersson" initials="P." surname="Andersson">
      <organization>Ionio Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2026" month="January" day="18"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document specifies how to use QUIC as a secure transport for exchanging Network Configuration Protocol (NETCONF) messages. NETCONF over QUIC allows to take advantage of QUIC streams, for example, to eliminate some TCP head-of-line blocking issues. NETCONF over QUIC provides security properties similar to NETCONF over TLS. This document also defines a YANG module which augments the ietf- netconf-client and ietf-netconf-server YANG modules. Editorial note (to be removed by the RFC Editor This draft contains placeholder values that need to be replaced with finalized values at the time of publication. This note summarizes all of the substitutions that are needed. No other RFC Editor instructions are specified elsewhere in this document. Artwork in this document contains shorthand references to drafts in progress. Please apply the following replacements: * AAAA --&gt; the assigned RFC value for this draft * BBBB --&gt; the assigned RFC value for draft-ietf-netconf-netconf- client-server * CCCC --&gt; the assigned RFC value for draft-ietf-netconf-quic- client-server</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-netconf-over-quic-07"/>
</reference>