<reference anchor="I-D.ye-ippm-switching-efficiency" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-ye-ippm-switching-efficiency-02">
  <front>
    <title>Switching Efficiency: A Metric Framework for AI Data Center Networks</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ye-ippm-switching-efficiency-02"/>
    <author initials="" surname="YNG2020" fullname="YNG2020">
      <organization>Shanghai Jiao Tong University</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="W." surname="Sun" fullname="Weiqiang Sun">
      <organization>Shanghai Jiao Tong University</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="D." surname="Wang" fullname="Dong Wang">
      <organization>China Mobile Research Institute</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="J." surname="Sun" fullname="Jiang Sun">
      <organization>China Mobile Research Institute</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="19" month="April" year="2026"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This document specifies the Switching Efficiency Framework, a
   measurement methodology designed to evaluate network efficiency in AI
   Data Centers (AIDCs).  Conventional network metrics, such as
   bandwidth utilization or network throughput, fail to directly link
   network activity to computational progress, as they cannot
   distinguish computationally effective data that directly advances
   neural network computing from the redundant traffic induced by both
   multi-hop forwarding and the algorithmic overhead of collective
   operations.

   To address this, this document defines the Switching Efficiency
   Framework, a measurement methodology for evaluating AIDC network
   efficiency.  The core metric, Switching Efficiency, quantifies the
   computationally effective data throughput delivered per unit of
   provisioned switching capacity.  To facilitate precise diagnostic
   analysis, the framework further decomposes this core metric into
   three fine-grained factors: Data Efficiency, Routing Efficiency, and
   Port Utilization.

   This framework provides metrics that can help operators identify
   communication bottlenecks and evaluate topology-traffic alignment.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>