<reference anchor="I-D.bush-inline-predictive-mgt">
  <front>
    <title>In-Line Network Management Prediction</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-bush-inline-predictive-mgt-00"/>
    <author fullname="Stephen F Bush" initials="S. F." surname="Bush">
      <organization>GE GRC</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Ned Smith" initials="N." surname="Smith"/>
    <date year="2002" month="August" day="1"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>In-line network management prediction exploits fine-grained models ofnetwork components, injected into the communication network, toenhance network performance. Accurate and fast prediction of localnetwork state enables more intelligent network control resulting ingreater performance and fault tolerance. Accurate and fastprediction requires algorithmic capability. Active and ProgrammableNetworking have enabled algorithmic information to be dynamicallyinjected into the network allowing enhanced capability andflexibility. One of the new capabilities is enhanced networkmanagement via in-line management code, that is, managementalgorithms embedded within intermediate network devices. In-linenetwork management prediction utilizes low-level algorithmictransport capability to implement low-overhead predictive management.A secondary purpose of this document is to provide generalinteroperability information for the injection of general purposealgorithmic information into network devices. This document may helpin some manner to serve as a temporary bridge between InternetProtocol and Active and Programmable Network applications. Thismay stimulate some thought as to the content and format of'standards' information potentially required for Active Networking.Management of the Internet Protocol and Active and ProgrammableNetworking is vital. In particular, coexistence and interoperabilityof active networking and Internet Protocol management is specifiedin order to implement the injection of algorithmic information into anetwork.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>