<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-opsawg-ntf" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-ietf-opsawg-ntf-07">
  <front>
    <title>Network Telemetry Framework</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-opsawg-ntf-07"/>
    <author initials="H." surname="Song" fullname="Haoyu Song">
      <organization>Futurewei</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="F." surname="Qin" fullname="Fengwei Qin">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="P." surname="Martinez-Julia" fullname="Pedro Martinez-Julia">
      <organization>NICT</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="L." surname="Ciavaglia" fullname="Laurent Ciavaglia">
      <organization>Nokia</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="A." surname="Wang" fullname="Aijun Wang">
      <organization>China Telecom</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="19" month="February" year="2021"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>   Network telemetry is a technology for gaining network insight and
   facilitating efficient and automated network management.  It
   encompasses various techniques for remote data generation,
   collection, correlation, and consumption.  This document describes an
   architectural framework for network telemetry, motivated by
   challenges that are encountered as part of the operation of networks
   and by the requirements that ensue.  Network telemetry, as
   necessitated by best industry practices, covers technologies and
   protocols that extend beyond conventional network Operations,
   Administration, and Management (OAM).  The presented network
   telemetry framework promises flexibility, scalability, accuracy,
   coverage, and performance.  In addition, it facilitates the
   implementation of automated control loops to address both today's and
   tomorrow's network operational needs.  This document clarifies the
   terminologies and classifies the modules and components of a network
   telemetry system from several different perspectives.  The framework
   and taxonomy help to set a common ground for the collection of
   related work and provide guidance for related technique and standard
   developments.

	 </t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>