<reference anchor="I-D.lkspa-rats-verifiable-geo-fence" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-lkspa-rats-verifiable-geo-fence-02">
  <front>
    <title>Verifiable Proof of Environment Attestation Profile</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-lkspa-rats-verifiable-geo-fence-02"/>
    <author initials="R." surname="Krishnan" fullname="Ramki Krishnan">
      <organization>JPMorgan Chase &amp; Co.</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="N." surname="Smith" fullname="Ned Smith">
      <organization>Intel</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="D." surname="Lopez" fullname="Diego Lopez">
      <organization>Telefonica</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="A." surname="Prasad" fullname="A Prasad">
      <organization>Oracle</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="S." surname="Addepalli" fullname="Srinivasa Addepalli">
      <organization>Aryaka</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="23" month="May" year="2026"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Operators of regulated, sovereign, and high-assurance deployments
   require hardware-rooted, machine-verifiable proof that a workload
   executes in its approved environment.  Current remote attestation
   mechanisms address two relevant properties in isolation: platform
   integrity — that the hardware and software stack are in an approved,
   untampered state — and physical residency — that the hardware resides
   within an approved geographic boundary.  Neither property alone is
   sufficient: integrity without residency permits a valid platform to
   operate outside approved boundaries; residency without integrity
   permits a compromised platform to claim valid placement.

   This document defines the *Verifiable Proof of Environment
   Attestation Profile (V-PEA)*, a profile of the RATS Architecture
   {{!RFC9334}} that fuses both properties into a single TPM-sealed
   Evidence structure (lah-bundle).  V-PEA defines two Evidence
   dimensions: *WHAT* — hardware provenance (TPM Attestation Key
   registered and manufacturer-endorsed), platform integrity (firmware
   and OS state matching reference values), and workload agent software
   integrity (binary digest matching an approved value); and *WHERE* —
   physical residency within an approved geographic boundary.  A TPM
   quote seal binds WHAT and WHERE into a single unforgeable statement:
   neither dimension can be forged or transplanted without invalidating
   the other.

   For the WHERE dimension, V-PEA supports Transparent Zero-Knowledge
   Proofs (ZKPs), enabling an Attester to prove geographic compliance
   without disclosing precise coordinates.  A positive V-PEA Attestation
   Result enables a Relying Party to issue hardware-rooted credentials
   or authorize operations — combining verified execution environment
   (WHAT) with verified physical placement (WHERE) — before releasing
   sensitive assets or granting access.  Integration with workload
   identity systems is described in the WIMSE Integration appendix.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>