<reference anchor="I-D.liu-iotops-modbus-seriallink-sec-spec" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-liu-iotops-modbus-seriallink-sec-spec-04">
  <front>
    <title>Modbus Serial Link Communication Security Protocol Specification</title>
    <author fullname="Penghui Liu" initials="P." surname="Liu">
      <organization>Pengcheng Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Rongwei Yang" initials="R." surname="Yang">
      <organization>Pengcheng Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Meiling Chen" initials="M." surname="Chen">
      <organization>China Mobile</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Yu Fu" initials="Y." surname="Fu">
      <organization>China Unicom</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Weizhe Zhang" initials="W." surname="Zhang">
      <organization>Pengcheng Laboratory</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2025" month="December" day="11"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Currently, the industry has only standardized TLS-based security protocol for Modbus TCP communication. However, for EIA/TIA-485 multi-point systems, whether in 2-wire or 4-wire configurations, cables with a maximum baud rate of 9600 bit/s and AWG26 (or thicker) specifications can reach lengths over 1000m. For RS485 Modbus, sufficient cable diameter supports lengths over 1000m, and Category 5 cables can reach up to 600m. Despite its widespread use, Modbus serial link communication lacks standardized security mechanisms. As an application-layer industrial communication protocol, Modbus urgently requires targeted security standards for different deployment scenarios to enhance its security framework and ecosystem. For instance, in scenarios involving hardware side-channel attacks or long-distance relay and bridged networks, transmitting plaintext Modbus data over serial links risks data leakage or malicious modification by intermediaries, posing significant data and command security threats. To address this, it is critical to improve the communication security of Modbus in serial link mode by introducing encryption and authentication mechanisms. A proposed Modbus serial link security standard defines simple encryption and authentication methods to significantly enhance security while maintaining compatibility. This provides a straightforward upgrade path for existing Modbus-based devices, ensuring secure and practical applications in industrial control systems.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-liu-iotops-modbus-seriallink-sec-spec-04"/>
</reference>