<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-anima-grasp-distribution">
  <front>
    <title>Information Distribution over GRASP</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-anima-grasp-distribution-03"/>
    <author>
      <organization abbrev="IETF">Internet Engineering Task Force</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Xun Xiao" initials="X." surname="Xiao">
      <organization>MRC, Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Bing Liu" initials="B." surname="Liu">
      <organization>Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Artur Hecker" initials="A." surname="Hecker">
      <organization>MRC, Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Sheng Jiang" initials="S." surname="Jiang">
      <organization>Huawei Technologies</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Brian E. Carpenter" initials="B. E." surname="Carpenter">
      <organization>School of Computer Science, University of      Auckland</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2021" month="July" day="12"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Autonomic network infrastructure (ANI) is a generic platform for tenant applications (i.e. AFs). As we will see in some examplery use cases, AFs may not only require communication capability supported from the infrastructure side, but also the capability the infrastructure can hold and re-distribute information on-demand. This document proposes a set of solutions for information distribution in the ANI. Information distribution is categorized into two different modes: 1) instantaneous distribution and 2) publishing for retrieval. In the former case, the information is sent, propagated and disposed of after reception. In the latter case, information needs to be stored in the network; additionally, conflict resolution is also needed when information stored in the network is updated with proposals from two different AFs. The capability of information distribution is a fundamental need for an autonomous network ([RFC7575]). This document describes typical use cases of information distribution in ANI and requirements to ANI, such that abundant ways of information distribution can be natively supported. This draft proposes a series of extensions to the autonomic nodes and suggests an implementation based on GRASP ([I-D.ietf-anima-grasp]) extensions as a protocol on the wire.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>