<reference anchor="I-D.ren-sidrops-soa-usage" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-ren-sidrops-soa-usage-03">
  <front>
    <title>Source Address Validation Using Source Origin Authorizations (SOAs)</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ren-sidrops-soa-usage-03"/>
    <author initials="R." surname="Gang" fullname="Ren Gang">
      <organization>Tsinghua University</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="M." surname="Jia" fullname="Minglin Jia">
      <organization>Tsinghua University</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="X." surname="Yin" fullname="Xia Yin">
      <organization>Tsinghua University</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="S." surname="Liu" fullname="Shuqi Liu">
      <organization>Tsinghua University</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="23" month="June" year="2026"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Given that an AS collaboration scheme for inter-domain source address
   validation requires an information-sharing platform, this document
   proposes a two-tier approach.  In the first tier, Resource Public Key
   Infrastructure (RPKI) is used for service discovery, identity
   authentication, and transmission of the minimum bootstrap information
   needed to establish a private channel.  Source Origin Authorization
   (SOA) is a newly defined cryptographically signed AS-level service-
   profile object for that purpose.  Subscribers and providers each
   publish their own SOA profiles; a concrete service relation exists
   only after discovery, bilateral request validation, and provider
   acceptance.  In the second tier, the legitimate predecessor AS
   information and its subsequent updates are exchanged over the
   authenticated private channel, by default using TLS[RFC8446] carrying
   CBOR[RFC8949]-encoded logical messages, enabling other ASes to
   collaboratively filter spoofed traffic while avoiding frequent
   routing-driven updates to RPKI and reducing exposure of subscriber-
   specific routing data.  This revision also describes a logical
   synchronization state model, evidence-tagged authorization state, and
   fail-open handling for unavailable synchronized state, while leaving
   private-channel wire encoding to future specifications or bilateral
   deployment profiles.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>