<reference anchor="I-D.aravamudhan-mobileip-nai-wn">
  <front>
    <title>NAI Resolution for Wireless Networks</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-aravamudhan-mobileip-nai-wn-00"/>
    <author fullname="Lachu Aravamudhan" initials="L." surname="Aravamudhan">
      <organization>Basavaraj Patil</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Mark O'Brien" initials="M." surname="O'Brien">
      <organization>Basavaraj Patil</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Basavaraj Patil" initials="B." surname="Patil"/>
    <date year="1999" month="October" day="21"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>RFC 2468 [1] defines the need of a standardized format foridentifying ISP subscribers for dial-up roaming operations. Itintroduced the Network Access Identifier (NAI) to fulfill thisneed. The NAI is provided by the mobile node to the dialed ISPduring PPP authentication.The ability to resolve an NAI for second and third generationcellular mobile nodes allow traditional cellular service providersto evolve their home cellular networks to provide cellularservices, IP packet data services and so on with a singlesubscription using NAIs. Additionally, this allows cellularprovider to evolve their networks to be IP based.Second and third generation cellular mobile nodes must perform aregistration and authentication process with their wireless serviceprovider before the mobile node user may initiate other operations(See [1] for examples). These mobile nodes do not support theprogramming of an NAI nor does the cellular registration messagesupport the transfer of an NAI to the wireless access network. Forexample, North American cellular networks (e.g. AMPS, TDMA, CDMA)service mobiler nodes that register with a Mobile IdentificationNumber (MIN). The MIN is then associated with a cellularsubscriber. MIN is shown here only as an example, the same generalidea is applicable to other types of identifiers used in differentaccess network types. For the same reasons stated in [1], it wouldbe convenient if an option was available to provide the wirelesssubscriber identification in the form of an NAI during the wirelessregistration and authentication process. This draft proposes asolution to resolve NAIs from traditional mobile node identifiers.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>