<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-dnsop-generalized-notify" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-ietf-dnsop-generalized-notify-00">
  <front>
    <title>Generalized DNS Notifications</title>
    <author fullname="Johan Stenstam" initials="J." surname="Stenstam">
      <organization>The Swedish Internet Foundation</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Peter Thomassen" initials="P." surname="Thomassen">
      <organization>deSEC, Secure Systems Engineering</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="John R. Levine" initials="J. R." surname="Levine">
      <organization>Standcore LLC</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2023" month="September" day="29"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Changes in CDS/CDNSKEY, CSYNC, and other records related to delegation maintenance are usually detected through scheduled scans run by the consuming party (e.g. top-level domain registry), incurring an uncomfortable trade-off between scanning cost and update latency. A similar problem exists when scheduling zone transfers, and has been solved using the well-known DNS NOTIFY mechanism ([RFC1996]). This mechanism enables a primary nameserver to proactively inform secondaries about zone changes, allowing the secondary to initiate an ad-hoc transfer independently of when the next SOA check would be due. This document extends the use of DNS NOTIFY beyond conventional zone transfer hints, bringing the benefits of ad-hoc notifications to DNS delegation maintenance in general. Use cases include DNSSEC key rollovers hints via NOTIFY(CDS) and NOTIFY(DNSKEY) messages, and quicker changes to a delegation's NS record set via NOTIFY(CSYNC) messages. Furthermore, this document proposes a new DNS record type, tentatively referred to as "NOTIFY record", which is used to publish details about where generalized notifications should be sent. TO BE REMOVED: This document is being collaborated on in Github at: https://github.com/peterthomassen/draft-ietf-dnsop-generalized-notify (https://github.com/peterthomassen/draft-ietf-dnsop-generalized- notify). The most recent working version of the document, open issues, etc. should all be available there. The authors (gratefully) accept pull requests.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-dnsop-generalized-notify-00"/>
</reference>