<reference anchor="I-D.ramakrishna-satp-data-sharing" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-ramakrishna-satp-data-sharing-00">
  <front>
    <title>Protocol for Requesting and Sharing Views across Networks</title>
    <author fullname="Venkatraman Ramakrishna" initials="V." surname="Ramakrishna">
      <organization>IBM Research</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Vinayaka Pandit" initials="V." surname="Pandit">
      <organization>IBM Research</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Ermyas Abebe" initials="E." surname="Abebe">
      <organization>Consensys</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Sandeep Nishad" initials="S." surname="Nishad">
      <organization>IBM Research</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Dhinakaran Vinayagamurthy" initials="D." surname="Vinayagamurthy">
      <organization>IBM Research</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2023" month="July" day="7"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>With increasing use of DLT (distributed ledger technology) systems, including blockchain systems and networks, for virtual assets, there is a need for asset-related data and metadata to traverse system boundaries and link their respective business workflows. Systems and networks can define and project views, or asset states, outside of their boundaries, as well as guard them using access control policies, and external agents or other systems can address those views in a globally unique manner. Universal interoperability requires such systems and networks to request and supply views via gateway nodes using a request-response protocol. The endpoints of this protocol lie within the respective systems or in networks of peer nodes, but the cross-system protocol occurs through the systems’ respective gateways. The inter-gateway protocol that allows an external party to request a view by an address and a DLT system to return a view in response must be DLT-neutral and mask the internal particularities and complexities of the DLT systems. The view generation and verification modules at the endpoints must obey the native consensus logic of their respective networks.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ramakrishna-satp-data-sharing-00"/>
</reference>