<reference anchor="I-D.sarikaya-int-area-prefix-delegation">
  <front>
    <title>Using DHCPv6 for Prefix Delegation in Cellular Networks</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-sarikaya-int-area-prefix-delegation-00"/>
    <author fullname="Behcet Sarikaya"/>
    <author fullname="Frank Xia"/>
    <date year="2009" month="December" day="16"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>According to IPv6 operation in cellular networks, one prefix can onlybe assigned to one interface of a mobile node by an access router anddifferent mobile nodes can't share a prefix. Managing Per-MNinterface prefixes is likely to increase the processing load at theaccess router. Based on the idea that DHCPv6 servers can manageprefixes as well as addresses, we propose a new technique in whichthe access router offloads delegation and release tasks of theprefixes to an DHCPv6 server. The access router first requests aprefix for an incoming mobile node to the DHCPv6 server. The accessrouter next advertises the prefix information to the mobile node witha Router Advertisement message. When the mobile node hands off, theprefix is returned to the DHCPv6 server. We also describe how AAAservers can help in prefix delegation.Status of this MemoThis Internet-Draft is submitted to IETF in full conformance with theprovisions of BCP 78 and BCP 79.Internet-Drafts are working documents of the Internet EngineeringTask Force (IETF), its areas, and its working groups. Note thatother groups may also distribute working documents as Internet-Drafts.Internet-Drafts are draft documents valid for a maximum of six monthsand may be updated, replaced, or obsoleted by other documents at anytime. It is inappropriate to use Internet-Drafts as referencematerial or to cite them other than as "work in progress."The list of current Internet-Drafts can be accessed athttp://www.ietf.org/ietf/1id-abstracts.txt.The list of Internet-Draft Shadow Directories can be accessed athttp://www.ietf.org/shadow.html.This Internet-Draft will expire on June 19, 2010.Copyright NoticeCopyright (c) 2009 IETF Trust and the persons identified as thedocument authors. All rights reserved.This document is subject to BCP 78 and the IETF Trust's LegalProvisions Relating to IETF Documents(http://trustee.ietf.org/license-info) in effect on the date ofpublication of this document. Please review these documentscarefully, as they describe your rights and restrictions with respectto this document. Code Components extracted from this document mustinclude Simplified BSD License text as described in Section 4.e ofthe Trust Legal Provisions and are provided without warranty asdescribed in the BSD License.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>