<reference anchor="I-D.ietf-idr-bgp-flowspec-oid" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-ietf-idr-bgp-flowspec-oid-13">
  <front>
    <title>Revised Validation Procedure for BGP Flow Specifications</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-ietf-idr-bgp-flowspec-oid-13"/>
    <author initials="J." surname="Uttaro" fullname="Jim Uttaro">
      <organization>AT&amp;T</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="J." surname="Alcaide" fullname="Juan Alcaide">
      <organization>Cisco</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="C." surname="Filsfils" fullname="Clarence Filsfils">
      <organization>Cisco</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="D." surname="Smith" fullname="David Smith">
      <organization>Cisco</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="P." surname="Mohapatra" fullname="Prodosh Mohapatra">
      <organization>Sproute Networks</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="12" month="April" year="2021"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>   This document describes a modification to the validation procedure
   defined for the dissemination of BGP Flow Specifications.  The
   dissemination of BGP Flow Specifications requires that the originator
   of the Flow Specification matches the originator of the best-match
   unicast route for the destination prefix embedded in the Flow
   Specification.  For an iBGP received route, the originator is
   typically a border router within the same autonomous system.  The
   objective is to allow only BGP speakers within the data forwarding
   path to originate BGP Flow Specifications.  Sometimes it is desirable
   to originate the BGP Flow Specification any place within the
   autonomous system itself, for example, from a centralized BGP route
   controller.  However, the validation procedure will fail in this
   scenario.  The modification proposed herein relaxes the validation
   rule to enable Flow Specifications to be originated within the same
   autonomous system as the BGP speaker performing the validation.
   Additionally, this document revises AS_PATH validation rules so Flow
   Specifications received from an eBGP peer can be validated when such
   peer is a BGP route server.

   This document updates the validation procedure in RFC8955.

	 </t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>