<reference anchor="I-D.barguil-teas-network-slices-instantation">
  <front>
    <title>Instantiation of IETF Network Slices in Service Providers Networks</title>
    <author fullname="Samier Barguil" surname="Samier Barguil">
      <organization>Telefonica</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Luis Miguel Contreras" surname="Luis Miguel Contreras">
      <organization>Telefonica</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Victor Lopez" surname="Victor Lopez">
      <organization>Nokia</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Reza Rokui" surname="Reza Rokui">
      <organization>Nokia</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Oscar Gonzalez de Dios" surname="Oscar Gonzalez de Dios">
      <organization>Telefonica</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2021" month="July" day="12"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Network Slicing (NS) is an integral part of Service Provider networks. The IETF has produced several YANG data models to support the Software-Defined Networking and network slice architecture and YANG-based service models for network slice (NS) instantiation. This document describes the relationship between IETF Network Slice models for requesting the IETF Network Slices and (e.g., Layer-3 Service Model, Layer-2 Service Model) and Network Models (e.g., Layer-3 Network Model, Layer-2 Network Model) used during their realizations. In addition, this document describes the communication between the IETF Network Slice Controller and the network controllers for the realization of IETF network slices. The IETF Network Slice YANG model provides the customer-oriented view of the network slice. Thus, once the IETF Network Slice controller (NSC) receives a request, it needs to map it to accomplish the specific parameters expected by the network controllers. The network models are analyzed to satisfy the IETF Network Slice requirements, and the gaps in existing models are reported. The document also provides operational and security considerations when deploying network slices in Service Provider networks.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-barguil-teas-network-slices-instantation-02"/>
  <format type="TXT" target="https://www.ietf.org/archive/id/draft-barguil-teas-network-slices-instantation-02.txt"/>
</reference>