<reference anchor="I-D.claise-opsawg-ipfix-ordered-ie" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-claise-opsawg-ipfix-ordered-ie-01">
  <front>
    <title>Ordered Information Element Export in IP Flow Information Export (IPFIX)</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-claise-opsawg-ipfix-ordered-ie-01"/>
    <author initials="B." surname="Claise" fullname="Beno&#xEE;t Claise">
      <organization>Everything OPS &amp; Arrcus</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="P." surname="Aitken" fullname="Paul Aitken">
      <organization>Ciena</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="H." surname="Keller" fullname="Holger Keller">
      <organization>Deutsche Telekom</organization>
    </author>
    <author initials="Y." surname="Liu" fullname="Yao Liu">
      <organization>ZTE Corporation</organization>
    </author>
    <date day="06" month="July" year="2026"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>The IP Flow Information Export (IPFIX) protocol allows the same
   Information Element to appear multiple times in a Template Record.
   RFC 7011 states that multiple occurrences of the same Information
   Element SHOULD follow the logical order of their treatments by the
   Metering Process; however, no protocol mechanism exists for the
   Exporting Process to explicitly signal to the Collecting Process that
   this ordering is guaranteed.  Without such a guarantee, the
   Collecting Process cannot safely interpret repeated Information
   Elements as ordered observations.  This document describes the
   problem, presents use cases, analyzes candidate solutions, and
   specifies a mechanism -- a new Ordered Set type -- that establishes
   an end-to-end ordering guarantee: the Metering Process records
   repeated Information Element values in the order the corresponding
   observations are made, the Exporting Process preserves and signals
   this guarantee, and the Collecting Process interprets the n-th
   occurrence of an Information Element as corresponding to the n-th
   observation by the Metering Process at the Observation Point.  This
   document updates RFC 7011, RFC 5476, and RFC 6183.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>