<reference anchor="I-D.strassner-policy-terms">
  <front>
    <title>Terminology for describing network policy and services</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-strassner-policy-terms-01"/>
    <author fullname="Ed J. Ellesson" initials="E. J." surname="Ellesson">
      <organization>IBM</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="John Strassner" initials="J." surname="Strassner">
      <organization>Cisco Systems</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Walter Weiss" initials="W." surname="Weiss"/>
    <author fullname="Andrea Westerinen" initials="A." surname="Westerinen"/>
    <date year="1999" month="March" day="1"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>Recent work in the IETF has led to multiple protocols which supportthe classification of packets for the purposes of treating certainclasses or flows of packets in a particular way compared to otherpackets. The successful wide-scale deployment of these protocolsdepends on the ability to administer and distribute consistent policyinformation to the multiple devices in the network which perform theclassification and packet conditioning or treatment. As a result,there is a clear need to develop a scalable framework for policyadministration and distribution that will enable interoperabilityamong multiple devices and device types that must work together toachieve a consistent implementation of policy. Unfortunately, terms like 'policy' and 'service' are notcurrently defined in sufficient detail as to enable the definition,specification, and implementation of policy servers and how policy isrecognized and enforced at the device level. At present, both 'policy'and 'service' (as well as other related terms) are overloaded withmultiple (often conflicting) meanings. This makes communication aboutpolicy in general and specifically policy-based networking cumbersomeand difficult. This document defines a set of terms that the Internet community canuse to exchange ideas on how policy creation, administration,management, and distribution could work among policy servers andmultiple device types.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>