<reference anchor="I-D.eckert-ietf-and-energy-overview" target="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/draft-eckert-ietf-and-energy-overview-08">
  <front>
    <title>An Overview of Energy-related Effort within the IETF, IRTF, and IAB</title>
    <author fullname="Toerless Eckert" initials="T. T." surname="Eckert">
      <organization>Futurewei Technologies USA</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Mohamed Boucadair" initials="M." surname="Boucadair">
      <organization>Orange</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Pascal Thubert" initials="P." surname="Thubert">
      <organization>Cisco Systems, Inc.</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Jeff Tantsura" initials="J." surname="Tantsura">
      <organization>NVIDIA</organization>
    </author>
    <author fullname="Carlos Pignataro" initials="C." surname="Pignataro">
      <organization>NC State University</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2025" month="August" day="29"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>This memo provides a compilation of existing work performed by or proposed within the IETF, the IRTF, and the IAB that relates to energy and sustainability: awareness, management, control, or reduction of energy consumption. The principal goal is to help IETF, IRTF, and IAB participants, especially newcomers and future contributors, become familiar with the body of work already published. This document serves as the first catalog of such efforts, providing a consolidated internal reference. An additional goal is to raise awareness and interest in energy- related activities within the IETF, IRTF, and IAB, to continue identifying gaps and investigating solutions as appropriate. The scope of this document includes selected work from the IETF, IRTF, and IAB where relevant. This document is descriptive in nature and does not propose new work items. This document captures work until 12/2022, when the "IAB workshop on Environmental Impact of Internet Applications and Systems” contextualized renewed community interest and discussion of the topic. This memo itself does not recommend or direct future work.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-eckert-ietf-and-energy-overview-08"/>
</reference>