<reference anchor="I-D.iyengar-ford-tng">
  <front>
    <title>A Next Generation Transport Services Architecture</title>
    <seriesInfo name="Internet-Draft" value="draft-iyengar-ford-tng-00"/>
    <author fullname="Janardhan Iyengar"/>
    <author fullname="Bryan Ford"/>
    <date year="2009" month="July" day="6"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>While there is substantial community interest in next-generationmultipath-capable Internet transports, evolutionary pressures havegradually eroded the simplicity of the Internet's original transportarchitecture to a point where it is no longer realisticallyapplicable to new tranports. This document proposes a newarchitectural framework for next-generation multipath-capabletransport protocols, focusing immediately on multipath TCP but takingcare to allow for generalization to other multipath-capabletransports. The architecture places emphasis on enabling newmultipath features in a safe, TCP-friendly, and backward-compatiblefashion, retaining full interoperability with both existingapplications and existing network infrastructure, and enabling reuseof existing protocols as much as possible while providing incrementaldeployment paths to new, more powerful and/or more efficientprotocols. The architecture re-establishes the long-lost principlesof end-to-end reliability and fate sharing, in the presence ofexisting and future network middleboxes, and enables the deploymentof transport-neutral end-to-end protection without interfering withthese policy-enforcing or performance-enhancing middleboxes. Thisdocument describes architecture goals, a layering model supportingthese goals, abstract properties of the interfaces between thearchitecture's new layers, general approaches to multipath congestioncontrol and how they fit into the architecture, realistic protocoldesign and incremental deployment paths, and ways in which thisdocument complements and relates to ongoing protocol designactivities in the IETF.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>